<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arabic on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/arabic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arabic on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/arabic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem Together</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</guid>
      <description>Allah introduces himself in Surah Fatiha as Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem, both. Both of these names derive their meaning from the word mercy (rahmah).
In classical Arabic, rahmah represents the mercy of a mother for her child. As the child grows, it causes the mother to be sick and weak; it eats nutrition from the mother; in the later trimesters, the child even stretches, punches, or kicks the mother&amp;#8217;s ribs! But still, the mother cares for, takes care of, and protects the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’anic Oath: Tallahi!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quranic-oath-tallahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 16:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quranic-oath-tallahi/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Aqsaam (oaths) in the Qur&amp;#8217;an are a very fascinating subject that we should study and focus on more. There are a few components needed for a qasm (oath) to occur. One of them is the harf qasm, a letter that shows there is an oath being taken.
There are a few letters in the Qur&amp;#8217;an that are used as harf qasm, for example, Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala says &amp;#8220;wal &amp;#8216;aadiyaati dhabhaa&amp;#8221;. The harf qasm in this oath is the letter wow (و).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’an vs Kitaab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 01:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
The two most common names for the Book of Allah are: Qur&amp;#8217;an and Kitaab.
We learn when studying the Qur&amp;#8217;an that even the words chosen are a revelation from Allah with divine wisdom. So, in that case, what do these two names mean and what is the difference between them?
The word &amp;#8216;Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8217; is said to be from two roots, one of them qaaf-ra-hamza, this root qara&amp;#8217;a means to recite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOW is the Time to Learn Arabic!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/now-is-the-time-to-learn-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 16:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/now-is-the-time-to-learn-arabic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bismillah walhamdulillah, was Salaatu was Salaamu &amp;#8216;alaa Rasoolillaah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;On the Day of Judgment, the Qur&amp;#8217;an and its people who used to act by it in the world shall be brought, being lead by Surat ul-Baqarah and Al-e-Imraan, which shall be arguing on behalf of their &lt;span&gt;companions&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (Reported by Muslim)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all strive to become a companion of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, but who are its true companions? The companions of the Qur&amp;#8217;an are those who studied it, memorized it, implemented it and lived by it. It is not possible, in the least bit, for one to become a companion of the Qur&amp;#8217;an and not know Arabic. Learning the language is the starting point of a life long journey with the Qur&amp;#8217;an. Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala chose this blessed language, as He states 11 times throughout the Qur&amp;#8217;an: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;A Book, whereof the verses are explained in detail as an &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, for people who know.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (41:3), &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;An &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, without any crookedness, so that they may have Taqwa.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (39:28), &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;We have sent it down as an &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, in order that you may gain understanding.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (12:2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do not know the language of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, they will be deprived of its true sweetness, of its blessings and most importantly, understanding the words of Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala. It is a cause of much grief and sadness to know that the majority of our ummah has lost the connection with the Book of Allah because the language has been lost, as the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Allah raises up peoples by this Book, and puts down by it others.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (Saheeh Muslim) We have abandoned this book, and the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam will testify to Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala on the day of judgment: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;And the Messenger will say, O my Rabb, indeed my people deserted this Qur&amp;#8217;an!&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (25:30)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The righteous companions and scholars of the past have testified to the importance of learning this language and they themselves, who were native Arab speakers, were concerned with studying this language. Umar radi Allahu anhu said, &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Learn Arabic for it is a part of your deen&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; (Iqtidaa&amp;#8217; al-Siraat al-Mustaqeem, &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;207&lt;/sub&gt;) It is also reported that Ubay ibn Ka&amp;#8217;b radi Allahu anhu said, &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Learn Arabic just as you learn to memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; (Ibn Abî Shaybah, &lt;em&gt;Al-Mu&lt;span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;annaf&lt;/em&gt; Vol.7 p150)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us want to take the proper steps to learn Arabic, but do not know where to start. What is the solution? Where do we begin? The best option is to study overseas, however many of us do not have that option to learn Arabic, so inshaAllah we&amp;#8217;ll cover in this article some easy steps one can take to begin the process of learning Qur&amp;#8217;anic Arabic if they cannot travel to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>