<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tazkiyyah on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/tazkiyyah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tazkiyyah on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:26:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/tazkiyyah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Practical Steps to Taqwa, Step 1: Muhasabah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/four-practical-steps-to-taqwa-step-1-muhasabah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/four-practical-steps-to-taqwa-step-1-muhasabah/</guid>
      <description>Photo Credit: Pienw (Flickr)
The first practical step to gaining taqwa is accountability, known as muhasabah in Arabic; taking account of your actions. We see this concept from the beginning of Islamic history.:
In the Qur&amp;#8217;an In Surah Al-Hashr, Allah says:
 يا ايها الذين امنوا اتقوا الله ولتنظر نفس ما قدمت لغد واتقوا الله ان الله خبير بما تعملون
 Translation: O you who have believed, fear Allah .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m Drowning and I Don’t Know Why</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/im-drowning-and-i-dont-know-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/im-drowning-and-i-dont-know-why/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever felt like you were drowning? Submerged in the depths of the world? With darkness encompassing you everywhere you went?
I have.
And what makes the situation even more difficult to swim through is when you don&amp;#8217;t know why. Everything seems to be on point; you&amp;#8217;re praying, going to the masjid, giving charity, etc. yet that feeling of drowning is ever-so-present.
What&amp;#8217;s going on? 
I want you to imagine an empty jar with dirt in it (or just look below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Do List After Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Wikipedia
Ramadan ended. (May Allah accept all our prayer, fasting, du&amp;#8217;a, and good deeds during this blessed month &amp;#8212; ameen!) How should we, as Muslims, act now?
We graduated from the school of Ramadan; can life simply return to normal?
Our scholars mention a few points about this:
 Allah says, in surah Baqarah, that Ramadan was prescribed on us in the hope that we gain taqwa. Did we achieve that goal of the school of Ramadan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pray as if This is your Last Prayer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/pray-as-if-this-is-your-last-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/pray-as-if-this-is-your-last-prayer/</guid>
      <description>You often hear the khatheeb or imam, right before the salah starts, saying &amp;#8220;pray as if this is your last prayer.&amp;#8221; Sure, but what does it mean, and how do we do it?
As one of the righteous people of the past said:
 Pray as if Jannah is on your right side, Hellfire is on your left side, the siraat (bridge over Hellfire) is under you, the angel of death is behind you (waiting to take your soul any minute), your sins are above you (waiting to crush and destroy you), and this is the last deed, the one that decides if you go to Jannah or Jahannam forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 15:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we started a new series. The goal of the series is to learn and implement the sunnah in our lives. We started with the sunnah of our beloved Prophet (May Allah&amp;#8217;s peace and blessings be upon him) on waking up. I hope all of you have been practicing that sunnah. Here is the sunnah for this week:
Entering the Washroom:
 Enter with slippers/shoes Make the dua Enter with Left foot  After Entering the Washroom:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacons of Light</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post from I Got it Covered, a blog about hijab, Islam, and life. You can find the original article here.
In the time of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab, radiAllahu anhu, the second Khalifah, it was mandatory upon all the young girls to learn Surat an-Noor.
From the beauty of this Surah is that it begins with, &amp;#8220;[This is] a surah which We have sent down and made [that within it] obligatory and revealed therein verses of clear evidence that you might remember&amp;#8221; [Surat an-Noor: 1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Tariq: You Will Be Recreated</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-tariq-you-will-be-recreated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 16:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-tariq-you-will-be-recreated/</guid>
      <description>This is post #37 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
Allah says, in Surah Tariq:
 وَالسَّمَاءِ وَالطَّارِقِ
وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الطَّارِقُ
النَّجْمُ الثَّاقِبُ
 Translation: By the sky and the night comer (At-Tariq), And what can make you know what is the night comer? It is the piercing star. [Surah At-Taariq, verses 1-3]
As we mentioned before, one of the characteristics of early and Mecci surahs, like this one, is that they begin with a qasam &amp;#8212; an oath, a testification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 15:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Continuing in the ten ways to achieve the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, here are the last five points as per ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallauh:
 Sixth, observing Allaah’s kindness, goodness and bounties, both hidden and open.
 It is to be aware of the vast amounts of Mercy Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala has engulfed His slaves with. It is to recognize and accept the blessings of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala and to show thanks for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 15:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Here are ten ways to attain the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, as per Ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallah:
 First, reciting the Qur’an while pondering over its meanings and what is meant by it.
 Allah says, the meaning of which is: &amp;#8220;Then do they not reflect upon the Qur&amp;#8217;an? If it had been from [any] other than Allah , they would have found within it much contradiction&amp;#8221; [4:82]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
We live this life yearning to be amongst those whom Allah loves. On top of that, we wish and pray that Allah gives us the opportunity to be amonst the blessed who sincerly love Him. Truly, this only comes from His Will and we should beg him for that opportunity day and night.
Here is a a beautiful du&amp;#8217;a that we have been taught by the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Humazah: The Crusher</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-humazah-the-crusher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 17:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-humazah-the-crusher/</guid>
      <description>This is post #36 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In Surah Humazah, Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) says:
 وَيْلٌ لِّكُلِّ هُمَزَةٍ لُّمَزَةٍ
 Translation: Woe to every scorner (humazah) and mocker (lumazah). [Surah Al-Humaza, verse 1].
As we mentioned many, many times before in this series, wayl is a curse. And when Allah says wayl about someone, it&amp;#8217;s not a curse, but a statement of reality&amp;#8211;because He, &amp;#8216;azza wa jal, is not in need of cursing anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Traveller</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-traveller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 16:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-traveller/</guid>
      <description>Umar (RA) passed by a garbage dump and stopped there, and it was as if his companions were bothered by it (the smell). He said [&amp;#8230; full story at the end&amp;#8230;]
What would you think of someone who goes for umra on a 1 week trip. He goes there, buys a car, clothes, house, grocery, &amp;#8230;.. He even takes dollars with him and doesn&amp;#8217;t exchange them into local currency! We would think that something is wrong with that person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are on camera!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 19:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</guid>
      <description>Imagine this. You are speeding on the road. The police officer catches you, pulls you over and gives you a speeding ticket. What would your reaction be, next time you are driving especially driving through the same road. You would naturally slow down! Or you are stealing from your prayer (i.e. racing through it), you glance over and it seems like your friends might be looking at you. Your reaction&amp;#8230;. In these and in countless other situations, we refrain from doing bad because we fear that we might be caught or someone might be looking at us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Not Despair? Reflections on Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</guid>
      <description>Why not despair? The Islamic meaning of sabr is to stop ourselves from despairing and panicking, to stop our tongues from complaining, and to stop our hands from striking our faces and tearing our clothes at times of grief and stress.
To have _sabr_ is to first realize within your own heart that a) there is a god that exists b) that this god is worthy of all my worship c) that this god is indeed characterized by attributes of perfectness and majesty, which can only be ascribed to god and no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ins and Outs of Halloween</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-ins-and-outs-of-halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 19:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-ins-and-outs-of-halloween/</guid>
      <description>So who&amp;#8217;s down for a party this Saturday? Let&amp;#8217;s do it! Meet at the closest masjid near your house at 7:45pm. Forget about these kiddish Halloween parties, be a person of dignity and honour, be amongst the party of Allah.
وَيُدْخِلُهُمْ جَنَّاتٍ تَجْرِي مِن تَحْتِهَا الْأَنْهَارُ خَالِدِينَ فِيهَا رَضِيَ اللَّهُ عَنْهُمْ وَرَضُوا عَنْهُ أُوْلَئِكَ حِزْبُ اللَّهِ أَلَا إِنَّ حِزْبَ اللَّهِ هُمُ الْمُفْلِحُونَ  And We will admit them to gardens beneath which rivers flow, wherein they abide eternally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Balad, Part 2: Iqtahamaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-balad-part-2-iqtahamaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 19:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-balad-part-2-iqtahamaa/</guid>
      <description>This is post #34 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
The CN Tower, 150 stories high. Fa laa iqtahamaa al-aqabah.  Continuing our discussion of Surah Balad, Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) says:
 أَلَمْ نَجْعَل لَّهُ عَيْنَيْنِ
وَلِسَانًا وَشَفَتَيْنِ
وَهَدَيْنَاهُ النَّجْدَيْنِ
 Translation: Have We not made for him two eyes? And a tongue and two lips? And have shown him the two ways?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Balad, Part 1: Life is Toil</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-balad-part-1-life-is-toil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 18:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-balad-part-1-life-is-toil/</guid>
      <description>This is post #33 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series). This is the first of two posts on the tafseer of Surah Balad.
Allah says:
 لَا أُقْسِمُ بِهَذَا الْبَلَدِ
 Translation: I swear by this city (Makkah) &amp;#8230; [Surah Balad, verse 1]
&amp;#8220;Laa uqsim&amp;#8221; literally means, &amp;#8220;I will not swear by.&amp;#8221; in Arabic language, it means &amp;#8220;this thing is so truthful, I almost don&amp;#8217;t even have to swear by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Tawbah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
This is a translation from the original article in Arabic.
1- It is a cause to receive the Love of Allah azza wa jal. The Most High says:
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ التَّوَّابِينَ وَيُحِبُّ الْمُتَطَهِّرِينَ Truly, Allah loves those who turn unto Him in repentance and loves those who purify themselves. (2:222)
2- It is a cause of success. The Most High says:
وَتُوبُوا إِلَى اللَّهِ جَمِيعًا أَيُّهَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ لَعَلَّكُمْ تُفْلِحُونَ  And all of you beg Allah to forgive you, O believers, that you may be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 03:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Eid Mubarak! As the sahaba would tell each other: May Allah accept our good deeds and your good deeds (from Ramadan). Ameen!
Ramadan is still fresh in your mind; the long days of fasting, the pain in your legs and back from taraweeh, and most of all, that biting regret that you didn&amp;#8217;t do enough.
Would you like to make the next Ramadan even better? With only five minutes worth of effort?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan for the Last 10 Nights of Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/plan-for-the-last-10-nights-of-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 20:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/plan-for-the-last-10-nights-of-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is coming to a close. Like the last half-kilometer of a 10km race, the finish-line is in sight. This is the time to pull out all the stops and to sprint, flat-out. This is the time when Laylatul-Qadar, the night where deeds are multiplied by more than one thousand, hides.
Are you ready for it?
Maybe you felt like Ramadan breezed by. Maybe you felt like you didn&amp;#8217;t do enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Burjooj: Fitnah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-burjooj-fitnah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 20:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-burjooj-fitnah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is post #27 in our series on Tafseer of Juz ‘Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah Al-Burooj:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالسَّمَاءِ ذَاتِ الْبُرُوجِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالْيَوْمِ الْمَوْعُودِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَشَاهِدٍ وَمَشْهُودٍ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;قُتِلَ أَصْحَابُ الْأُخْدُودِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By the sky containing great stars. And [by] the promised Day. And [by] the witness and what is witnessed. Cursed were the companions of the trench. [Surah Al-Buruj, verses 1-4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of Ashaab-ul-Burooj, the People of the Ditch, is pretty well-known; in fact, we have an &lt;a href=&#34;the-people-of-the-ditch&#34;&gt;entire 15-part series&lt;/a&gt; on this surah. Check it out insha&amp;#8217;Allah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah opens this surahs with testifications. Then he testifies: qutila ashaabul-&amp;#8216;uqdood. &amp;#8216;uqdood is another word for ditch. Qutila, literally, means &amp;#8220;they were killed.&amp;#8221; But Ibn Abbaas (radiallahu anhu) said, whenever you read qutila in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, it means lu&amp;#8217;ina&amp;#8211;cursed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allah cursed the People of the Ditch.&lt;/strong&gt; And Allah is not in need of cursing&amp;#8211;He can do anything, to anybody, anytime, anywhere. Lu&amp;#8217;ina means, they were destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they _are_destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what great sin did they perpetrate in order to deserve this immense reward&amp;#8211;not only being cursed and destroyed, but &lt;em&gt;being documented in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, to be recited until the end of time&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Shams: One Man’s Sin</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-shams-one-mans-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 10:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-shams-one-mans-sin/</guid>
      <description>This is post #26 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
The noble she-camel, prized in the Arab society, was actually one of the signs Allah sent to a nation. What did they do with it?  Surahs are usually named by something unique in their content. But the sun (ash-shams) is mentioned in several surahs; so why is this one called Surah Shams?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Resource Bonanza!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#8217;s better than a chest of gold and jewels? A post full of Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah!  Bismillah.
This is a guest post by an author who compiled a wide number of resources related to fasting, reciting Qur&amp;#8217;an, and sincerity of intention. This is a great resource of ahadith and ayaat related to fasting. May Allah grant them a great reward (ameen!) and forgive any mistakes I have made in re-formatting it and linking all the sources to their citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Project Unveiled: Salah Support</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 16:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we&amp;#8217;ve been working in the background for a while to launch a new project. Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who helped out, may Allah keep giving you reward for it insha&amp;#8217;Allah long after your bones are dust&amp;#8211;allahumma ameen!
First, check yourself, and fill out the poll below:
[poll id=&amp;#8221;3&amp;#8243;]
If you haven&amp;#8217;t guessed, our new project is: Salah Support, a forum where you can find resources on salah&amp;#8211;everything from videos on how to pray, to ebooks on khushoo&amp;#8217;, to creative alarms for Qiaaym-ul-Layl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Lessons From the Death of Michael Jackson</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/7-lessons-from-the-death-of-michael-jackson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 14:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/7-lessons-from-the-death-of-michael-jackson/</guid>
      <description>Michael Jackson&amp;#8217;s $25,000 gold-plated bronze coffin (hand-polished).  This post is a brief and timely diversion from our tafseer series.
Michael Jackson was one of the most popular and well-known celebrities and icons of the western world; and now, he&amp;#8217;s dead. As Muslims, what lessons can we learn from this event? I&amp;#8217;ve listed below some of the lessons that came to my mind:
 Your Life is a Box. The Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) once drew a dot in the sand, and lines radiating out from it; he said (paraphrased), &amp;#8220;this is the human, and their plans/desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say: O You Kafiroon …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 20:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is post #20 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Kafiroon, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;قُلْ يَا أَيُّهَا الْكَافِرُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَا أَعْبُدُ مَا تَعْبُدُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنَا عَابِدٌ مَّا عَبَدتُّمْ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَكُمْ دِينُكُمْ وَلِيَ دِينِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Say, &amp;#8220;O disbelievers, I do not worship what you worship. Nor are you worshippers of what I worship. Nor will I be a worshipper of what you worship. Nor will you be worshippers of what I worship. For you is your religion, and for me is my religion.&amp;#8221; [Surah Kafiroon]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mushrikeen (polytheists) of Mecca tried many, many different techniques to get the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) to stop spreading Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this ayah was revealed, they decided to make a pact with him. They said, &amp;#8220;Look, how about this&amp;#8211;you worship our gods for one year, and we&amp;#8217;ll worship your God for one year.&amp;#8221; And to sweeten the deal: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ll go first.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they applied the Broken Record technique. Whenever the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) would try to speak to them about Islam, they would only repeat this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he, salallahu alayhi wa sallam, refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who are wondering why&amp;#8211;although it seems on the surface like a fair trade, it&amp;#8217;s not. Allah &lt;strong&gt;does not forgive shirk&lt;/strong&gt;, worshipping other than him; not even a single sujood, or a single du&amp;#8217;a, none of it is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So clearly, this is not a contract the Messenger of Allah could engage with. So he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he &lt;em&gt;refused&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the Mushrikeen said, &amp;#8220;ok, how about this&amp;#8211;just &lt;em&gt;speak highly&lt;/em&gt; of our gods, and we&amp;#8217;ll do the same for you.&amp;#8221; A smaller compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whenever people approached them, they would say, &amp;#8220;Well, we&amp;#8217;re trying to compromise (like &lt;em&gt;we&amp;#8217;re&lt;/em&gt; the good ones in this deal&amp;#8211;even though we kill our daughters and murder on whims and &amp;#8230;), but he&amp;#8217;s not agreeing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) went to the ka&amp;#8217;bah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/kabah-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; title=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1206&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mushrikeen were there. And in front of &lt;strong&gt;everybody&lt;/strong&gt; he said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Who Show Off in Their Salah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is post #19 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, Allah says:
 فَوَيْلٌ لِّلْمُصَلِّينَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَن صَلَاتِهِمْ سَاهُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ يُرَاءُونَ
وَيَمْنَعُونَ الْمَاعُونَ
 Translation: So woe to those who pray; those who are heedless of their prayer, those who make show [of their deeds]; And withhold [simple] assistance (al-ma&amp;#8217;oon). [Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, verses 4-7]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do YOU Encourage Good?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/do-you-encourage-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 19:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/do-you-encourage-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #18 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series). Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;ll be kicking up the post frequency to three times a week in order to finish before Ramadan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يُكَذِّبُ بِالدِّينِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَذَلِكَ الَّذِي يَدُعُّ الْيَتِيمَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا يَحُضُّ عَلَى طَعَامِ الْمِسْكِينِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Have you seen the one who denies the Repayment? For that is the one who drives away the orphan, and does not encourage the feeding of the poor. [Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, verses 1-3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the connection here&amp;#8211;verse one, the one who denies Ad-Deen, the Day of Repayment. And verse two and three? He drives away orphans, He doesn&amp;#8217;t encourage feeding of the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not that he &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;#8217;t feed&lt;/em&gt; the poor. It&amp;#8217;s that he &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;#8217;t encourange&lt;/em&gt; feeding the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Hakumu At-Takathur …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/al-hakumu-at-takathur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/al-hakumu-at-takathur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #17 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/empty-grave.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;empty-grave&#34; title=&#34;empty-grave&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1187&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  Competition in [worldly] increase diverts you, until you visit the graves &amp;#8230;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah At-Takaathur:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;أَلْهَاكُمُ التَّكَاثُرُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;حَتَّى زُرْتُمُ الْمَقَابِرَ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Competition in [worldly] increase diverts you, until you visit the graveyards. [Surah At-Takaathur, verses 1-2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subhanallah, even though these verses were revealed over 1400 years ago, we still see the &lt;em&gt;exact same&lt;/em&gt; situation today. Al-Haakum means, it makes you compete with each other. At-Takaathur is rivalry, competition, in accumulating material things; thinking that life is about toys, and the one with the most (or most expensive) toys wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Takaathur?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Duhaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 18:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is our 12th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/breakfast-on-bed.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1118&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  Islam is about social service and shukr (thankfulness).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insha&amp;#8217;Allah in this post, we&amp;#8217;re going to discuss three points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The close relationship between Allah and His prophet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A glimpse of Paradise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A core theme of social services in Islam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) received revelation prior to Surah Duhaa. Then for a while, nothing. Umm Jameelah, the wife of Abu Lahab, came to him and said: &amp;#8220;I hope your shaytaan has finally left you.&amp;#8221; Because the Arabs used to say, if someone was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good at something, that they had a shaytaan helping them. (No doubt like some of the musicians today.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still nothing came. The people began to talk &amp;#8230; and they said, maybe his Lord has left him. Maybe He has abandoned him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so Allah revealed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Duhaa, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالضُّحَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَى&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By duhaa (the morning brightness after Fajr), and [by] the night when it covers with darkness, your Lord has not taken leave of you, [O Muúammad], nor has He detested [you].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[This hadith is found in Bukhari and Muslim, and is quoted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://tafsir.com/default.asp?sid=93&amp;amp;tid=58628&#34;&gt;Tafseer ibn Katheer&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows us two things: first, that the people &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; when revelation came; that it was a big deal, and everybody knew about it. And second, &lt;span class=&#34;gem&#34;&gt;the immense love of Allah for His prophet.&lt;/span&gt; How close their relationship&amp;#8211;that even something as small as this stress, Allah revealed verses on behalf of the prophet, to reassure him. Subhanallah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, Allah &lt;em&gt;swears&lt;/em&gt; by duhaa&amp;#8211;by the brightness of the day right after the sun has come up&amp;#8211;and by the night, as it covers up the day with darkness. (This shows the greatness of these creations&amp;#8211;that Allah swears by them. Who would deny these things? Nobody!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Laziness and Incapability</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) used to make a du&amp;#8217;a:
 اللّهُمَّ إنِّي أعُوذُبِكَ مِن العَجزِ وَ الكَسلٍTransliteration: Allahumma inniy a&amp;#8217;oothubika min al-ajzi wal-kasli
Translation: O Allah, I seek refuge in you from incapability and laziness.  Why is this du&amp;#8217;a important? For two reasons:   Laziness is an attribute of munafiqeen. If this wasn&amp;#8217;t bad enough, being lazy leads to procrastination, which leads to its own set of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness After Forgiveness After Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 17:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s a beautiful du&amp;#8217;a that Allah mentions near the end of Surah Baqarah:
وَاعْفُ عَنَّا وَاغْفِرْ لَنَا وَارْحَمْنَا  Translation: So do &amp;#8216;affuw on us. And forgive us. And have mercy on us. [Surah Baqarah, verse 286]
Allah mentions three things, in order:
 &amp;#8216;Affuw &amp;#8216;annaa: Affuw linguistically means to erase something; to obliterate something; to completely destroy something and leave no traces of it whatsoever. This du&amp;#8217;a is saying: make affuw of our sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become a Sadaqa Millionaire</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/become-a-sadaqa-millionaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 19:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/become-a-sadaqa-millionaire/</guid>
      <description>How would you like to give sadaqa? You might say &amp;#8220;sure, I&amp;#8217;d like to do it&amp;#8211;but I have no money!&amp;#8221; What if I told you there&amp;#8217;s a way to give sadaqa that doesn&amp;#8217;t require money? That, in fact, you could even out-class the rich people in their sadaqa! All it takes is a little time and effort!
Would you be interested?
One of the things the companions used to do is compete with each other in good deeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Made the Companions Special</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-made-the-companions-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 16:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-made-the-companions-special/</guid>
      <description>In a report by Abdullah bin `Amr bin `Aas (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu), he related that a woman came to the Messenger of Allah with her daughter. On the daughter&amp;#8217;s wrist were two heavy gold bracelets. The Messenger asked her, &amp;#8220;Do you pay Zakaat on this?&amp;#8221; She replied, &amp;#8220;No.&amp;#8221; The Messenger said: &amp;#8220;Would it please you that Allah will encircle you with two bracelets of fire?&amp;#8221; The reporter commented that she took them off and threw them down in front of the Messenger, and said: &amp;#8220;They are for Allah and his Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Qiyaam-ul-Layl Alarms</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 16:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We all know that we should pray tahajjud, aka qiyaam-ul-layl. It&amp;#8217;s well established in the deen that this is a very, very rewarding thing to do (but it&amp;#8217;s not fard, so don&amp;#8217;t sweat it if you&amp;#8217;re not doing it). Some motivational factors for this include:
 The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) used to pray Qiyaam-ul-Layl until his legs swelled. When asked why&amp;#8211;since Allah has forgiven all his past and future sins, he said: Should I not be a grateful slave?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naseeha From Our Brother Sa’ad Gaya</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/naseeha-from-our-brother-saad-gaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 20:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/naseeha-from-our-brother-saad-gaya/</guid>
      <description>Below is some naseeha from our brother, Sa&amp;#8217;ad Gaya. Sa&amp;#8217;ad was one of those 18 individuals thrown in jail as part of the &amp;#8220;Toronto 18 terrorist plot.&amp;#8221; Despite evidence that the entire plot was spurred by a CSIS mole, despite an increasing lack of any credible evidence, several of these 18 brothers are still languishing in a jail cell.
  My Dear Brothers and Sisters,
I write these words not as one who has any superiority over you , whether in knowledge or deeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reasons Behind Seasons</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Why did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) create seasons? All of this&amp;#8211;snow, leaves changing, hot summer days and freezing winter nights. In some countries&amp;#8211;like Canada, and the US&amp;#8211;you have places where Isha time starts around 11pm, or 12am (midnight), and Fajr starts arond 2-3am! You also have days where Isha starts at 6pm, and Fajr starts around 7am.
What can we learn from this?
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) gives this away when he narrates: &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) made the night short so you can pray, and the day short so you can fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking News</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/breaking-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 22:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/breaking-news/</guid>
      <description>The news is out. Its a BIG one. Media won&amp;#8217;t broadcast it. People wouldn&amp;#8217;t talk about it. The most deadly serial killer is out after a month of imprisonment. He is back to take the revenge. He could in in your neighbourhood right now. To make it worse, he could be in your house with you eating and drinking right now! He is very dedicated, clever, motivated and doesn&amp;#8217;t leave behind any traces!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zaid Recognizes the Black Ant</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zaid-recognizes-the-black-ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 18:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zaid-recognizes-the-black-ant/</guid>
      <description>Zaid: As-Salamu &amp;#8216;Alykum
Abdur-Rahmaan: Wa-Alykum As-salam&amp;#8230;..how was your volunteer experience at the seminar?
Zaid: Alhumdullilah. But&amp;#8230;. I worked so hard for this event but no one came to me and said any thanks or any words of appreciation!
Abdur-Rahmaan: Perhaps if you niyyah was correct, you wouldn&amp;#8217;t be thinking like that. If only you were doing it sincerely for the sake of Allah and expecting reward only from Him. I think you need to see a heart specialist and get some x-rays!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Tasbeeh?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 14:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we now know what hamd means, let&amp;#8217;s move on to tasbeeh!
Tasbeeh means to say subhanAllah just as tahmeed means to say alhamdulillah.
  Tasbeeh is comprised of two words: Subhan and Allah: سبحان الله
Subhan which is derived from tasbeeh is from seen-ba-ha (س-ب-ح) and it means to glorify, praise, magnify, extol Allah, by tongue or by heart. It includes:
1-To say He has no flaw in His Perfection Far above any imperfection</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooba!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 01:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah ta’ala says:
الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ طُوبَىٰ لَهُمْ وَحُسْنُ مَآبٍ  Those who have believed and done righteous deeds – ‘Tooba’ is theirs and a good return. (Suratur Ra’ad, ayah 29)
Allah ta’ala promises ‘Tooba’ to the believers in this ayah. We also know this word for the famous hadeeth of the strangers, the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam states: fa Tooba lil ghurabaa’, so Tooba to the strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levels of Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 15:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
Truly, patience is a characteristic of the Muslim that is required on many levels:
 Patience in worshiping Allah Patience in abstaining from wrong actions Patience at times of trials  These are the three levels we should constantly be monitoring, for verily it is these levels of patience that will bring us success. My dear brothers and sisters, Ramadan is only days away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is they who are Guided</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
My dear brothers and sisters in this beautiful religion of Islam, sometimes we have to sit back and ponder about life and ponder about the purpose of it. Sometimes we know the purpose, yet we fall of track due to the play and amusement of this world. Nonetheless, we should never despair of the mercy of our Lord, for verily He is the Most Merciful and Most Forgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Peace</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Sitting in a halaqah–in a khutbah–in an AlMaghrib class, learning about the deen of Allah– the emanrush, your heart just flutters with tranquility. With satisfaction. With humility. With peace.
Why do we only feel this way in these gatherings?
Allah azza wa jal provides the answer:
He says in Surah Ra’d ayah 28:الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ وَتَطْمَئِنُّ قُلُوبُهُم بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ أَلاَ بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ تَطْمَئِنُّ الْقُلُوب
Those who have believed and whose hearts find satisfaction in the remembrance of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Complain only to Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
I start by asking a very simple question: Where does patience stand within our lives today?
SubhanAllah, what a beautiful trait it is yet we rarely see the implementation of it. Such a beautiful tree by which the sweetest of fruits cultivate and bless our lives, yet we just let it slip away as a &amp;#8220;thing of the past&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Matter What…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum, Time comes and goes; some people grow, some people remain exactly same throughout time.
وَالْعَصْرِ
By the Time!
إِنَّ الْإِنسَانَ لَفِي خُسْرٍ**_
_** Indeed! Mankind is in loss__
Thus, Allah makes clear that by the passing time man is in complete loss. Why? Because they don&amp;#8217;t take heed, they don&amp;#8217;t learn, they don&amp;#8217;t listen, they go on doing what their hearts desire without thinking twice. They (in general) don&amp;#8217;t ponder about the real purpose of their life; they (in general) cover reality with their false notions and desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2500 Sins in a Day</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/2500-sins-in-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2008 09:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/2500-sins-in-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Abdullah bin &amp;#8216;Amr bin al-&amp;#8216;Aas (رضي الله عنه‏) narrated that the Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said:
 There are two characteristics that no servant possesses except that he will enter Paradise. They are both very easy, but those who act upon them are quite few:
The first is that one of you says &amp;#8216;Subhan Allah&amp;#8217; ten times, &amp;#8216;al-Hamdu lillah&amp;#8217; ten times, and &amp;#8216;Allahu Akbar&amp;#8217; ten times after each prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The King of the Body</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-king-of-the-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 20:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-king-of-the-body/</guid>
      <description>The king is the one who rules over the land and has power over it. Every king has soldiers. If the king is righteous, then the soldiers are righteous; and if the king is evil, then the soldiers are evil.
And the body has a king, too&amp;#8211;the Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: &amp;#8220;There is a piece of flesh in the body; if it is righteous, the whole body is righteous; if it is evil, then the whole body is evil; indeed, it is the heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qareen</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 01:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</guid>
      <description>What is a Qareen? A shaytaan, a devil, assigned to someone to mislead and misguide him. Someone to whisper to him in the light of day and the darkness of night. Allah says:
وَمَن يَعْشُ عَن ذِكْرِ الرَّحْمَنِ نُقَيِّضْ لَهُ شَيْطَاناً فَهُوَ لَهُ قَرِينٌ  Translation: And whoever is blinded from remembrance of Ar-Rahman, we appoint for him a qareen, and he is to him a companion. [Surah Az-Zukhruf, verse 36]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ihsaan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ihsaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 20:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ihsaan/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said:
عـن أبي يعـلى شـداد بـن اوس رضي الله عـنه ، عـن الـرسـول صلى الله عـليه وسلم قـال : إن الله كتب الإحـسـان عـلى كــل شيء ، فـإذا قـتـلـتم فـأحسـنوا القـتـلة ، وإذا ذبـحـتم فـأحسنوا الذبحة ، وليحد أحـدكم شـفـرتـه ، ولـيـرح ذبـيـحـته .
رواه مسلم  Translation: Indeed, Allah prescribed ihsaan in all things. Thus, if you kill, kill well; and if you slaughter, slaughter well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Minute Dawa Speech</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-minute-dawa-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 15:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-minute-dawa-speech/</guid>
      <description>If you live in a western society, such as Canada, America, England, and so on, be aware that some scholars have said that, for people living in these societies, da&amp;#8217;wa is fard &amp;#8216;ayn&amp;#8211;an obligation on each and every Muslim. But don&amp;#8217;t be scared&amp;#8211;because the Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: &amp;#8220;By Allah, if Allah were to guide one man through you, it would be better for you than a red camel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Plans for Friday?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 16:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Check out this hadith:
‏إِنَّ مِنْ أَفْضَلِ أَيَّامِكُمْ يَوْمَ الْجُمُعَةِ فَأَكْثِرُوا عَلَيَّ مِنْ الصَّلاَةِ فِيهِ
فَإِنَّ صَلاَتَكُمْ مَعْرُوضَةٌ عَلَيَّ قَالَ فَقَالُوا يَا رَسُولَ اللَّهِ
وَكَيْفَ تُعْرَضُ صَلاَتُنَا عَلَيْكَ وَقَدْ أَرَمْتَ ‏- ‏قَالَ يَقُولُونَ بَلِيتَ
‏قَالَ إِنَّ اللَّهَ تَبَارَكَ وَتَعَالَى حَرَّمَ عَلَى الأَرْضِ أَجْسَادَ الأَنْبِيَاءِ صَلَّى اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِمْ
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Surely, among the best of your days is Friday; so increase in (invoking Allah&amp;#8217;s) salaat upon me during it, for your (invocations for Allah&amp;#8217;s) Salaat (upon me) will be displayed to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hajj Black Dots</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/hajj-black-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/hajj-black-dots/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at the following picture. What do you see?
 
Most people will say they see the black dot. Not the whole field of white dots.
That&amp;#8217;s people for you! Despite all the white dots around us&amp;#8211;our health, wealth, youth, our household, our family, our fine clothing&amp;#8211;we only see the black dots. That guy at work who&amp;#8217;s always talking on the phone. That punk at school who keeps stealing your cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success is For the Believers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 18:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the first few verses of Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon:
قَدْ أَفْلَحَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ فِي صَلَاتِهِمْ خَاشِعُونَ  Translation: Successful are the Believers! Those who establish their salaah with khushoo. [Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon, verses 1-2]
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) carries on to mention many other characteristics of the believer in this surah&amp;#8211;however, the thing to focus on, the thing to ponder about, is that the FIRST characteristic that Allah chooses to describe a believer by&amp;#8211;a person who establishes the salaah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following vs. Obeying</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 15:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-e-Imran ayaat 31-32:
قُلْ إِن كُنتُمْ تُحِبُّونَ اللّهَ فَاتَّبِعُونِي يُحْبِبْكُمُ اللّهُ وَيَغْفِرْ لَكُمْ ذُنُوبَكُمْ وَاللّهُ غَفُورٌ رَّحِيمٌ
قُلْ أَطِيعُواْ اللّهَ وَالرَّسُولَ فإِن تَوَلَّوْاْ فَإِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يُحِبُّ الْكَافِرِينَ  Translation: Say: If you should love Allah, then follow me (so) Allah will love you and forgive your sins. And Allah is Al-Ghafuwr (the All-Forgiving), Ar-Raheem (the All-Mericful). Say, Obey Allah and His Messenger. But if you turn away then indeed, Allah does not love the disbelievers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Qantarah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/al-qantarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 17:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/al-qantarah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Abu Sa’eed al Khudree (رضى الله عنه) reports that the Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said, “when the believers cross the Hellfire, they will be stopped at a small arched bridge (Qantarah) before entering the paradise and will be given retribution for injustices between them until they become purified. (Then) they will be permitted to enter Jannah. So, by the One in Whose Hands is my soul, they will know their way to their homes in Jannah, better than they know their ways to their homes in dunya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zina</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 18:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zina/</guid>
      <description>We live in a world in which the concept of haya between man and women is lost. We forget that at every step Shaytaan waits to pounce, to guide us to evil. Living in the West, going to University, we see a lot of evil, and we see the plan of Shaytaan at work; Muslim men and Muslim women forgetting their boundaries and falling into the fitnah of society. Every wonder what would happen if you die in a state of disobedience to Allah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 8</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 01:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-8/</guid>
      <description>The fact of the matter is that Shaytan is an open enemy to humankind. It is through his whispers that he causes all of us to stray off in to the darkness of evil and misguidance. How else does Shaytan influence humankind? Listen to the podcast and find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worship</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</guid>
      <description>We go through life praying, giving to the poor, fasting, and other forms of worship which are prescribed by Allah. However, when was the last time we sat back and really tried to understand what it means to worship Allah? Why do we worship Him? Listen to the podcast for more details on this crucial aspect of Islam&amp;#8211;worship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the footsteps of Khalilullah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/follow-the-footsteps-of-khalilullah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 14:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/follow-the-footsteps-of-khalilullah/</guid>
      <description>Once upon a time, on the day of Eid-ul-Adha:
Abdullah: As-Salam Alykum, Eid Mubarak..Taqabal Allah minna wa minkom! (May Allah accept it, from us and from you)
Abdur-Rahman: Wa &amp;#8216;Alykum As-salam. Eid Mubarak to you as well.
Abdullah: How has been your Eid day so far?
Abdur-Rahman: Man, I heard this new song today, and kept listening to it :( I know I shouldn&amp;#8217;t have been listening to music, it&amp;#8217;s haram, but I just can&amp;#8217;t give it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Purification Water</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 09:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</guid>
      <description>Can you re-use water used for purification&amp;#8211;wudoo or ghusl? This issue doesn&amp;#8217;t apply to most people unless they&amp;#8217;re stuck somewhere without much water&amp;#8211;like Cambodia, where they get water once a year, during flood season, and keep it for nine months.
(Before you read this, read about the three-fold categorization of water; in summary, water can either be purifying (tuhoor), pure (taahir), or impure (najas), and we can only use purifying water for wudoo and ghusl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Hajj Jackpots</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-hajj-jackpots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-hajj-jackpots/</guid>
      <description>Hajj is an amazing act of ibadah&amp;#8211;one that requires everything: mind, body, and wealth. People invest so much time, so much energy, and so much money into Hajj&amp;#8211;and for what? What do they get out of it?
For a properly-intentioned, well-planned and correctly-executed Hajj&amp;#8211;one free of, for example, arguing, pushing, and harming other Muslims, full of patience&amp;#8211;there are five jackpots you cash out on when you perform Hajj:
 Deeds: The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever performs Hajj to this house&amp;#8211;the Ka&amp;#8217;bah&amp;#8211;and does not commit any obscenity and wrongdoing, he, or she, will come out as the day he or she was born,pure and free from sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Do You Not Love that Allah Should Forgive You?”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 17:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</guid>
      <description>SubhanAllah, we all know the story about the accusations that were forged against &amp;#8216;Aishah (رضالله عنها), but in addition to that story, the tafsir for Surat An-Nur (Surah 24), ayah 22, reveals another story&amp;#8211;a story of forgiveness, a story of compassion, a story demonstrating the superiority of those who act for the sake of Allah (may Allah make us of them).
  Mistah was the cousin of As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Museebah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 12:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-Baqarah:
وَلَنَبْلُوَنَّكُمْ بِشَيْءٍ مِّنَ الْخَوْفِ وَالْجُوعِ وَنَقْصٍ مِّنَ الأَمْوَالِ وَالأنفُسِ وَالثَّمَرَاتِ وَبَشِّرِ الصَّابِرِينَ
الَّذِينَ إِذَا أَصَابَتْهُم مُّصِيبَةٌ قَالُواْ إِنَّا لِلّهِ وَإِنَّا إِلَيْهِ رَاجِعونَ  Translation: And We shall surely test you with something of fear and hunger and a loss of wealth and lives and fruits, but give good tidings to the patient. Those who when disaster strikes them, say, &amp;#8220;Indeed we belong to Allah and indeed to Him we will return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
There are many words in Arabic that translate as &amp;#8220;love&amp;#8221; in English; two of them are hubb and wudd. What is the difference between hubb (حَبَّ) and wudd (وَدَّ)? Hubb, which is from ح ب ب ، means to love. It is a love that you have for someone or something that you keep inside of you&amp;#8211;inner feelings of admiration and fondness. While wudd, from و د د، is a more intense form of hubb, a whole-hearted and deep love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Hajj Gems</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/amazing-hajj-gems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 03:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/amazing-hajj-gems/</guid>
      <description>Did you know:
 The literal meaning of hajj is ‘desire’?   Hajj is one of the main five pillars and all muslims desire to go for hajj.   We should hasten to do it/plan for it as early as possible. [1]   Hajj is expensive, but ALHAMDULILAH we have been given glad tidings: by the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), who said, it eliminates poverty and sin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dua: The Weapon of the Believer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-the-weapon-of-the-believer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 17:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-the-weapon-of-the-believer/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of life is to worship Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and dua is the crux of worship.
Dua: The Weapon of the Believer Video
Dua: Goes hand-in-hand with tawakkul (trust and hope in Allah (سبحانه وتعالى))
Dua is the essence of worship: calling to The One, the Only One who can actually help you and Who actually deserves to be called upon. The One who is As-Samad, The Satisfier of every need; upon Whom everything depends but He depends on no one and nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 21:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-2/</guid>
      <description>What is the second most important pillar of faith? Did you ever think that it was angels? Well it is &amp;#8230; come learn why! What are angels? Who are they? Why should we study the creation of angels? Listen and find out &amp;#8230; because surely securing knowledge of this creation of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) lights up the hearts with eman.
Listen to this podcast to find out the reality of eman, in Ilm Fruits’ exclusive Light of Eman series!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizq Without Measure</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
كُلَّمَا دَخَلَ عَلَيْهَا زَكَرِيَّا الْمِحْرَابَ وَجَدَ عِندَهَا رِزْقاً قَالَ يَا مَرْيَمُ أَنَّى لَكِ هَذَا قَالَتْ هُوَ مِنْ عِندِ اللّهِ إِنَّ اللّهَ يَرْزُقُ مَن يَشَاءُ بِغَيْرِ حِسَابٍ  هُنَالِكَ دَعَا زَكَرِيَّا رَبَّهُ قَالَ رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِن لَّدُنْكَ ذُرِّيَّةً طَيِّبَةً إِنَّكَ سَمِيعُ الدُّعَاءِ  Translation: Every time he entered Al-Mihrab to her, he found her supplied with sustenance. He said: &amp;#8220;O Maryam (Mary)! From where have you got this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 02:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-1/</guid>
      <description>Eman. So simple&amp;#8230;yet we have failed to understood its true place in our deen.
And the man asked, &amp;#8220;What is Eman?&amp;#8221; The Prophet replied, &amp;#8220;It is to believe in Allah and&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
What did the Prophet say about Eman? How does it relate to us? Listen to this podcast to find out the reality of eman, in Ilm Fruits&amp;#8217; exclusive Light of Eman series!
Don&amp;#8217;t miss out! Check the Light of Eman page for the schedule!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jahannam and Jaheem</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/jahannam-and-jaheem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 16:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/jahannam-and-jaheem/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Reminders of the akhirah can have a great effect on our hearts and bring us out of the ghaflah (heedlessness) we are in. By looking at two words, Jahannam and Jaheem from the Qur&amp;#8217;an, we are able to see what the real life is, the real ending and the real punishment. May Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) make our best deeds our last and may He (سبحانه وتعالى) make us among those who will enter Jannah without reckoning or punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness in Front of your Eyes</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/happiness-in-front-of-your-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 11:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/happiness-in-front-of-your-eyes/</guid>
      <description>Time comes and goes, life slips and goes forth, what is to come? No creation knows.
Sometimes, things (سبحانه وتعالى) takes it away, because in His infinite Wisdom it is something which is not good for you. However, what is to say that same thing is not good for you later in life? Time can go by, a jewel can accumulate dust, but with a blow of the mouth and a brush of the hands, it sparkles like new just as it was before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500 Years of Worship</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/500-years-of-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 18:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/500-years-of-worship/</guid>
      <description>500 Years of Worship  By Shaikh Abul Laith Samarkandi
Angel Jibreel (عليه السلام) told Rasulullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) the following incident:
 A man in the past worshipped Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) continuously for 500 years. He was granted a shelter on top of a mountain that was surrounded by salty water. However, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) caused a stream of sweet water to flow through the mountain for that individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charity – Where to Give</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/charity-where-to-give/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 14:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/charity-where-to-give/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I have already donated enough to masajids. I want to help the needy, poor, orphans and widows. Its so hard to find these people here in the west. Back home, it was so easy.&amp;#8221; This is the typical problem that many of us face.
So if you are wondering, how and where should I spend my charity, follow these six steps:
 Niyah Check: Make sure that you are only doing it for Allah, not to please anyone else or get praised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Delayed Response of Du’aa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-delayed-response-of-duaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2007 14:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-delayed-response-of-duaa/</guid>
      <description>A Delayed Response of Du&amp;#8217;aa
An eye-opener for those who believe &amp;#8230;
While talking to himself, Ibn Al-Jawzi blamed his soul in a gentle way. He said:
 I found myself in trouble, and so I made du&amp;#8217;aa (supplication) consistently, all the while requesting relief and comfort. The response to my du&amp;#8217;aa seemed to be delayed, and so my soul became disturbed and worried.
However, I rebuked it saying, &amp;#8220;Woe unto you; look attentively at yourself, are you the one possessed or are you the possessor?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pen is Lifted From Three</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pen-is-lifted-from-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2007 11:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pen-is-lifted-from-three/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The Pen is lifted from three (i.e., their deeds are not recorded):
 a child until he reaches puberty; an insane man until he comes to his senses; one who is asleep until he wakes up.&amp;#8221;  [Recorded in Abu Dawud #4403, and Ibn Majah #2041]
This is an important hadith, fundamental to usool-ul-fiqh. This hadith applies in practically every situation and with every issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</guid>
      <description>So, another Ramadan has come and gone! 30 days of reading Qur&amp;#8217;an and feeding the poor, 30 nights of Qiyaam-ul-Layl and Taraweeh and Tahajjud. And so, &amp;#8216;Eid comes again.
Congratulations! You have been one of those lucky few who lived to receive this great blessing from Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), this chance to get all your sins forgiven! Because the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever fasts during Ramadan out of sincere faith and hoping to attain Allah&amp;#8217;s rewards, then all his past sins will be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Why Are You Fasting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/so-why-are-you-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/so-why-are-you-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Why are you fasting? The answer to this questions determines your reward on Judgment Day. Monks fast. Some poeple fast to lose weight. Is it a cultural thing?
Or is it because Allah is worthy of worship, and only He deserves your fast? That you are seeking His reward? This is what the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;Whoever fasted Ramadan with belief, hoping for the reward from Allah, all his previous sins will be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Amazing Ramadan: Planning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/your-amazing-ramadan-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 14:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/your-amazing-ramadan-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is here, you&amp;#8217;re all excited, praying in the masjid &amp;#8230; but how can you make the MOST of Ramadan? Do you have what it takes to keep your heart in touch, regardless of the distractions around you? To be one of those who look back and realize they&amp;#8217;ve had an AMAZING Ramadan?
Listen to the podcast below to figure out how to plan your Ramadan! Props out to Living Halal for this amazing ilm-tastic podcast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abu Bakr and His Request</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 08:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</guid>
      <description>What do you make of the amazing incident when the best of the sahaba (رضالله عنه) came to the best of the Prophets (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to ask for a du&amp;#8217;a to make in his prayers?
 Narrated Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه) I asked Allah&amp;#8217;s Apostle (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to teach me an invocation so that I may invoke Allah with it in my prayer. He told me to say, [Sahih Bukhari]  (Hover your mouse over each line to see the translation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE Purpose of Creation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-purpose-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-purpose-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>Our purpose of creation is one and that is tawheed. Tawheed is making Allah One and Unique in His Lordship (Ruboobiyyah), in His Names and Attributes (Asmaa was Sifaat), and in His rights to be worshiped (Uloohiyyah). There are many blessings associated with tawheed, of them are:
 Jannah a means for sins to be forgiven the right that Allah has over us the reason for sending Prophets and Books the dangers of its opposite &amp;#8211; shirk  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Role Models–Got Any?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 08:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</guid>
      <description>Who are your role models? Movie stars? Sports stars? Celebrities? Do we have any role models for Ramadan&amp;#8211;people we can look on to and learn from? Let us take a glimpse at how our pious predecessors and the early generations spent their Ramadan.
Their reading of Qur&amp;#8217;an in Ramadan:
 Salam ibn Abi Muti&amp;#8217; informs us that Qatadah used to normally complete reading the Qur&amp;#8217;an in 7 days, but in Ramadan, he completed it in three days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where’s Our Dignity?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wheres-our-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 07:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wheres-our-dignity/</guid>
      <description>Of the beautiful Names of Allah is al-Aziz, the Mighty. Al-Aziz is exalted, perfect in Might, He is the One who grants us victory, and He is the one who hates to have his slaves be humiliated. Dignity, Power, and Glory comes from Allah and Allah alone, and no one can attain this without worshiping Allah. It&amp;#8217;s time to become a true Abdul-Aziz.
Listen to the podcast to learn how exactly you can become a true Abdul-Aziz!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“As-Salaah! As-Salaah!”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/as-salaah-as-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2007 08:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/as-salaah-as-salaah/</guid>
      <description>The importance of salaah can be seen in the seerah of our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم). Allah raised our beloved Prophet to His heights to give him the command of salaah directly, rather than sending it through Angel Jibreel. Also, the importance of salaah is seen in the seerah, when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) was on his death bed, when he had the chance to give one last message that he could give his ummah until the Day of Judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you Established the Salaah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-established-the-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 06:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-established-the-salaah/</guid>
      <description>The greatest command after that of tawheed is of salaah. Allah lays out a list for whom this Qur&amp;#8217;an is a guidance, and amongst the first things He says are about those who establish the salaah; those who guard them strictly and stand in front of Allah with obedience. The example of Prophet Ibrahim (عليه السلام) is amongst the best, and as he builds the ka&amp;#8217;ba, he makes du&amp;#8217;a to Allah to make him amongst those who establish salaah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earn MAXIMUM Profit This Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earn-maximum-profit-this-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 08:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earn-maximum-profit-this-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah,
Ramadan is of a countable number of days, so we have to be smart, and think about how can we MAXIMIZE the rewards we earn! Inshallah following is a list of ibada that take less time and have big reward. We need to be smart and think like a businessman (small investment -&amp;gt; big profit)
Remember reward of every deed is multiplied in Ramadan.
 Get the reward of hajj and umrah every single day Be smart in your dhikar Get the reward of fasting many Ramadans Get the reward of performing salaah the whole night Earn the reward of reciting one third of Qur&amp;#8217;an in few minutes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relax! Who are you Racing?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/relax-who-are-you-racing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 06:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/relax-who-are-you-racing/</guid>
      <description>We at times find ourself in a race with salaah. One of the primary ways to gain khushoo in our salaah is to take our time in it, so much so that our Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) told us to be slow and articulate with each movement&amp;#8211;we should let all our bones rest and then continue on, not before that. No need to race, because this will come back on the Day of Judgment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prophet’s Sermon on the Reception of Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prophets-sermon-on-the-reception-of-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 11:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prophets-sermon-on-the-reception-of-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Below is a well-published Sermon of the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) on Ramadan; if anyone knows the source, please post it in a comment&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s well-known as far as the internet goes!
  &amp;#8220;Indeed ahead of you is the blessed month of Allah. A month of blessing, mercy and forgiveness. A month which, with Allah, is the best of months. Its days, the best of days, its nights, the best of nights, and its hours, the best of hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“If it is sound then the rest of his deeds will be sound…”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/if-it-is-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 07:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/if-it-is-sound/</guid>
      <description>Going on about the importance of salaah, salaah is the first matter that a slave/abd/person will be brought account for on the Day of Judgment. So important is salaah, that Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said that if this one matter is good then everything else will also be good.
Listen to the podcast to gain more understanding on how to make your salaah sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Tips</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 10:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-tips/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me&amp;#8230; and, well, probably a lot of other people, you won’t fully realize that Ramadan is here until you’re dragging yourself out of bed a few hours early to eat while it’s still dark.
Ramadan offers us a very unique opportunity. Ramadan offers us the opportunity to start fresh. It may not necessarily have the &amp;#8220;wash-away-all-your-sins&amp;#8221; publicity that Hajj does, but Ramadan gives us a chance to put ourselves through a mind, body and soul detoxification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitless: Ramadan Planning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</guid>
      <description>My brothers and sisters a blessed month is fast approaching us, a month in which the opportunities are limitless and the reward is ready for taking in abundance. This blessed month, known as Ramadan is approaching us and we will soon say good-bye to it as well.
Inshallah, join me on this journey as we go through some self-planning for this blessed month, and inshallah learn about the one action which is most noble in the sight of Allah&amp;#8230;that action being du&amp;#8217;a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be An Orange</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-an-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 12:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-an-orange/</guid>
      <description>This Ramadan…be an orange!
Say what?
 &amp;#8220;The example of a believer, who recites the Qur&amp;#8217;an and acts on it, is like an orange (utrujjah) which tastes nice and smells nice.
And the example of the believer who does not recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an but acts on it is like a date that tastes sweet but has no smell.
And the example of the hypocrite who recites the Quran is like a sweet basil which smells good but tastes bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Believer?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/are-you-a-believer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 08:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/are-you-a-believer/</guid>
      <description>We sometimes forget the vast importance of salaah in our lives. Successful are the believers. Who are these believers? They are those who offer their salaah with full khushoo, with full submissiveness to Allah, those who establish the salaah.
Listen to the podcast for more details on how you can be among the believers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sayyidul Istaghfar – The Chief of Prayers for Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sayyidul-istaghfar-the-chief-of-prayers-for-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2007 06:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sayyidul-istaghfar-the-chief-of-prayers-for-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>One of the greatest gifts that Allah has blessed us with is the ability to make tawbah and istaghfar after committing sins continuously. He (سبحانه وتعالى) has taught our forefather Adam (عليه السلام) the words of repentance and He taught Rasoolullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) a very special dua. The dua is called the sayyidul istaghfar, and it is one of the pearls from the Sunnah that we should know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pinnacle of Salaah: Khusoo’</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pinnacle-of-salaah-khusoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 20:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pinnacle-of-salaah-khusoo/</guid>
      <description>Khushoo is to be conscious of God, to have taqwa, to have fear of Allah. And so khushoo is something that comes from the heart, and if the heart is clean, then the salaah&amp;#8211;and everything else&amp;#8211;will be clean. There are many ways that one can go about gaining khusoo; a few of them a few are:
 prepare ahead of time by performing wudoo properly use miswak repeat the words of the adhaan make du&amp;#8217;a between the adhaan and the iqaamah  For more information, listen to the podcast below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magnificent Three</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-magnificent-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 10:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-magnificent-three/</guid>
      <description>In our last post, we looked at one of the dhikars taught to us by Rasulullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) We noted that by being smart, we can earn lots of hasanats much more quickly.
The dhikhar was:
  Subhaan Allaah wa bi hamdih, &amp;#8216;adada khalqihi, wa ridaa nafsihi, wazinata &amp;#8216;arshihi, wa midaada kalimaatihi (Glory and praise be to Allaah, as much as the number of His creation, as much as pleases Him, as much as the weight of His Throne and as much as the ink of His words) [Shaheeh Muslim: Book 35, Number 6575]    When I first heard this hadith, I just loved it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umm Sulaym and the Death of her Son</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-sulaym-and-the-death-of-her-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 07:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-sulaym-and-the-death-of-her-son/</guid>
      <description>Remember the story of the companion Umm Sulaym (رضي الله عنها), what an amazing thing about how a wife is with her husband. Her husband, Talha, was out working, and it so happened that day that their son, 10 years old, died.
She had a decision to make: when he comes home should she tell him right away, or should she just bear it and make him happy first and then when he is comfortable and settled in, then tell him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Points From Marriage 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/five-points-from-marriage-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 08:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/five-points-from-marriage-101/</guid>
      <description>Safi Khan, in his &amp;#8220;Marriage 101&amp;#8243; lecture CD (available from here), mentions many points; of the best, he mentions the following:
 For Brothers: use extreme compassion and mercy towards your wives! Almost all relationships could benefit from more mercy and compassion. For Sisters: struggle not to complain! Once complaints start, they only get worse, and in the end, they can spoil your marriage. For Both: have a common goal&amp;#8211;to serve Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), to worship Him, and to enter Jannah together, without reckoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Dignity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/protect-your-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/protect-your-dignity/</guid>
      <description>With the Facebook craze that has struck us all in the past months, we have forgotten about a very serious matter that our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسل) talked about, and that matter being exposing of ones sins. We post messages on peoples walls, we post up pictures and what not, and its all exposing our sins to the public. We should be very cautious of the environment and inshallah try our best to protect our own dignity but also the dignity and respect of our brothers and sisters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typical</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 08:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</guid>
      <description>Typ‧i‧cal: Conforming to a particular type. For someone to be &amp;#8220;typical&amp;#8221;, he/she would be one who conforms to his society and behaves much like his environment.
Typical in the 21st century: clubbing, flirting, sex, drugs, alcohol, stealing, cheating, swearing, injustice, premarital relations, immodesty, and the list goes on and on.
So who&amp;#8217;s typical? Is it the one who refrains from all the above, or the one indulges in it? Is it the one who&amp;#8217;s perceived weird when he speaks out against someone swearing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe for Being Worry-Free</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/recipe-for-being-worry-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2007 06:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/recipe-for-being-worry-free/</guid>
      <description>بَلَى مَنْ أَسْلَمَ وَجْهَهُ لِلّهِ وَهُوَ مُحْسِنٌ فَلَهُ أَجْرُهُ عِندَ رَبِّهِ وَلاَ خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلاَ هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ  Translation: Nay, but whoever submits his face (himself) to Allah and he is a Muhsin then his reward is with his Lord (Allah), on such shall be no fear, nor shall they grieve. [Suratul Baqarah, verse 112]
1. Submit to Allah = fulfill the faraidh and abandon the haram
2. Be a Muhsin = do ibadah as if you see Allah, treat parents outstandingly, fulfill the rights of others outstandingly…basically, do good at every opportunity and whatever you do, try to be outstanding in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Smart</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2007 15:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-smart/</guid>
      <description>What if you were asked to praise Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) in the best possible way, using the best possible words? What words would you pick? Subhanallah, look at the words of our beloved prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم):
Juwairiya (رضي الله عنها) reported that Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم) came out from her apartment in the morning as she was busy in observing her Fajr prayer in her place of worship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/keys-to-paradise-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 23:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/keys-to-paradise-2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Whoever wishes to be delivered from the fire (of Hell) and enter the garden (of Paradise) should die with faith in Allah and the Last Day and should treat the people as he wishes to be treated by them.&amp;#8221;
[Muhammad &amp;#8211; Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) as recorded in Sahih Muslim]
1. Make a list of people you deal with:
 Parents Friends Co-workers  _2. Write how you would want to be treated in each of those roles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Ghafuwr and Al-Ghaffaar</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 08:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</guid>
      <description>Of Allah&amp;#8217;s greatest names is Al-Ghafuwr (الغَفُور). It&amp;#8217;s one of the most common names mentioned in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (91 times). The name itself is on the pattern that denotes a very powerful doer of an action.
Linguistic Meaning: The root of Al-Ghaffuwr and Al-Ghaffar is the verb is ghafara (غَفَرَ), which does NOT mean &amp;#8220;to forgive&amp;#8221;; rather, it means to shield and protect and cover. Like a helmet, which, in Arabic, is called a &amp;#8220;mighfaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Qahhar – The Subduer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</guid>
      <description>ٱلۡقَهَّارُ &amp;#8211; Al Qahhar  The root word for ٱلۡقَهَّارُ is قَهر which is defined as:
 to compel something or someone against his/her wishes to subdue to overcome to force [1]  Thus, with regards to Allah (سبحانه وتعال), the noble name Al-Qahhar can be translated as &amp;#8220;the Subduer, i.e. the Subduer of His creatures by His sovereign authority and power and the Disposer of them as He pleases, with and against their will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etiquettes of Eating</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/etiquettes-of-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 07:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/etiquettes-of-eating/</guid>
      <description>Islam is a deen&amp;#8211;a complete, total, and comprehensive way of life. Islam teaches us everything, from how to worship Allah (سبحانه وتعال), to how to eat, sleep, socialize, govern a state, perform financial transactions, everything!
What, then, are some of the etiquettes of eating?
&amp;#8216;Umar bin Abu Salamah (رضي الله عنه) reported: Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم), said to me, &amp;#8220;Mention Allah&amp;#8217;s Name (i.e., say Bismillah before you start eating), eat with your right hand, and eat from what is near you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Rumors</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wild-rumors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 02:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wild-rumors/</guid>
      <description>After the battle of Uhud, &amp;#8216;Aisha (رضالله عنها) lost her necklace; so while the Muslim army moved forward, she stayed behind to find it. The army had a lost-and-found guy&amp;#8211;Sawfan ibn Mu&amp;#8217;atib (رضالله عنه)&amp;#8211;who travelled behind the army and picked up lost items. So when he saw her, he immediately said la hawla wa la quwwata illa billah (there is no might or power except Allah), hopped off his camel, and let her go on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Minute at a Time</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-minute-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 03:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-minute-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>Everybody wants to read the Qur&amp;#8217;an more&amp;#8211;and why not? The Word of Allah, no less&amp;#8211;unfiltered, unmodified, eternal; guidance for the entire planet. Yet many of us&amp;#8211;even Arabs, who understand and have no problems reading and reciting&amp;#8211;procrastinate and put off reading the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
So try this inshaAllah: every day, read and recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an for at least one minute. Try it. I mean, one minute is hardly time enough to do anything&amp;#8211;so you have no excuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Fitnah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-meaning-of-fitnah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2007 11:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-meaning-of-fitnah/</guid>
      <description>In the old days, back when people used to actually use gold coins, forgeries abounded; so how do you tell the difference between a real gold coin and a fake gold coin? How can you tell the percentage that&amp;#8217;s real or not?
The answer is, you put it through a test.
أَحَسِبَ النَّاسُ أَن يُتْرَكُوا أَن يَقُولُوا آمَنَّا وَهُمْ لَا يُفْتَنُونَ
وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا الَّذِينَ مِن قَبْلِهِمْ فَلَيَعْلَمَنَّ اللَّهُ الَّذِينَ صَدَقُوا وَلَيَعْلَمَنَّ الْكَاذِبِينَ  Translation: Do people think that they will be left alone because they say: &amp;#8220;We believe,&amp;#8221; and will not be tested?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do YOU want for your children?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-do-you-want-for-your-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 09:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-do-you-want-for-your-children/</guid>
      <description>Most parents love their children so much &amp;#8212; they sacrifice their time, wealth, and energy in ensuring all their children&amp;#8217;s needs are met or surpassed! They pray for their well-being, and also plan in advance to give them the best educate them accordingly to have the best career, so they can get the best house and car. But how often do we see parents planning for their child&amp;#8217;s deen? If we want the best in this life for our children, then why don&amp;#8217;t we want the best ETERNAL life for them in the akheera?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Travelling</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-for-travelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 08:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-for-travelling/</guid>
      <description>Whether you travel by foot or by bike, by bus or by car, by train or by plane, you should recite the du&amp;#8217;a the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) taught us &amp;#8212; because du&amp;#8217;as are always for our protection.
This du&amp;#8217;a, in particular, comes in handy these days, since so many people have to commute to school or work.
Allah says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
لِتَسْتَوُوا عَلَى ظُهُورِهِ ثُمَّ تَذْكُرُوا نِعْمَةَ رَبِّكُمْ إِذَا اسْتَوَيْتُمْ عَلَيْهِ وَتَقُولُوا سُبْحانَ الَّذِي سَخَّرَ لَنَا هَذَا وَمَا كُنَّا لَهُ مُقْرِنِينَ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance That Benefits</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/inheritance-that-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 06:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/inheritance-that-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Death. It&amp;#8217;s inevitable. It&amp;#8217;s one of the certainties of life. No one denies it and no one can escape it. And once you&amp;#8217;re dead, your good deeds stop. Except in the following ways:
Abu Hurayrah (رضالله عنه) reported that Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;When a human being dies, all of his deeds are TERMINATED, except for three types:
 An ongoing charity (aka sadaqah jariyah)
 A knowledge (of Islam) from which others benefit,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Uncles of the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-uncles-of-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 09:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-uncles-of-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>During the 23 years of revelation, the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) had many supporters and opponents, including his two uncles&amp;#8211;Abu Talib (the father of Ali (رضالله عنه)), and Abdul &amp;#8216;Uzza ibn Abdul-Muttalib, aka Abu Lahab.
Subhanallah, even within two uncles of the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم), we see great differences. Compare and constrast them:
Abu Talib:
 Extended his protection to his nephew, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), even though the Quresh wanted to kill him Wrote strong, emotional poetry during the boycott of Mecca in order to move people towards nullifying it Commanded his sons to sleep in the Prophet&amp;#8217;s (صلي الله عليه وسلم) bed at night, so that if any assassins came, the sons would die instead of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said regarding him: because of me, he will be in the lightest part of the Hellfire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should I Study?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/why-should-i-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2007 08:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/why-should-i-study/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago in Uzbekistan, a baby boy was born blind. His Mother, the strong mu&amp;#8217;minah that she was, did not lose sight of He who had the Power to cure him. She prayed and prayed for her son&amp;#8217;s sight. And within a few years, the boy regained his eyes.
She was widowed, the boy orphaned. She traveled with him to Makkah so that he could receive an Islamic education. She arranged for him to attend the circles of the scholars, and in those circles, he excelled in the science of hadith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice from an Older Brother: Study your Deen</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/advice-from-an-older-brother-study-your-deen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 08:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/advice-from-an-older-brother-study-your-deen/</guid>
      <description>From a lecture given at MIST Nationals 2006 by Abu Ammaar Yasir Qadhi
Friday July 21st, 2006
Knowledge and Studying your Deen  &amp;#8220;I am here in front of you today, and if I were to choose again, I would go back and do the same thing and do religious studies. I can&amp;#8217;t even remember what courses I took when I was at UH. My main motivation for choosing to do Islamic studies was that I realized I needed to do something for the ummah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gems From Hassan Al-Basri</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/gems-from-hassan-al-basri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 07:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/gems-from-hassan-al-basri/</guid>
      <description>Umar Ibn Hubayra Al-Fazari was the governor of Iraq in the period of the Khilafa of Yazid Ibn Abdul-Malik of the Bani Umayyah. Hassan Ibn Yasar Al-Basri once came to the court of Umar Ibn Hubayra and said to him:
&amp;#8220;O Ibn Hubayra! Fear Allah when you obey Yazid, and do not fear Yazid when you obey Allah. Know that Allah will protect you from Yazid, but Yazid can not protect you from Allah (سبحانه وتعال)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sincerity and Conformity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sincerity-and-conformity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2007 01:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sincerity-and-conformity/</guid>
      <description>For any action to be accepted by Allah (سبحانه وتعال), it has to meet two requirements: sincerity and conformity. Sincerity means that the action must be done purely to earn the pleasure of Allah, and not for other reasons (such as &amp;#8220;because it&amp;#8217;s cool&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;because my friends are doing it&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;so the community will love me&amp;#8221;).
Conformity means that the action must be done in conformity with Shari&amp;#8217;ah, the Qur&amp;#8217;an and the Sunnah of the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path of Goodness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-path-of-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 00:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-path-of-goodness/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعال) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
فَأَمَّا مَن أَعْطَى وَاتَّقَى
وَصَدَّقَ بِالْحُسْنَى
فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْيُسْرَى
وَأَمَّا مَن بَخِلَ وَاسْتَغْنَى
وَكَذَّبَ بِالْحُسْنَى
فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْعُسْرَى
وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّى
إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا لَلْهُدَى
وَإِنَّ لَنَا لَلْآخِرَةَ وَالْأُولَى  Translation: &amp;#8220;So for him who gives in charity, fears Allah, and testifies to goodness, We shall facilitate for him the Path of good. As for him who is stingy and considers himself independent of Allah and rejects the goodness, We shall facilitate for him the Path to evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Investment</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-perfect-investment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 23:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-perfect-investment/</guid>
      <description>We go through our entire lives looking for that perfect investment; whether it be our education, our jobs or our wealth. We put in so much time to gather information and to make sure that our investment will yield a satisfying return. In the end though, there is no certainty of the return on investment that we will gain, it could be 5%, 10%, or even -10%. We never know whether we will gain or lose from the investment that we make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evils of Interest</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-evils-of-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2007 02:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-evils-of-interest/</guid>
      <description>The Evils of Interest, with Practical Examples  Why is interest evil?
Allah Forbade Interest  Allah says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
الَّذِينَ يَأْكُلُونَ الرِّبَا لاَ يَقُومُونَ إِلاَّ كَمَا يَقُومُ الَّذِي يَتَخَبَّطُهُ الشَّيْطَانُ مِنَ الْمَسِّ ذَلِكَ بِأَنَّهُمْ قَالُواْ إِنَّمَا الْبَيْعُ مِثْلُ الرِّبَا وَأَحَلَّ اللّهُ الْبَيْعَ وَحَرَّمَ الرِّبَ  Translation: Those who devour usury will not stand except as stand one whom the Evil one by his touch Hath driven to madness. That is because they say: &amp;#8220;Trade is like usury,&amp;#8221; but Allah hath permitted trade and forbidden usury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Love of Your Life</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-love-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 08:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-love-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>One of the best things about Islam is that it&amp;#8217;s a deen&amp;#8211;a total, comprehensive, complete, and perfect way of life, and it governs every aspect of life from large-scale social phenomena (such as marriage) to the way you eat and sleep.
For people who are dating, subhanallah, they say they&amp;#8217;re looking for that &amp;#8220;special someone&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the right person.&amp;#8221; But they continue dating for 6 months, a year, two years, five years, TEN years, they have kids&amp;#8211;they&amp;#8217;re still just dating&amp;#8211;and they STILL don&amp;#8217;t know!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breach of Covenant</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/breach-of-covenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2007 08:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/breach-of-covenant/</guid>
      <description>Breach of Covenant  Surah Baqarah. The name conjures to mind the story&amp;#8211;the cow, Bani Israeel, Prophet Musa (عليه السلام), the creation of Adam (عليه السلام), the origin of magic, and others. The longest surah in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
Breach of Covenant is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef. It teaches tafseer&amp;#8211;the text, the lessons, the gems. Explore Surah Baqarah in a light you&amp;#8217;ve never seen it through before. Learn, ayah by ayah, the meanings of the first juz of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, and open your eyes to the deeper patterns, the deeper lessons, the deeper benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reap Reward Recurringly</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/reap-reward-recurringly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 01:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/reap-reward-recurringly/</guid>
      <description>Salmaan Al-Farasi (رضي الله عنه) said: I expect Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to reward me in my sleep as he rewards me in my tahajjud.
Why would he expect that? Because he unlocked the secret: Allah rewards all normal deeds, if done with the intention to please Him, the same as acts of &amp;#8216;ibaadah. Why? Because the right intention upgrades it to the next level!
&amp;#8220;So,&amp;#8221; you might ask, &amp;#8220;what kind of intentions might someone have to reap this reward in their sleep?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any Last Words?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/any-last-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 14:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/any-last-words/</guid>
      <description>The day the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) died, what was the last thing he did? He used siwak to clean his mouth. Then he raised his hands and said &amp;#8220;Allahumma ar-rafeeq al-&amp;#8216;ala&amp;#8221; (o Allah, the highest friends &amp;#8212; the closest companions to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) in the Hereafter)&amp;#8211;and then he died (صلي الله عليه وسلم).
Commenting on this, his beloved wife &amp;#8216;Aisha (رضي الله عنها) said: no Prophet lives except he is given a choice between the dunya (this word) and the akhira (the next life), and all of them chose the next life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Nature is Insatiable</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 02:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</guid>
      <description>Human Nature is Insatiable  Human nature is insatiable. No matter how much you get, you will never be happy with it. That is the way we have been created. The key to happiness is not to get it all, but rather, to be content with little.
&amp;#8220;O Allah, I seek refuge in Thee from incapacity, from sloth, from cowardice, from miserliness, from decrepitude, and from the torment of the grave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Empowering Beliefs from ibn Al-Khattab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/four-empowering-beliefs-from-ibn-al-khattab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 12:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/four-empowering-beliefs-from-ibn-al-khattab/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), the second khalifa, had four beliefs that made it easier for him to bear calamities:
 The situation could have been worse. It didn’t strike him in his religion. Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) will reward him with Jannah in return inshallah. When he remembered the hardship of losing the Prophet(صلي الله عليه وسلم) everything else faded away.  Subhanallah, these are profound beliefs from the second khalifa that we can all benefit from!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victory Comes With Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 12:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said to his cousin: &amp;#8220;And know that victory comes with patience, relief with affliction, and ease with hardship. 1
Even in the battle of Qadisiyyah, after fighting through the whole day, the Muslim leader said &amp;#8220;just be patient, and keep fighting.&amp;#8221; Even into the night, when most armies stop fighting at night! But subhanallah, what happened? By the next morning, the Muslims had won.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two for the Price of One</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-for-the-price-of-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2007 22:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-for-the-price-of-one/</guid>
      <description>Allah says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
فَإِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْراً
إِنَّ مَعَ الْعُسْرِ يُسْراً  Translation: So verily, with the hardship, there is relief; Verily, with the hardship, there is relief! [Surah Ash-Shrah, verses 5-6]
Two for the price of one! How&amp;#8217;s that for a deal?
So if you find yourself in a position of hardship, ask yourself: What ease am I forgetting?
And also, the use of with, shows that the two are so closely related as to be companions&amp;#8211;they are together!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Around Salaah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/schedule-around-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2007 03:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/schedule-around-salaah/</guid>
      <description>Not enough time to do what you want in life? Are you over-worked, over-stressed, and over-tired? Looking for that one key element that&amp;#8217;ll make everything fall into place time-wise?
Schedule around salaah. Try it&amp;#8211;plan your day around your salaah. &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ll do x, y, z after Fajr.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;I can fit these things in before Dhur &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Sorry bro, I can&amp;#8217;t meet up until after Isha&amp;#8221; etc.
And see the difference it makes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QMajd Issue 1: Rules of Engagement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/qmajd-issue-1-rules-of-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 05:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/qmajd-issue-1-rules-of-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who haven&amp;#8217;t heard of the AlMaghrib institute, you&amp;#8217;re missing out&amp;#8211;they give some mashallah amazing double-weekend Islamic classes.
Qabeelat Majd (QMajd) is the Toronto branch. Mashallah, through the dedicated efforts of some dozen or so people, they finally published their first newsletter! It&amp;#8217;s for the Rules of Engagement class (click to learn more about the class), so it covers the subject of akhlaaq&amp;#8211;manners, etiquettes, dealings with Allah, with people, with yourself&amp;#8211;and contains such fruitful topics as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you remember?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-you-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 19:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-you-remember/</guid>
      <description>Why are we on this earth? This time, this place. People, make the use of the situation based on a cycle. The EAT-WORK-SLEEP cycle, which I believe turns out to be boring. Monday work starts, lasts till friday. Then again the same old weekend, were some claim to enjoy.
Or lets look at life as a whole. A person is born, goes to school, goes to university/ college, gets a job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distance of One Mile</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</guid>
      <description>In a very beautiful hadith, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: __
 “There are seven whom Allah will shade in His Shade on the Day when there is no shade except His Shade:
 a just ruler; a youth who grew up in the worship of Allah, the Mighty and Majestic; a man whose heart is attached to the mosques; two men who love each other for Allah’s sake, meeting for that and parting upon that; a man who is called by a woman of beauty and position [for illegal intercourse], but be says: ‘I fear Allah’; a man who gives in charity and hides it, such that his left hand does not know what his right hand gives in charity; and a man who remembered Allah in private and so his eyes shed tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearer of Beautiful Fragrance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/bearer-of-beautiful-fragrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 05:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/bearer-of-beautiful-fragrance/</guid>
      <description>In the fast-paced world we live in, we often lose the righteousness needed to attain the closeness to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) that we desire. We go through constant struggles, fighting with ourselves to do what is good and to stay on The Straight Path. At times we prosper and succeed, but much of the time, we lose the fight, but why? Why do we succumb to the temptations of this world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</guid>
      <description>Innal-Hamdu lillah was-Salaatu was-Salaam `alaa Rasoolillah
&amp;ldquo;Lucky escape &amp;hellip; hmmm &amp;hellip; Nah! It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t my time to go yet; Allah saved me and gave me a little longer &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Driving home from work after having a late staff meeting, it was an ordinary evening not much traffic on the road. I got onto the dual carriage, I was in the right lane doing around 60-70 miles an hour, then all of a sudden *BANG* the bonnet of my car flew open and smashed against my car windscreen, *SMASH* all the glass cracked and from the great impact, my back view mirror had completely broken off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eh! You Wanna Enter Jannah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eh-you-wanna-enter-jannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 04:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eh-you-wanna-enter-jannah/</guid>
      <description>Attaining Jannah can be easy if we want it to be. The choice is ours to make. Just take a step towards Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and watch!
To make things easy, it is reported that Abu Umamah said: The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: “Whoever recites Ayatul-Kursi immediately after each prescribed prayer, there will be nothing standing between him and his entering Paradise except death.” (Reported by An-Nasa’i and Ibn Hibban)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Step Towards Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/take-a-step-towards-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 02:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/take-a-step-towards-allah/</guid>
      <description>So, do you want to enter Jannah? Think about it for a second.
OK, that was an easy one. Here&amp;#8217;s a more difficult question, how do you plan on getting there? Take your time and think about that one.
That thinking in and of itself will help you get to Jannah, inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) will make the path easier for those who sincerely desire to come closer to Him and find ways to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Grateful to Your Lord</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/being-grateful-to-your-lord/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 04:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/being-grateful-to-your-lord/</guid>
      <description>Truly, Allah is most gracious and merciful to us, but most of us are not thankful. Try the alhamdulillah game &amp;#8211; come up with a list of everything we should say alhamdulillah for. Try it with your brother and sister and mother and father and son and daughter.
To start,-
 Alhamdulillah for the fact that Allah gave us the ability to thank and praise Him, yet we could never thank Him enough for what He gave us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Can Recite a Third of the Qur’an Tonight?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/who-can-recite-a-third-of-the-quran-tonight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 02:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/who-can-recite-a-third-of-the-quran-tonight/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ll tell you who can. YOU!
Thats right my brothers and sisters, recite a third of the Qur&amp;#8217;an in just one minute every night!
How?
Al-Bukhari (رحمالله) recorded from Abu Sa`id (رضي الله عنه), that the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said to his Companions, &amp;#8220;Is one of you not able to recite a third of the Qur&amp;#8217;an in a single night?&amp;#8221; This was something that was difficult for them and they said, &amp;#8220;Which of us is able to do that, O Messenger of Allah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losers!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2007 21:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/losers/</guid>
      <description>I walked by as I noticed a bunch of people moved by music, indulged in gossip, purchased tickets from each other &amp;#8230; until I spotted my younger sister, Ayesha. I signed, looking at them, as I commented to her, &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;bunch of losers.&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8220;What makes you think they are all losers?&amp;#8221; questioned Ayesha.
&amp;#8220;Well, look at all the things they are indulged in? They&amp;#8217;re obviously losers,&amp;#8221; I responded, as we both noticed other people carrying on with their activities disapprovingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 17:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rejected/</guid>
      <description>On the Authority of the Mother of the Faithful, Umm Abdullah Aa’isha (رضي الله عنها) who said:
&amp;#8220;The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, ‘Whoever innovates something in this matter of ours that is not from it will have it rejected.&amp;rsquo;&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Holy Qur’an:
“This day, those disbelieved have given up all hope of your religion, so fear them not, but fear Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Your Intentions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/watch-your-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 19:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/watch-your-intentions/</guid>
      <description>There are many times throughout our daily activities that we do things without clarifying the intention to ourselves. We may buy a new car but end up doing it to raise our status in society or for pride. At the same time though, we may buy a car and do it solely for Allah&amp;#8217;s cause, and in this there is good. Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
&amp;#8220;So whomsoever does good equal to the wieght of an atom (or a small ant), shall see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 17:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/think/</guid>
      <description>To continue our series of ways to purify our salaah, a very important aspect is to take some time and to actually reflect and think about the ayaat being recited.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
(This is) a Book (the Qur&amp;#8217;an) which We have sent down to you, full of blessings that they may ponder over its Verses, and that men of understanding may remember.”
&amp;#8211; Surah Saad 38:29 Now the word ponder has strong implications in this translation of the verse quoted above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Severe Consequence</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-severe-consequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 03:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-severe-consequence/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Be not like those who forgot Allah, as a result Allah caused them to forget themselves, it is they who are the transgressors&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8211; Surah Hashr V.19 A very powerful ayah in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, very powerful indeed for those who ponder and reflect upon the words of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). This one ayah speaks to many amongst our ummah in this day and age at the same time shows us the results of their doings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imam Abu Hanifa: A True Tradesman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2006 11:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</guid>
      <description>Once, a women came to Abu Hanifa (رحمالله) to sell a silk garment. Abu Hanifa asked &amp;#8221; How much is it?&amp;#8221; She replied, &amp;#8220;one hundred.&amp;#8221; He said, &amp;#8220;It is worth more than a hundred. How much?&amp;#8221;
So the woman increased the price by hundred, and again, and when it reached four hundred, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;It should be more than that.&amp;#8221; The woman said, &amp;#8221; you are mocking me.&amp;#8221;
So, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;bring a man to value it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money, Power, Respect</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/money-power-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 16:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/money-power-respect/</guid>
      <description>How do we attain money, power, and respect?
The path is easy, you follow the way of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and the commands of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), then inshallah you will attain the money, the power, and the respect. Now it is up to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) whether He blesses you with such things. However, with sincerity in your actions, the chances are high.
The overlying goal is to keep Islam in your heart; thrive for it, live to please Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), do all your actions in accordance to the sunnah, and follow the commands of The Al-Mighty, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Days of the Year</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Are you a student, or working? Are you depressed or frustrated that you could not take the advantage of the last ten nights of Ramadan? There were midterms, assignments, and projects for all the working folk, all those cliched reasons, or maybe you did take advantage. Here is another chance. Its on our doorsteps, the most beloved days to Allah, the first ten days of Dhul Hijjah.
It was reported by Ibn ‘Abbas (رضي الله عنه) that the Rasoolullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;There are no days in which righteous deeds are more beloved to Allah than these ten days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptions of the Believers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/descriptions-of-the-believers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 19:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/descriptions-of-the-believers/</guid>
      <description>How does it feel after reading Qur&amp;#8217;an? Does it make a difference in us? How much do we implement it regularly, or even within the same day of reading an ayah?
When learning from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and the seerah of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), Allah mentions a believers qualities in the Qur&amp;#8217;an. The believers hearts become fearful and their eyes tear. This is a sign of the true believers, as Allah describes them in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceiving Isn’t Reality</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/percieving-isnt-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2006 21:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/percieving-isnt-reality/</guid>
      <description>Remember that the outcome of our actions are in the Will of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and nothing else. Our efforts do not convey a certainty towards the outcome whatsoever. There are times where you study, study, study for a test and only score a 60. Then there are times you may just briefly glance over your notes the night before and score an 80.
Is it by luck?
No.
This shows that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) is The One in control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice and Slow</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/nice-and-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2006 14:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/nice-and-slow/</guid>
      <description>Continuing in our series of ways to attain purification in salaah: Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur’an:
وَرَتِّلِ الْقُرْآنَ تَرْتِيلاً  “&amp;#8230; and recite the Qur’an in slow, measured rhythmic tones” (Surah al-Muzammil 73:4)
From this alone, we see the importance of reciting the Qur’an in a proper manner–slowly and with a rythmic tone–and not just whizzing through it as if we were reading a magazine of some sort. Also, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) had a recitation which was clear, with each letter proncounced distinctly (Ahmad, 6&amp;frasl;294, saheeh).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Defined</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/family-defined/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 02:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/family-defined/</guid>
      <description>After years of dawah the people of Nuh (عليه سلام), Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) revealed to Nuh (عليه سلام) (interpretation of the meaning) &amp;#8220;None of thy people will believe except those who have believed already! So grieve no longer over their (evil) deeds.&amp;#8221; (Surah Hud, verse 35)
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) instructed Nuh (عليه سلام) to build an ark, and that the sinners will drown in a flood. As Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) states in Qur&amp;#8217;an (to the interpretation of the meaning): &amp;#8220;But construct an Ark under Our eyes and Our inspiration, and address Me no (further) on behalf of those who are in sin: for they are about to be overwhelmed (in the Flood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Ain’t Cheap</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/talk-aint-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/talk-aint-cheap/</guid>
      <description>One of the diseases we experience in our culture is cheap talk. People say things all the time, whether they mean it or not. Worse, people lie as easily as they breathe&amp;#8211;sometimes, even as often&amp;#8211;and sometimes, under the guise of &amp;#8220;just kidding!&amp;#8221;
But is talk cheap? Let&amp;#8217;s look at some evidence from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah.
 Shahada: People enter Islam when they take the shahada&amp;#8211;in other words, when they say certain words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call of Jahiliyyah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-call-of-jahiliyyah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 17:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-call-of-jahiliyyah/</guid>
      <description>Once a young man from the Muhajiruwn and a young man from the Ansaar quarreled. So the muhajirun called out for help stating: &amp;#8220;O Muhajiruwn!&amp;#8221; And the ansaari said: &amp;#8220;O Ansaar!&amp;#8221; The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) heard this and said: &amp;#8221;Is it with the call off jahiliyyah that you are calling out, and I am present amongst you!&amp;#8221; (Bukhari)
Allah loves Muhajiruwn and Ansaar. Allah states (interpretation of the meaning) : &amp;#8220;And [those Allah grants mercy on includes] the first to embrace Islam from the Muhajiruwn and the Ansaar, and those who followed them in goodness, beliefs and actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/love-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 02:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/love-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Want to earn the love of Allah? Imagine! To be loved by the greatest, the self-sufficient, the lord of the universe! Who doesn&amp;#8217;t want that? Read on inshallah and find out how to achieve that lofty goal!
Love of Allah  Ibn al-Qaiyim (رحمالله) mentioned ten causes that result in Allah&amp;#8217;s (سبحانه وتعالى) love for His slave and the slave&amp;#8217;s love for his Lord. [These ten are:]
First, recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an while pondering over its meanings and what is meant by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Du’a</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-meaning-of-dua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 20:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-meaning-of-dua/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;#8220;du&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8221; is the verbal noun of the verb &amp;#8220;da&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8221;, which means &amp;#8220;to call out, to summon.&amp;#8221;
With that said, du&amp;#8217;a is a fundamental aspect of Islam, and without it, one&amp;#8217;s eman cannot be intact. Allah mentions du&amp;#8217;a in the Qur&amp;#8217;an to signify many things, such as:
 Worship: وَلاَ تَدْعُ مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ مَا لاَ يَنْفَعُكَ وَلاَ يَضُرُّكَ 
Translation: &amp;#8220;And do not call besides Allah that which will not harm you or benefit you&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; [Surah Yunus, 10:106].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract the Honey, but do not Break the Hive</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/extract-the-honey-but-do-not-break-the-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 00:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/extract-the-honey-but-do-not-break-the-hive/</guid>
      <description>The following is an excerpt from &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t be Sad&amp;#8221; by Shaykh Aaidh ibn Abdullah Al-Qarni.
Extract the Honey, but do not break the Hive  Everything that has gentleness within it is beautified, and whatever lacks it is spoiled. When you meet someone, giving them a bright smile and a kind word, you are displaying a characteristic of the truly successful person, a characteristic that even a bee exhibits. When a bee lands on a flower (doing so for a practical purpose) it does not destroy it, because Allah rewards gentleness with that which He does give for harshness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s a Bird, It’s a Plane, It’s … MuminMan?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muminman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 00:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muminman/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s a bird, it&amp;#8217;s a plane, it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8230; MuminMan?  By night, a city slicker patrols the streets. Seen but not seen, he&amp;#8217;s just another face in the crowd, unnoticed with trendy glasses and the slickest new Nike running shoes. He breezes in and out through bars and clubs. He chills with his friends. And if she&amp;#8217;s not mad, maybe he&amp;#8217;ll call his girlfriend for a date. Just your ordinary homeboy or girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Parable of Grass</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-parable-of-grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-parable-of-grass/</guid>
      <description>It rained today. And rained. And rained. And as I walked through the rain, I noticed three distinct types of ground: pavement, grass, and flooded grass.
As rain falls on the pavement, it streams off, making the surface slick and slippery, or else pools. Drainage systems handle large amounts of water, but those have their own cost. As for pools, what do they do? They erode away slowly at the pavement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Last Prayer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-last-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 23:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-last-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Getting further in our discussion on the means to attain the utmost purification in our salaah; one of the best ways is to realize that it may be our last salaah we offer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). So the question is, how do you wanna go out?
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Remember death in your prayer, for the man who remembers death during his prayer is bound to pray properly, and pray the prayer of a man who does not think that he will pray any other prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Concerns You?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-concerns-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 12:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-concerns-you/</guid>
      <description>Concerns of a med student:
Ahmed: I&amp;#8217;ve been trying so hard to make it into that post med program.
Friend: Hey, what about meeting with Dr.Muneeb. Just go ask him what you need to get in, he is THE BEST doctor.
Ahmed: You think I havent already? I am practically following ALL his footsteps to the best to my ability &amp;#8230; just sometimes I get concerned if I&amp;#8217;m still going to make it or not &amp;#8230; hope I can achieve all the marks I need before its too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Scholars</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/code-of-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 12:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/code-of-scholars/</guid>
      <description>Code of Scholars  Code of Scholars is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef. The course teaches the basics of the science of Usool ul-Fiqh, derived from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah. What does haram mean? Who makes laws? What are the different types of fard actions? What Arabic keywords indicate something is haram? Students who succeed gain the ability to analyze contradicting fatawa and determine which are more correct islamically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: Preperation is KEY!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-preperation-is-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2006 12:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-preperation-is-key/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of the purification of salaah, one of the primary ways to gain khushoo’ is to prepare ahead of time! Try these authentic actions from the sunnah:
 Perform wudoo properly; start with bismillah and end with ash-hadu an laa ilaaha illallah wahdahu laa sharee ka lahu wa ash-hadu anna Muhammadan abdahu wa rasoolahu.
Umar bin Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه) narrated that the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever of you performs wudoo thoroughly then says: &amp;#8216;I testify that there is no god but Allah, with Whom there is no associate, and that Muhammad is His servant and Messenger,&amp;#8217; the eight gates of Paradise will be opened to him to enter from whichever he wants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules of Engagement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Rules of Engagement  Rules of Engagement is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad ibn Faqih. The course teaches and emphasizes ethics, morality, rights, character attributes, and manners&amp;#8211;everything from the rights of children before they&amp;#8217;re born to the cause for the decline and destruction of socieities to the literally dozens of virtues one earns from sabr! The course focuses a lot on self-development, self-improvement, and dealing with others, as well as improving oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purification of Salaah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/purification-of-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 04:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/purification-of-salaah/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all been there…You’re just chillin’, chatting on MSN with your buddies, and then you take a look at the time. Its 12:13am and you still haven’t prayed Isha. O mannn! You get off MSN, go make wudoo, and then perform your prayer. However, as we all know, our laziness and tired state takes over us, and this reflects in our prayer.
You finish praying at 12:17am and you find yourself in the same position you were no more than five mins ago, on MSN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic Four</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 06:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</guid>
      <description>One day, the Prophet (peace be upon him) sat with his companions, early in the morning. He asked, &amp;#8220;who among you is fasting this day?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I am.&amp;#8221; The Prophet (peace be upon him) asked, &amp;#8220;who amongst you followed the funeral bier (i.e. a janaazah) today?&amp;#8221; and Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.&amp;#8221; Then the Prophet (peace be upon him) said, &amp;#8220;who amongst you served food to the needy?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing on Behalf of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 12:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Never, ever, EVER say such-and-such is haram/halal/fard/etc. without knowledge. To say so, is to sign on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). And who dares to do that without knowledge? This is the job of the mujtahiduwn &amp;#8212; those who research fiqh issues and then issue fatawa. Notice, the best of them always say, &amp;#8220;this is the final ruling, and Allah knows best.&amp;#8221; Why? Because they are signing on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Please Everyone</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Today I have learned a valuable lesson, and I believe its a lesson that all of you readers can benefit from. The lesson itself is very simple, but realizing the importance and understanding the implications it may have in one’s life is what matters the most. The lesson is: you can‘t please everyone. Sounds so simple, right? Many of us are reading this and saying, well duh! So then, if its so obvious why do we keep persisting in our efforts to doing so?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 02:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</guid>
      <description>Anytime Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) mention Paradise for an action, it means that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) holds that action in high regard. So perform these activities regularly, and with ihsaan! Inshallah in the coming days, we will expound and narrate some instances where Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or His messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم), promised paradise &amp;#8212; keys that we can use to unlock the doors and, inshallah, enter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Arabic</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/accelerate-your-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/accelerate-your-arabic/</guid>
      <description>Want to learn Arabic&amp;#8211;or for that matter, any language&amp;#8211;quickly? Transcend beyond what you learn in class? Fly past your peers in terms of knowledge and understanding? Want to achieve all this without spending hours of time or hundreds of dollars?
Well, the solution is here&amp;#8211;and it&amp;#8217;s already available to you! All you need is a pen, some paper, and a mushaf (copy of the Qur&amp;#8217;an)&amp;#8211;and, most importantly, your brain!
Read  Read and recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Feel the Pain.</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/i-feel-the-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 08:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/i-feel-the-pain/</guid>
      <description>We feel the pain. We are hurting. We are crying. Reality has kicked in. Up until a month ago, everything was just a blur, didn’t know the effect and seriousness of the situations around the world. Up until a month ago, don’t even know if I felt for those around the world. However, when it creeps up into your own country, your own city, your own community, your own _family_–you feel everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruit of Ilm: Where has it Gone?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruit-of-ilm-where-has-it-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2006 19:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruit-of-ilm-where-has-it-gone/</guid>
      <description>We all are sitting in a world in which the value of knowledge is at its all-time high. Many of us, or our parents, invest a good amount of income towards this so-called &amp;#8220;educational system&amp;#8221; entitled “University” or “College”. Many of us invest hours upon hours, days upon days, week after week indulged in books and lectures learning about Limits, Laws of Neutrality, Psychological Human Behaviour, or, my favourite, Pareto Optimal (:S).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental Appreciation 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/parental-appreciation-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2006 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/parental-appreciation-101/</guid>
      <description>Want to appreciate your parents more? Maybe give them the respect and honour they really deserve? Here&amp;#8217;s an easy way to do it!
Have you ever been in a position where someone did you a really big favour&amp;#8211;big to you, anyway&amp;#8211;and you really, really appreciated it? Think back in your life. Chances are you thanked the person a lot for days after it&amp;#8211;and, what&amp;#8217;s more, you changed the way you treated them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Sensitivity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/time-sensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2006 15:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/time-sensitivity/</guid>
      <description>As Ramadan comes to a close and the remaining few days fly over our heads, many of us wonder at where it disappeared. We dust off our Qur&amp;#8217;ans and gun our engines to catch salaah at the masjid&amp;#8211;Taraweeh, Qiyam al-Layl, or just the daily five.
All of us acquire a certain sensitivity to time. Suddenly, every day, every hour counts. We think twice about spending two hours here or half an hour there on things we normally just do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006/</guid>
      <description>Just like we have different starting dates for Ramadan, we have different Eid dates.
And you know what? That&amp;#8217;s ok. Why? Because it&amp;#8217;s all based on legitimate difference of opinion. Not some beardy guy making stuff up because he feels like it.
So when &amp;#8216;Eid rolls around, enjoy it, and don&amp;#8217;t hate on other people for when they celebrate. That&amp;#8217;s messed up.
By the way&amp;#8211;when &amp;#8216;Eid rolls around, remember this: you just fasted for 30 days straight, give or take a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Fasting</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-purpose-of-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 19:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-purpose-of-fasting/</guid>
      <description>One of the verses of the Qur&amp;#8217;an we hear all the time in the context of fasting is this one:
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ كُتِبَ عَلَيْكُمُ الصِّيَامُ كَمَا كُتِبَ عَلَى الَّذِينَ مِن قَبْلِكُمْ لَعَلَّكُمْ تَتَّقُونَ  Translation: O you who believe! Allah prescribed fasting upon you, as it He prescribed for those before you, that you may attain taqwa (piety, God-consciousness). [Al-Baqarah, 2:183]
Those last two words summarize the entire purpose of fasting: to attain taqwa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Umar and the Eloquent Woman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, in a long hadith: &amp;#8220;A believer should speak good or keep silent!&amp;#8221; We all know this hadith, right?
But how do we implement this hadith? What if someone does something wrong? What if they deprive us of our rights? Should we still keep silent, or give them 80 lashes with our tongues?
Check this out&amp;#8211;this incident ocurred during the life of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), second Khalifa of Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Categories of Everything</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2006 21:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>Those five categories of all actions&amp;#8211;fard (also known as wajib), mustahab (sometimes called &amp;#8220;sunnah&amp;#8221;), mubah, makrooh, and haram&amp;#8211;what do they really mean? While you can understand these from different angles, we explain these from an Usool-ul-Fiqh perspective. Here they are:
    Fard/Wajib (obligatory) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn a punishment from abstaining from. Examples include praying, fasting, etc.
Mustahab/Sunnah (recommended) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn nothing from abstaining from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Burn-Out</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-burn-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-burn-out/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is the month of Qur&amp;#8217;an. A month where many of us fast, pray Taraweeh, pray Qiyam al-Layl, and read the entire Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8211;maybe more then once!
But subhanallah, in our love for Ramadan and our zeal for good deeds, we sometimes aim to accomplish more then our human capacity. We&amp;#8217;re humans, we all have limits.
But people say &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to read the WHOLE QUR&amp;#8217;AN this time!&amp;#8221; when they can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8211;sometimes, even reading only one juz, maybe even the last juz, is an accomplishment for them, one within their ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an: It’s All For You!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-its-all-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-its-all-for-you/</guid>
      <description>When you read the Qur&amp;#8217;an, cultivate the mentality that every single surah, verse, ayah, and letter was revealed for you, personally. Verse addressed to Banu Israeel (Jews)? Maybe Ahlil Kitaab (people of the book)? Or maybe An-Naas (humankind)? Or even the obvious, to those who believed? Yes, it addresses them&amp;#8211;but it also addresses you. Learn from their past&amp;#8211;their triumphs and their defeats, their actions and their mistakes, their joys and their pains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-mubarak-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 17:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-mubarak-2006/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan Mubarak to you and your families! May Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) make this a most blessed and beneficial month for you all, and a source of taqwa and eman for the whole year, ameen!
Subhanallah, one of the companions of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) even said, &amp;#8220;We spend half the year making du&amp;#8217;a for Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to allow us to see another Ramdaaan, and we spend half the year making du&amp;#8217;a for Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to accept the Ramdaan that passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan: The Excuse-Killer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan kills all the excuses we make for ourselves throughout the year, and allows us to soar to new heights of eman! If someone said to you, &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s go to the masjid every day,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! If someone said &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s play Qiyam al-Layl all night,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! Subhanallah, in Ramdan, wishes and hopes and dreams can become reality!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moonsighting or Moonfighting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/moonsighting-or-moonfighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 17:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/moonsighting-or-moonfighting/</guid>
      <description>In many countries (mostly Western countries&amp;#8211;America, Canada, Europe, etc.) our communities fight over the actual start date of Ramadan. This, itself, is not so bad&amp;#8211;because, alhamdulillah, everyone backs up their opinion with a legitimate fiqh source (more on that in a second). However, the problem is that people in the same region fast on different days&amp;#8211;sometimes, even two people in the same house fast on different days!
So how do we go about picking an appropriate date to start fasting?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowering Your Gaze: The Six Ps</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lowering-your-gaze-the-six-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 19:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lowering-your-gaze-the-six-ps/</guid>
      <description>For those who live in Western societies, fitnah abounds. From the moment you leave your house (or even before that), it bombards you from all sides, whether you&amp;#8217;re a man or a woman. How can we lower our gaze under these distressing conditions?
The following tactics will benefit you inshallah if you apply them consistently.
 Peripheral Vision: Fix your gaze on the ground a meter or two in front of you and see with your peripheral vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lessons: Power With Conciseness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 15:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</guid>
      <description>Another important gem we learn from the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and the early generations is that power comes with conciseness.
During the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), he received a letter from a man named Musaylimah, who claimed prophethood as well, and wished to divide up the area. In response, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) wrote:
&amp;#8220;From Muhammad the Messenger of Allah to Musaylimah the liar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping Up: Leadership Lessons from Az-Zubayr</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/stepping-up-leadership-lessons-from-az-zubayr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 19:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/stepping-up-leadership-lessons-from-az-zubayr/</guid>
      <description>During the battle of Yarmuk, Az-Zubayr (رضي الله عنه) tried to incite the mujahideen to fight against the Romans. (You can read the entire incident here.)
From this incident, we learn some important leadership lessons:
 When nobody steps up to the task, the leader must take the initiative to get the job done. Because, one way or another, the task must be completed. Leaders also work in the trenches, when circumstances require it of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alhamdulillah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/alhamdulillah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 03:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/alhamdulillah/</guid>
      <description>We praise someone under two circumstances: for the excellent attributes they possess, or for the deeds they perform towards us, such that we feel gratitude towards them. [1]
The only one who deserves praise in all these levels is the Creator of excellence, the Perfect Being who showers us with abundant favors again and again!
الْحَمْدُ للّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ  Translation: All praise belongs to Allah, Lord of the worlds. [Surah Al-Fatiha, verse 2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should I Read?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-should-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2006 00:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-should-i-read/</guid>
      <description>Last month before summer ends, we let the days go by or wrap up summer courses before it all starts over again! To get that degree, we consistently keep up with projects, homework, study for tests, etc. And sure enough, most of us accomplish this &amp;#8216;goal&amp;#8217; within the time we aimed for.
But do we have similar goals for learning the deen? It might be something we admired&amp;#8211;and perhaps desired&amp;#8211;but never really worked for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zuhd?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/zuhd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 00:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/zuhd/</guid>
      <description>On the authority of Abu al-&amp;#8216;Abbas Sahl bin Sa&amp;#8217;d al-Sa&amp;#8217;idi (رضي الله عنه) who said:
A man came to the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and said: &amp;#8220;O Messenger of Allah, direct me to an act which if I do it, [will cause] Allah to love me and people to love me.&amp;#8221; He (صلي الله عليه وسلم) answered: &amp;#8220;Be indifferent to the world and Allah will love you; be indifferent to what people possess and they will love you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’anic Word of the Day</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/quranic-word-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 15:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/quranic-word-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>Learning Arabic? Trying to memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an? Then inshaAllah you&amp;#8217;ll find this Yahoo Groups beneficial: Qur&amp;#8217;anic Word of the Day.
Every day, the administrator sends out a word&amp;#8211;Arabic and english&amp;#8211;as well as references to two ayat in the Qur&amp;#8217;an that contain the word (transliteration and translation). Very beneficial mashaAllah.
Also, for those new to Yahoo! Groups, they&amp;#8217;re like public mailing lists. You can configure your settings so you receive an email daily, or a digest weekly, or no email (and you browse from the site).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wife</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-wife/</guid>
      <description>The following is a beautiful little speech by Shaykh Abdullah Adhami, entitled &amp;#8220;A Wife&amp;#8221;. Read it inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala and benefit from it. Props to Beautiful Islam for the original.
  By getting married you are not just getting a wife, you are getting your whole world. From now until the rest of your days your wife will be your partner, your companion, and your best friend.She will share your moments, your days, and your years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cup? What’s That?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/world-cup-whats-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/world-cup-whats-that/</guid>
      <description>While FIFA World Cup blares over TV, reports on the radio, articles in the paper, we see our friends, our family, our co-workers, all of them glued to this new world.
Here are eleven reasons to unglue them (and yourself!) inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala:
 I will be questioned on the Day of Judgement about how I squandered and wasted my time. Who are those guys running around like headless chickens kicking that ball?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amplify Your Du’a With Tawassul</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amplify-your-dua-with-tawassul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 22:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amplify-your-dua-with-tawassul/</guid>
      <description>What is Tawassul? Linguistically, it means that which brings you closer to an object. The Arabic is tawassul (توسّل) or wasiylah (وسيلة). Islamically, it means any good deed that brings you closer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)&amp;#8211;so every single good deed can be called tawassul&amp;#8211;though scholars use it specifically to mean things that increase our chances of having our du&amp;#8217;a accepted.
The Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah only sanction four types of tawassal (with a difference of opinion on the fifth).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase Your Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2006 01:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Now that you know what barakah is, you might ask, how can one increase the barakah in his or her life? Aside from visiting the places with barakah, and making use of times with barakah, what else can you do?
The answer is very simple. If you want Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to bless you, then do anything for the sake of Allah, upon the sunnah (methodology) of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sins: Tawbah and Repetition</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/sins-tawbah-and-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 11:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/sins-tawbah-and-repetition/</guid>
      <description>Scholars say: there are no major sins with tawbah, and there are no minor sins with repetiton. What does that mean? The one who commits major sins and performs tawbah is forgiven; and the one who commits minor sins repeatedly is overcome by them, and they reach the level of major sins.
Ibn Mas&amp;#8217;ud (رضي الله عنه) said: A believer treats a sin as if it is a mountain over his head that may fall on him any moment; whereas a dissolute person looks at it as a fly that hovers around his nose and he waves it away with his hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Emptive Parental Kindness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pre-emptive-parental-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pre-emptive-parental-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Kindness to parents is pre-emptive&amp;#8211;you fulfill their needs and wants before they can ask, before they even know it themselves. Kindness to parents is pre-emptive&amp;#8211;it means you fulfill their needs before they ask. It&amp;#8217;s not antagonistic, where they ask and ask and ask until you give in and do what they say. It&amp;#8217;s not passive, where they have to tell you every little thing they need. It&amp;#8217;s active, so take the initiative and do what needs to be done, in order to earn the pleasure of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge, Practice, Da’wah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 18:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</guid>
      <description>Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
Q: Allah grants knowledge to those He loves. What do you do to be among these people?  A: Strive. Show interest in the deen. Come closer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and He will come closer to you. There is a hadith on how to gain knowledge: &amp;#8216;ilm is only gained by studying. It&amp;#8217;s not gained by hiding in a cave and worshipping Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Studious study is the only way to gain knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessings of Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/blessings-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2006 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/blessings-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>The Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah both praise knowledge. There are many blessings of knowledge&amp;#8211;but first, we must define, &amp;#8220;what IS knowledge?&amp;#8221;
The Prophet said, in one hadith: &amp;#8220;If Allah wants to do a favor to somebody, He bestows on him, the gift of understanding the deen.&amp;#8221; [Bukhari 9/92/415]1 From this hadith, we know that knowledge, as defined in the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah, refers to knowledge of Islam, and not secular knowledge (such as Chemistry or Meteorology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/on-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/on-patience/</guid>
      <description>Patience is active, not passive. What does this mean? It mains patience doesn&amp;#8217;t just &amp;#8220;happen&amp;#8221;. You must strive for it. You have to actively remind yourself and make yourself patient.
Also, remember that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) tests you with what you are not patient with. If He (سبحانه وتعالى) tested you with things you already succeed at, how could you ever learn and grow?
For a classic example of patience, consult Surah Yusuf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Times Blessed with Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/times-blessed-with-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2006 22:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/times-blessed-with-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask “what times has Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) blessed with barakah?”
There are six blessed times:
 Ramadan: The month of Ramadan, in general, is blessed. Also, the night of Laylatul-Qadr is specifically also very blessed. These are ideal times to worship Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), because the reward is greater. The last ten nights of Ramadan are the most blessed nights of the year&amp;#8211;more then the days of Dhul Hijjah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places that Contain Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/places-that-contain-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2006 03:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/places-that-contain-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask “what places has Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) blessed with barakah?”
To start, the three blessed massajid:
 The Ka&amp;#8217;bah: it is the most blessed place on the Earth, more-so then the surrounding holy sites. Medina: The city is blessed with barakah, and also, masjid an-nabawi has been blessed with barakah. Masjid al-Aqsa: the masjid, located in Jerusalem, in blessed, as well as the surrounding area of Sham in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fight For Sincere Intentions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fight-for-sincere-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 23:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fight-for-sincere-intentions/</guid>
      <description>In the first hadith in Sahih Bukhari, the messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The reward of deeds depends upon the intentions and every person will get the reward according to what he intended. So whoever emigrated for worldly benefits or for a woman to marry, his emigration was for what he emigrated for.&amp;#8221;1 The majority scholarly opinion is that this hadith applies to all actions, natural or religious (read more about the distinction here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Way to Increase Eman?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2006 16:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</guid>
      <description>Question: What is the best way for a person increase his or her eman?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The single greatest way to increase your eman is to gain knowledge. Study what eman is, study tawhid, the pillars of eman, etc. It automatically increases your eman.
Good deeds also increase eman&amp;#8211;each and every single good deed and act of worship you perform increases your eman. Fast a day. Read Qur&amp;#8217;an. Pray Tahajjud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (10): Ease and Light Crossing the Sirat</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 20:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-10/</guid>
      <description>19) Ease and Light Crossing the Sirat  Towards the end of Judgement Day&amp;#8211;a day that will last 50 000 years (Surah Al-Maarij, verse 4)1, after the judgement has been decreed, the people will have to cross the Sirat&amp;#8211;a bridge sharper then a sword and thinner then a hair2, that runs over Hell&amp;#8211;in order to get to Jannah. People will fall off&amp;#8211;there will be hooks like thorns of a size known only to Allah, to snag people into the Fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (9): Benefit From Advice</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 01:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-9/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
18) Benefit From Advice  In Surah Adh-Dhariyat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَذَكِّرْ فَإِنَّ الذِّكْرَى تَنفَعُ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ  Translation: And continue to remind, for surely the reminder profits the believers. (Surah Adh-Dhariyat, verse 55)1
Notice, here, who benefits from the reminders&amp;#8211;not all humankind, but believers. Why? Try this hypothethical situation on for size: there&amp;#8217;s a guy who&amp;#8217;s sinning&amp;#8211;say he&amp;#8217;s drinking beer in front of you inside his home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (8): Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2006 03:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-8/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
17) Love Here and in the Hereafter  In Surah Maryam, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ سَيَجْعَلُ لَهُمُ الرَّحْمَنُ وُدًّا  Translation: On those who believe and work deeds of righteousness, (Allah) The Most Gracious bestows love. (Surah Maryam, verse 96)1
That is: on those who have eman and perform good deeds, Allah decrees for them love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (7): Brotherhood</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 18:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-7/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
16) Brotherhood  In Surah Hujraat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّمَا الْمُؤْمِنُونَ إِخْوَةٌ فَأَصْلِحُوا بَيْنَ أَخَوَيْكُمْ وَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ لَعَلَّكُمْ تُرْحَمُونَ  Translation: The Believers are but a single Brotherhood &amp;#8230; (Surah Hujraat, verse 10)1
If you&amp;#8217;ve ever been to a different city, you walk into the grocery store, and nobody says anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (6): Khilafah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 21:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-6/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
15) The Khalifa  In Surah Noor, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَعَدَ اللَّهُ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا مِنكُمْ وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ لَيَسْتَخْلِفَنَّهُم فِي الْأَرْضِ كَمَا اسْتَخْلَفَ الَّذِينَ مِن قَبْلِهِمْ وَلَيُمَكِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ دِينَهُمُ الَّذِي ارْتَضَى لَهُمْ وَلَيُبَدِّلَنَّهُم مِّن بَعْدِ خَوْفِهِمْ أَمْنًا يَعْبُدُونَنِي لَا يُشْرِكُونَ بِي شَيْئًا وَمَن كَفَرَ بَعْدَ ذَلِكَ فَأُوْلَئِكَ هُمُ الْفَاسِقُونَ  Translation: Allah has promised, to those among you who believe and work righteous deeds, that He will, of a surety, grant them in the land, , inheritance (of power), &amp;#8230; [when] they worship Me (alone) and not associate aught with Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (5): Glad Tidings of Angels Before Death</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2006 22:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-5/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
14) Glad Tidings of Angels before Death  In Surah Fussilat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ قَالُوا رَبُّنَا اللَّهُ ثُمَّ اسْتَقَامُوا تَتَنَزَّلُ عَلَيْهِمُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ أَلَّا تَخَافُوا وَلَا تَحْزَنُوا وَأَبْشِرُوا بِالْجَنَّةِ الَّتِي كُنتُمْ تُوعَدُونَ  Translation: In the case of those who say, &amp;#8220;Our Lord is Allah&amp;#8221;, and, further, stand straight and steadfast, the angels descend on them [and say]: &amp;#8220;Fear ye not, nor grieve!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (4): A Good Life</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 16:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
13) A Good Life  In Surah Nahl, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
مَنْ عَمِلَ صَالِحًا مِّن ذَكَرٍ أَوْ أُنثَى وَهُوَ مُؤْمِنٌ فَلَنُحْيِيَنَّهُ حَيَاةً طَيِّبَةً وَلَنَجْزِيَنَّهُمْ أَجْرَهُم بِأَحْسَنِ مَا كَانُواْ يَعْمَلُونَ  Translation: Whoever works righteousness, man or woman, and has Faith, verily, to him will We give a new Life, a life that is good and pure and We will bestow on such their reward according to the best of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (3)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 16:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-3/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
9) Good Always Happens to You  In one hadith, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;How amazing is the situation of the believer. His affair is always for the best, and this is not true for anyone besides the believer. If good befalls him he is thankful and this is best for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (2)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 00:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
4) Forgiveness of Sins  In Surah Furqan, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِلَّا مَن تَابَ وَآمَنَ وَعَمِلَ عَمَلًا صَالِحًا فَأُوْلَئِكَ يُبَدِّلُ اللَّهُ سَيِّئَاتِهِمْ حَسَنَاتٍ وَكَانَ اللَّهُ غَفُورًا رَّحِيمًا  Translation: [Whoever] repents, believes, and works righteous deeds, Allah will change the evil of such persons into good, and Allah is Oft-Forgiving, Most Merciful,&amp;#8221; (Surah Furqan, verse 70)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (1)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-1/</guid>
      <description>Allah says in the Qur’an, in Surah Ibrahim:
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ ضَرَبَ اللّهُ مَثَلاً كَلِمَةً طَيِّبَةً كَشَجَرةٍ طَيِّبَةٍ أَصْلُهَا ثَابِتٌ وَفَرْعُهَا فِي السَّمَاء
تُؤْتِي أُكُلَهَا كُلَّ حِينٍ بِإِذْنِ رَبِّهَا وَيَضْرِبُ اللّهُ الأَمْثَالَ لِلنَّاسِ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ  Translation: Have you not seen how Allah has given the parable of a beautiful kalimah, like a beautiful tree whose roots are firmly established, and whose branches tower in the sky? It gives its fruits at all times by the permission of it&amp;#8217;s Lord, and Allah sets forth parables for mankind in order that they may remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Ibadah, Natural Actions, Religious Actions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Ibadah. We hear the word all the time. But what does it mean?
Linguistically, &amp;#8216;ibadah means to show subserviance, or to be subserviant to.
From a shar&amp;#8217;ee perspective, &amp;#8216;ibadah has two meanings:
 The spiritual conscience of the worshipper&amp;#8211;what constitutes worship spiritually. The actions&amp;#8211;what consitutes worship in action.  And Ibn Tamiyyah says: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Ibadah includes all hidden and shown actions, statements, and beliefs beloved to Allah.&amp;#8221;
Of actions, there are two types: natural and religious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water, Soil, Plants, Fruit, Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 05:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that your time is water. Every day, you get 24 liters to use as you wish. You keep it in one giant metal bucket and carry it around with you. The bucket leaks&amp;#8211;if you don&amp;#8217;t pour your time into buckets and use it effectively, most of it will end up spilled on the ground, lost.
Each day, you pass by some plants, and you have to stop and water them, or they die&amp;#8211;the big, thick bush of family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Responsibility, Spread the Message</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-responsibility-spread-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 03:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-responsibility-spread-the-message/</guid>
      <description>In the Qur&amp;#8217;an, surah Nisaa, Allah says:
فَقَاتِلْ فِي سَبِيلِ اللّهِ لاَ تُكَلَّفُ إِلاَّ نَفْسَكَ وَحَرِّضِ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ عَسَى اللّهُ أَن يَكُفَّ بَأْسَ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُواْ وَاللّهُ أَشَدُّ بَأْسًا وَأَشَدُّ تَنكِيلاً  Translation: Then fight in Allah’s cause &amp;#8211; you are responsible only for yourself &amp;#8211; and rouse the believers. It may be that Allah will restrain the fury of the Unbelievers; for Allah is the strongest in might and in punishment (Surah Nisaa, 4:84)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aim for 110%</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/aim-for-110/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 02:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/aim-for-110/</guid>
      <description>All of us, and especially those of us in educational institutes, run into tests and projects and assignments. And often&amp;#8211;too often&amp;#8211;we aim merely for a pass. A 60% or 50%, and we&amp;#8217;re good to go.
But, imagine if you will, an archer shooting at a target. High above his head is 100%. Somewhere level with him is 50%&amp;#8211;a pass. And below, lesser marks.
He draws back his arrow. He aims. 50%?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: A Springboard of Eman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-springboard-of-eman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 22:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-springboard-of-eman/</guid>
      <description>Salaah is the springboard of eman. Everytime you perform salaah, your eman should go up. In Surah Baqarah, Allah says: &amp;#8220;And seek help in patience and prayer. Indeed it is difficult, except for those with kushu&amp;#8220;.
Here are some tips inshaAllah to help you achieve awesome salaah:
 Pray as if it is your last prayer. We hear imams say this a lot. But what does it mean? How would your salaah be if you knew it was your last salaah before you returned to Allah, Lord of the Worlds?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Stages of Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-stages-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 19:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-stages-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>There are six stages of knowledge.
 Knowledge of Facts: know the information (eg. what year did &amp;#8216;Umar (radiallahu &amp;#8216;an) become the Khalifa?) Comprehension: think about the information and understand it (eg. the khalifa is in charge of the entire Muslim ummah) Application: learn and apply the knowledge&amp;#8211;it helps you remember. Apply it to your context. What does it mean for you and me, here, today? Analysis: Analyze the information critically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sea, the Boat, and the Governers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 03:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are a boat, and the dunya is the sea. Far off in the distance, is land &amp;#8212; the akhira.
&amp;#8220;You are a boat. You sail the waters of the dunya towards the lands of Jannah.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;Abdur-Rahman
What happens if the sea floods into the boat? You sink.
So be like the best Muslim leaders: they ditched the dunya for the akhira.
In particular, I refer to the governers in the time of the Khulafa Rashideen (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (13): Your Purpose on Earth</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 03:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-13/</guid>
      <description>The king asked the boy to renounce his religion, to which the boy refused. The king said &amp;#8220;take him to the highest mountain and if he doesn&amp;#8217;t renounce by the time you reach the top, throw him off.&amp;#8221;
Why not saw him in half? Because the boy&amp;#8217;s useful. He has influence among the poeple. People love him, and if he joins the king, many will follow his example.
So they took him up, and the boy said &amp;#8220;O Allah, suffice me against them in whatever way You please&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (12): Sincerity of Du’a</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 02:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-12/</guid>
      <description>We often make empty du&amp;#8217;as&amp;#8211;they lack in sincerity, but hey, we don&amp;#8217;t expect them to be answered. But why do it? Are you just testing Allah?
Think with certiny that Allah will answer your du&amp;#8217;a. Make the most sincere, heart-felt du&amp;#8217;a of your existance. And have hope that Allah will answer it. Before Islam, there was a man named Jurayj, a worshipper of Allah. The people around him had intense jealousy of him for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Time For Yourself: Avoid Burnout</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/make-time-for-yourself-avoid-burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 04:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/make-time-for-yourself-avoid-burnout/</guid>
      <description>When you get involved in da&amp;#8217;wah, don&amp;#8217;t forget yourself. We see many examples of this&amp;#8211;people join the local MSA, and spend 40 hours a week to keep it alive. And the next year, you see them in the bar, with their girlfriend or boyfriend. Or others spend months putting together The Biggest Conference Ever, and while it goes on, they miss all the lectures and mill around outside with their friends, or out in the parking lot arguing about lunches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallout From Not Practicing Islam Properly</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fallout-from-not-practicing-islam-properly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2006 03:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fallout-from-not-practicing-islam-properly/</guid>
      <description>Familiarize yourself with Ar-Rajal, companion to the fake prophet Musaylimah.
Many people believe that when you don&amp;#8217;t practice Islam 100%, you&amp;#8217;re not hurting anyone but yourself. But subhanallah, if you look at Ar-Rajal, how many people did he misguide by not practicing Islam? Howmany tens or hundreds or thousands joined Musaylimah because Ar-Rajal endorsed him?
If you work or attend school, look around you. How many &amp;#8220;Muslims&amp;#8221; do you know who don&amp;#8217;t wear a beard, don&amp;#8217;t observe hijab, they drink, they go clubbing, they have a girlfriend or boyfriend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware Endorsements: The Fitnah of Ar-Rajal</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/beware-endorsements-the-fitnah-of-ar-rajal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 22:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/beware-endorsements-the-fitnah-of-ar-rajal/</guid>
      <description>A man came to the Prophet (salallhu alayhi wa sallam) from Al-Yamamah, learned some Quran, and apostated and joined Musalimah. His kunya (pet-name) was Ar-Rajal (&amp;#8220;the man&amp;#8221;). He endorsed Musaylimah.
His fitna was more intense then Musaylimah. People thought he was learned and scholarly, and he believed in Musaylimah. It caused a huge doubt among the ignorant people. They felt that if Ar-Rajal listened, they should listen, too.
Today, everyone has endorsements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Identity?  Know Your Roots</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/know-your-identity-know-your-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 22:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/know-your-identity-know-your-roots/</guid>
      <description>To know your identity, know your roots.
One way to destroy a people is to isolate them from their roots.
Muslims today remain ignorant of their identity. Who was the Prophet, (صلي الله عليه وسلم)? What was he like? Who are Abu Bakr, &amp;#8216;Umar, &amp;#8216;Aisha, Az-Zubayr, Abu Darda? Who was Imam Shafi&amp;#8217;ee, Imam Malik, Salahuddin (may Allah be pleased with all of them)?
So study your history! Read the seerah of the Prophet, the seerah of the Khulafa, and Islamic history &amp;#8212; including major figures like the four imams, Salahuddin, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Sacrifice</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/benefits-of-sacrifice-tafseer-surah-nisaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 20:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/benefits-of-sacrifice-tafseer-surah-nisaa/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Nisaa, Allah says:
وَلَوْ أَنَّا كَتَبْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ أَنِ اقْتُلُواْ أَنفُسَكُمْ أَوِ اخْرُجُواْ مِن دِيَارِكُم مَّا فَعَلُوهُ إِلاَّ قَلِيلٌ مِّنْهُمْ وَلَوْ أَنَّهُمْ فَعَلُواْ مَا يُوعَظُونَ بِهِ لَكَانَ خَيْرًا لَّهُمْ وَأَشَدَّ تَثْبِيتًا
وَإِذاً لَّآتَيْنَاهُم مِّن لَّدُنَّـا أَجْراً عَظِيمًا
وَلَهَدَيْنَاهُمْ صِرَاطًا مُّسْتَقِيمًا  Translation: If We had ordered them to sacrifice their lives or to leave their homes, very few of them would have done it. But if they had done what they were (actually) told, it would have been best for them, and would have gone farthest to strengthen their (faith).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Interaction: Professionalism</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 04:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</guid>
      <description>The key to gender interaction (aka gender relations) is professionalism. During the lifetime of the Prophet, peace be upon him, &amp;#8216;Umar said to one woman sahaba in Abysinnia: &amp;#8220;We have more right to the Prophet then you&amp;#8221;. She said (to the effect of) &amp;#8220;nope&amp;#8221;. She approached the Prophet and narrated the incident to him, and he said &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Umar was incorrect. You (Abyssinians) made hijrah (migration) twice, you get double the reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnt Food: An Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/burnt-food-an-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 19:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/burnt-food-an-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Common reactions among many types of people when their spouse burns their food, or forgets the salt, or oversalts, or otherwise destroys it, are statements such as &amp;#8220;what&amp;#8217;s wrong with you, don&amp;#8217;t you know how to cook&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;didn&amp;#8217;t your mother/father ever teach you anything&amp;#8221; and so on.
Remain patient, as the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) remained when his wives cooked food he didn&amp;#8217;t like. He sat, and said nothing at all, nor did he eat from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Before Death</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-before-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-before-death/</guid>
      <description>From the teachings of the khulafa rashideen: when you&amp;#8217;re about to do something, ask yourself: &amp;#8220;Would I be happy and unregretful of how I spent my time today?&amp;#8221;
If the answer is &amp;#8220;no&amp;#8221;, then find something better to do with your time.
And remember: Time is one of the ONLY irreversable resources. Money comes and goes, status builds, but time, once it&amp;#8217;s gone, it never comes back.
The Prophet, peace and blessings upon him, said: Two things about which people are deceived are their health and their time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief Shapes Identity and Action</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-shapes-identity-and-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-shapes-identity-and-action/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Baqarah, Allah says:
وَإِذَا لَقُواْ الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ قَالُواْ آمَنَّا وَإِذَا خَلَوْاْ إِلَى شَيَاطِينِهِمْ قَالُواْ إِنَّا مَعَكْمْ إِنَّمَا نَحْنُ مُسْتَهْزِؤُونَ  Translation: &amp;#8220;When they meet those who believe, they say &amp;#8216;we believe,&amp;#8217; but when they are alone with their shayateen, they say &amp;#8216;we are with you&amp;#8216; &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; (Al-Quran, Surah Al-Baqarah, 2:14)1
Although the hypocrites say they believe, they associate their identities with shayateen (devils, or &amp;#8220;evil ones&amp;#8221;).
The lesson: your belief system shapes your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khalid bin Walid: From General to Foot-Soldier</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</guid>
      <description>During the reign of Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم), and later, the reign of Abu Bakr, the first Khalifa, may Allah be pleased with him, Khalid bin Walid, commander of the Muslim army, rocked the non-Muslim armies again and again and again and lead the Muslims to many victories. In this way, he became a fitnah&amp;#8211;people ascribed victory to him, and not to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).
After the battle of Yarmuk, the newly-instated Khalifa, &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (may Allah be pleased with him) removed Khalid bin Walid from leadership of the army and instated Abu Ubaydah (RA) as the commander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memorize Qur’an: Triple Reinforcement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/memorize-quran-triple-reinforcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 05:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/memorize-quran-triple-reinforcement/</guid>
      <description>To memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an, regardless of your learning style, utilize your senses (sight and sound) plus your intellect to reinforce your memorization inshaAllah.
 See it: See the Qur&amp;#8217;an in Arabic. A tajweed colour-coded mushaf works. Pick a script you like, and read it over a few times. Learn how the letters look. Read it after you listen to it a few times. Hear it: Download your favourite reciter and listen to the particular verse you want to memorize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (7): The People Most Tested</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 03:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-7/</guid>
      <description>Some companions asked the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) &amp;#8220;Who are the people most tested?&amp;#8221; The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said &amp;#8220;The rightly guided people.&amp;#8221;
Allah tests people according to the strength of their faith. As you increase in iman, your tests become tougher and tougher. Allah tests everyone, even non-believers. So if you&amp;#8217;re going to be tested, be tested for fleeing to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (5): Humility with Arrogance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 03:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-5/</guid>
      <description>After the boy killed the lion, news spread fast&amp;#8211;news arrives like an ant and leaves like an elephant. Sensationalism.
The boy meets the scholar and informs him of what occurred. The scholar replied with: &amp;#8220;O my boy, today you are better then me. You will be tested, so when it happens, do not reveal me (don&amp;#8217;t rat me out).&amp;#8221;
How was the boy better? He gained knowledge and implemented it, and increased in humility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Key to Attract an Amazing Spouse</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-attract-an-amazing-spouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 02:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-attract-an-amazing-spouse/</guid>
      <description>The key to attract an amazing spouse is to nurture in yourself those qualities that appeal to a person of that standard. Many of us pine for the perfect spouse&amp;#8211;realize he or she does not exist. Pick the best you can find, and learn to live with and cover their warts and weaknesses.
Set your criteria (based on the hadith of the Prophet, peace be upon him)&amp;#8211;have they memorized the Qur&amp;#8217;an?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wear Islam Responsibly</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/wear-islam-responsibly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 04:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/wear-islam-responsibly/</guid>
      <description>When you wear Islam, wear it properly and responsibly. &amp;#8211;A. M. When you grow a beard or put on hijab, be aware of the responsibility. You represent the Muslims, more then ever. Represent properly!
Don&amp;#8217;t mess up and appear at clubs or bars and similar places. With the greater reward comes the greater potential of punishment&amp;#8211;you can misguide many, many people if you represent Islam improperly.
May Allah protect us from anti-da&amp;#8217;wah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek Protection From Shirk</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-protection-from-shirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 03:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-protection-from-shirk/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) asked Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) for His protection from shirk. So why do we act like we know we&amp;#8217;ll die Muslim? Remember, this is the Prophet of Allah. He spoke to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) without any barrier. He received revelation directly from Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). He is the best of creation.
So seek protection in Allah from shirk, the unforgivable sin that destroys good deeds. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) taught us the following du&amp;#8217;a:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Happiness Doesn’t Exist</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/perfect-happiness-doesnt-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 03:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/perfect-happiness-doesnt-exist/</guid>
      <description>All people on Earth seek happiness&amp;#8211;whether it&amp;#8217;s through wealth, or love, or piety. Few realize that perfect happiness does not exist in the dunya. When you think about it, you&amp;#8217;ll find that hardship and pain exist with moments of great happiness. For example, you ate your favourite meal after a long time, but you feel over-full and you become tired and lazy. Or, you enjoy a wonderful hike through the woods, minus the insect bites and that bee that flew into your ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Pronounciation in Surah Fatiha</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-pronounciation-in-surah-faitha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 03:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-pronounciation-in-surah-faitha/</guid>
      <description>Surah Fatiha contains almost all the Arabic letters that the English language lacks: &amp;#8216;Ayn (ع), Saad (ص), Daad (ض), Taw (ط), Qaf (ق), and 7a (ح). Once you learn to pronounce these letters correctly, you practice them 17 times a day, every day, in every state of mind. Bi ithnillah, once you learn them, practice, and you will master them quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tajweed Review Website</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tajweed-review-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 03:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tajweed-review-website/</guid>
      <description>If you know your tajweed (Qur&amp;#8217;anic rules of beautifying recitation) but feel a bit rusty or need to review them, this website explains it very well. The website helps more if you already know tajweed but need a refresher. It&amp;#8217;s very difficult to learn tajweed without a real, human teacher.
May Allah accept our reading of the Qur&amp;#8217;an as &amp;#8216;ibadah. Ameen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etiquettes and Adab of Du’a (Supplication)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/etiquettes-and-adab-of-dua-supplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 02:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/etiquettes-and-adab-of-dua-supplication/</guid>
      <description>Learn all about the etiquettes and adab of du&amp;#8217;a here. Highlights include:
 Make du&amp;#8217;a at times of trouble and of joy. Repeat the du&amp;#8217;a three times Make du&amp;#8217;a in a moderately low voice  And remember, with du&amp;#8217;a, three things can occur:
 Allah can accept your du&amp;#8217;a! Alhamdullilah. Allah will save it for you until the akhira. Allah will avert evil from you.  In any case, you benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Arabic from the Qur’an</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-arabic-from-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-arabic-from-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>One way to learn Arabic is to memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an with a word-by-word translation.
emuslim.com provides such a tool. Once you memorize a few (approximately 20-30) verses, you&amp;#8217;ll find that other verses become decipherable, and familiar words leap at you everywhere you turn.
I recommend this method to everyone&amp;#8211;for some, it&amp;#8217;s the only way to memorize Qur&amp;#8217;an.
Related Links: emuslim English word-for-word translation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Arabic Language</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-in-arabic-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 01:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-in-arabic-language/</guid>
      <description>Islamic-Knowledge.com&amp;#8217;s Lessons in Arabic Language website provides an online self-paced course for people to learn Arabic, in Arabic. It follows the famous three Medina Arabic books page by page, and displays translations and transliterations for every word used.
Unlike other online courses, this course teaches entirely in Arabic (minus the transliteration), similar to the way they teach Arabic at Al-Medina university. Although more difficult to learn than an English course, it forces the reader to think in Arabic, an advantage not offered by many other courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MadinahArabic.com: Open the Portal to Learning Arabic</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madinaharabiccom-open-the-portal-to-learning-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2006 04:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madinaharabiccom-open-the-portal-to-learning-arabic/</guid>
      <description>MadinahArabic.com teaches Arabic in the style of the Madinah Book Series, used to teach Arabic at Al-Medina university. The series style caters to English-speakers. The website follows a similar teaching paradigm.
The course walks you through the process step by step. They seperate the material into two sections: Arabic Reading Course, which teaches letters, and Arabic Language Course, which teaches grammar and vocabulary.
The course offers a self-paced and comprehensive approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation (Shura): A Fundamental Leadership Technique</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 02:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</guid>
      <description>Consultation, or shura, is a fundamental leadership technique in Islam. You consult with the experts, and you implement it, and you close the issue. Shura means consultation. It also means the consulted group. Shura is a fundamental technique in leadership. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), the best and most knowledable and noble of people, practiced shura with his companions&amp;#8211;and who knew better than he? How can the rest of us believe we don&amp;#8217;t need shura?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Key to Happiness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness lies in rememberence of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and His blessings. It keeps you happy. One guy performed Hajj (pilgrimage to Mecca) once, and complained about the crush of the crowd. But would you be happy if you were the only Muslim there? No way. You&amp;#8217;d hate it. So remember the blessings even when Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) tests you with difficult tests.
Tip: When you say Al-Hamdullilah, mean it. Think about a specific blessing Allah blessed you with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotions Misguide</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emotions-misguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emotions-misguide/</guid>
      <description>After the death of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), many tribes apostated from Islam. Some stopped paying zakaah (poor-due), and some tribe leaders claimed prophethood. Many of the common people at that time lacked education. The emotional charge of the situation swept up many of the Muslims.
Protect yourself. If you allow the river of emotion to sweep you up, in a lot of cases, it will misguide you towards the wrong direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Hold Back Your Talents</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</guid>
      <description>If you possess some skill you can utilize to the benefit of the people everywhere, never hold back. Don&amp;#8217;t hold it to yourself. Forget about what other people are thinking. Focus on how they can benefit from it. This applies especially if a) you have relatively rare talents, or b) nobody knows about your skills.
Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with Ihsaan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</guid>
      <description>As Islamic workers, we never lower our standers. Not as volunteers, not as professionals, and not as Muslims. Always strive to the best of your abilities. And inshaAllah this way, your skills and talent grow faster than if you barely use them.
Never fall into the trap of so many people who produce second-rate material &amp;#8220;just because&amp;#8221; it&amp;#8217;s for Islamic work, and not for their own (percieved/worldly) benefit.
And remember: ihsaan means excellence, not perfection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Saudi Guy Walks Into a Bar …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-saudi-guy-walks-into-a-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-saudi-guy-walks-into-a-bar/</guid>
      <description>A Saudi guy walks into a bar, decked out in his thobe and kufi. (He doesn&amp;#8217;t believe in the meat of the People of the Book arguement.) He walks up to the bar and says &amp;#8220;Bartender, I want a chicken sandwich.&amp;#8221;
The bartender looks at him, nods, and turns to fill the order.
A desi guy who sits nearby stares. The Saudi guy turns to the desi guy. Black spiked hair, leather jacket, one hand clamps around the handle of a half-filled mug of beer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership at the Front and Leadership from the Back</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 23:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</guid>
      <description>Front Leaders: These leaders take charge, set the vision, and lead the way. They take the initiative, and step up to the call when Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) calls them.
Back Leaders: These leaders encourage, gather everyone&amp;#8217;s opinion, call meetings, and encourage mutual agreement and compromise.
In Islaimc work, and in any project, you need both types of leadership. Like when a group hikes through a trail. You need someone at the front to pick the path and set the pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Management: Abstraction</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/effective-management-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 22:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/effective-management-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Abstraction: Selective ignorance of certain elements in order to focus on other elements.
In software development, abstraction means you zoom out and see the big picture. You ignore minor implementation details&amp;#8211;what are the little pieces? How do they work?&amp;#8211;and focus on the whole. These are the systems and how they fit together, and this is the overall goal.
When you employ abstraction, efficiency increases. No longer bogged down with function pointers, memory management, or 16-bit register values, you focus on how to make your software work better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Beard can be Weird</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 02:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t judge a book by its cover or a man by his beard, because what&amp;#8217;s behind the beard can be weird.&amp;#8221; Apply this to your lives, and you&amp;#8217;ll find that, bi ithnillah (by the permission of Allah), you will never be surprised or dissapointed. When you make great assumptions about people, where can they go except down?
Great assumptions often lead to great letdowns. Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear the Creator, Fear the Creation?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fear-the-creator-fear-the-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 22:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fear-the-creator-fear-the-creation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;If you fear the creator, you will never fear the creation.&amp;#8221; -Imam Anwar al-Awlaki If your heart trembles in fear of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and awe of His majesty, nothing in the dunya (world) can ever overshadow that fear. The dunya can throw a bigger army at you, better weapons, everything and anything. And if you fear Allah the way He deserves to be feared, none of that can overshadow your fear of the Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiTimer: Multiple Labeled Item Timers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</guid>
      <description>MultiTimer, a lightweight application, allows you to track your time commitments to multiple items simultaneously. You type in the timer label, set the inital time and count method (countup or countdown), and the application handles the rest.
In particular, if you need to track (and, optionally, aggregate) time usage for multiple projects, you can assign one timer per project and track your time use per day. Or per week. Or per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</guid>
      <description>This article by Steve Pavlina explains how to effectively manage your life by focusing on tasks based on their long-term effects.
The article defines three categories of tasks, and allocates your daily time to each of them proportionally based on their expected benefit.
 &amp;#8220;A&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in five or more years, such as learning a new language. &amp;#8220;B&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in two or more years, such as training for a marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Things Are Worth Crying Over</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Very few things in life are worth crying over.&amp;#8221; Ponder it. Very few things in life are worth throwing a fit over or complaining about. In Islamic work, especially, people attach importantance to things that aren&amp;#8217;t issues, tempers rise, fights break out, and brotherhood dies. And in the end, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) controls over all things.
So sit back, chill out, and let it run by you. No harm done, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>