<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aqeeda on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/aqeeda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aqeeda on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/aqeeda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem Together</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</guid>
      <description>Allah introduces himself in Surah Fatiha as Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem, both. Both of these names derive their meaning from the word mercy (rahmah).
In classical Arabic, rahmah represents the mercy of a mother for her child. As the child grows, it causes the mother to be sick and weak; it eats nutrition from the mother; in the later trimesters, the child even stretches, punches, or kicks the mother&amp;#8217;s ribs! But still, the mother cares for, takes care of, and protects the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Naba’, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-naba-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 18:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-naba-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is post #40 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In the previous post, we discussed the first 16 verses of Surah Naba&amp;#8217;. The remaining 24 verses discuss the Day of Judgment, Paradise, and Hellfire; you should read them to extract the details. Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;re going to touch on a few points that are interesting.
First, a recap&amp;#8211;verse 16 talked about (a continuing discussion of) some of the blessings of Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) in the dunya on the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness – Part 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 15:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-4/</guid>
      <description>IT IS ALLAH ALONE WHO IS WORTHY OF WORSHIP A STATEMENT OF TRUTH REVEALED TO THE MUSHRIKS
Continuing and inshallah the last post in the explanation of the poem, we will now we move into the third aspect of tawheed: maintaining the oneness, uniqueness, and exclusiveness of Allah’s rights to be worshipped (tawheed al-uloohiyyah)
The grand importance of tawheed al-uloohiyyah is evident in the fact that the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam was commissioned to a nation that confirmed many aspects of the first two categories of tawheed but rejected worshipping Allah alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness – Part 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 16:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-3/</guid>
      <description>HE IS ALLAH, THE MOST HIGH WHO DOES NOT SLEEP NOR DOES HIS CREATION TAKE PART IN HIS MAJESTY
Continuing in our explanation of the poem and our discussion of the five points relating to tawheed al-asma was-sifat:
4) We do not Ascribe the Qualities of Creation to the Creator It is not befitting the majesty of Allah subhanahu wa ta’ala that we ascribe to Him characteristics and weaknesses of creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness – Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</guid>
      <description>ALLAH IS AS HE DESCRIBES HIMSELF WITH NO ADDITIONS BEYOND WHICH WE DO NOT PONDER NOR PUT CONDITIONS
Continuing in our explanation of the poem and our discussion of the branches tawheed, we now move into the second branch which is the oneness, uniqueness, and exclusiveness of Allah’s Names and Attributes (tawheed al-asma was-sifat). There are five points we will discuss; three points in this post and the remaining two in the next post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness: Poem with Explanation – Part 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-poem-with-explanation-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 03:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-poem-with-explanation-part-1/</guid>
      <description>ALLAH, THE LORD OF THE HEAVENS AND THE EARTH
THE CREATOR, SUSTAINER, ABOVE GIVING BIRTH
ALLAH IS AS HE DESCRIBES HIMSELF WITH NO ADDITIONS
BEYOND WHICH WE DO NOT PONDER NOR PUT CONDITIONS
HE IS ALLAH, THE MOST HIGH WHO DOES NOT SLEEP
NOR DOES HIS CREATION TAKE PART IN HIS MAJESTY
IT IS ALLAH ALONE WHO IS WORTHY OF WORSHIP
A STATEMENT OF TRUTH REVEALED TO THE MUSHRIKS  &amp;#8220;ALLAH, THE LORD OF THE HEAVENS AND THE EARTH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Four Priorities of the Muslim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</guid>
      <description>Abu Barzah al-Aslami radi Allahu anhu reported that Allah’s Messenger sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, “The two feet of the servant will not cease (from standing before Allah) on the Day of Judgment until he is asked about four things: on his life and how he spent it; on his knowledge and what he did with it; on his wealth and where he earned it and how he spent it; and on his body and in what way he utilized it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to Reject Narrators of Ahadith</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reasons-to-reject-narrators-of-ahadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 20:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reasons-to-reject-narrators-of-ahadith/</guid>
      <description>As you know, we cannot just accept a hadith from anyone&amp;#8211;this is our deen! If anyone could just say what they wanted, we would have nothing left of the true, pure message of Allah.
The scholars have analyzed the biographies of every narrator of hadith. They compile information on when he was born, and where, his kunya, his tribe, who he met, what his character was, what other people narrated about him &amp;#8230; piles and piles of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Mursal Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 18:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</guid>
      <description>In the sciences of hadith, there&amp;#8217;s something called a &amp;#8220;mursal&amp;#8221; hadith. What exactly is a mursal hadith? What is it&amp;#8217;s status? What are the fiqh rulings on mursal ahadith? And why does it matter?
(Ok, for the answer to the last question, read and learn about the science of hadith. In a sentence: Scholars have devised an extremely rigorous process to determine which hadith are authentic, and which are not. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to spend your whole life following a &amp;#8220;hadith,&amp;#8221; only to find out it really wasn&amp;#8217;t legit, do you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allah’s Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/allahs-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 16:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/allahs-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>We take it for granted that Allah has infinite knowledge. But what does this mean? Let&amp;#8217;s take a &amp;#8220;tour,&amp;#8221; if you like, of some of the things Allah knows.
There are 6-8 billion people on the face of the earth. That&amp;#8217;s 6 * 1000 * 1000 * 1000. That&amp;#8217;s a lot of people! Can you imagine learning 6 names? Or 60? Or 6000? But Allah knows their names&amp;#8211;all 6,000,000,000 of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unborn: Surah Ikhlas – Pt. 3 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
First and foremost, Ramadan Kareem! May Allah azza wa jal give us all the opportunity to take advantage of this blessed month and to make it a means of us attaining His Paradise. Ameen.
Due to Ramadan, I&amp;#8217;ve found myself to be quite busy. Nonetheless, I do apologize for not having written anything for the past few makes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qareen</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 01:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</guid>
      <description>What is a Qareen? A shaytaan, a devil, assigned to someone to mislead and misguide him. Someone to whisper to him in the light of day and the darkness of night. Allah says:
وَمَن يَعْشُ عَن ذِكْرِ الرَّحْمَنِ نُقَيِّضْ لَهُ شَيْطَاناً فَهُوَ لَهُ قَرِينٌ  Translation: And whoever is blinded from remembrance of Ar-Rahman, we appoint for him a qareen, and he is to him a companion. [Surah Az-Zukhruf, verse 36]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elite 99 Names of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-elite-99-names-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-elite-99-names-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Having already discussed the unlimited number of Allah&amp;#8217;s names and attributes, we turn now to an authentic hadith that seems to clash with what we said before.
The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said:
إِنَّ لِلَّهِ تِسْعَةً وَتِسْعِينَ اسْمًا مِائَةً إِلاّ وَاحِدًا مَنْ أَحْصَاهَا دَخَلَ الْجَنَّةَ .  Translation: Indeed, Allah has 99 names (one hundred minus one); whoever memorizes them will enter Jannah. [Saheeh Bukhari and Saheeh Muslim]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rays of Faith</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/rays-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 23:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/rays-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>Rays of Faith  Rays of Faith is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Waleed Basyouni. Rays of Faith focuses on the pillars of Emaan: belief in the Angels, the Books, the Prophets, the Day of Judgment, and the Divine Decree (Qadr wa Qadaa&amp;#8217;). This course will also go over the creation and realm of Jinns. These matters to us, are matters of the unseen but why is it so important?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Qantarah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/al-qantarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 17:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/al-qantarah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Abu Sa’eed al Khudree (رضى الله عنه) reports that the Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said, “when the believers cross the Hellfire, they will be stopped at a small arched bridge (Qantarah) before entering the paradise and will be given retribution for injustices between them until they become purified. (Then) they will be permitted to enter Jannah. So, by the One in Whose Hands is my soul, they will know their way to their homes in Jannah, better than they know their ways to their homes in dunya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 9</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 16:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-9/</guid>
      <description>We walk through life not understanding that we are in the midst of the biggest battle with the wretched of all enemies&amp;#8211;Shaytan. Understanding his tactics is one thing&amp;#8211;being able to follow it up with our own weapons is another. Listen to the podcast to learn and understand the different weapons believers can equip themselves with in this war against Shaytan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 8</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 01:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-8/</guid>
      <description>The fact of the matter is that Shaytan is an open enemy to humankind. It is through his whispers that he causes all of us to stray off in to the darkness of evil and misguidance. How else does Shaytan influence humankind? Listen to the podcast and find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 7</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 17:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-7/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on the topic of Shaytaan, this lecture focuses on the relationship between man and him. What is the clash between humans and Shaytaan? What is the goal of Shaytaan? And truly, what are the techniques by which he is succeeding in this battle? Listen to the podcast and find out more about this fore-sworn enemy of humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 6</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 17:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-6/</guid>
      <description>Of the devils, is the grand devil of them all, known as Iblees or Shaytaan. This lecture will focus on some of the wisdoms behind the creation of Shaytaan. As Muslims, we know that Shaytaan is our open enemy; not just for a period of time, but an enemy to the sons and daughters of Adam (عليه السلام) until the end of time. What was this wisdom of Allah behind the prolonged life of Shaytaan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 5</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 17:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-5/</guid>
      <description>With this lecture, we will begin to step into a brand new world &amp;#8230; the world of the Jinn. Who are they? What is their purpose? What is the Muslims&amp;#8217; stance on the Jinn? Listen to the podcast to find out about this little-known topic steeped in ignorance and superstition!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 17:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/light-of-eman-session-4/</guid>
      <description>The angels indeed are a beautiful creation of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Believing in them is of the pillars of eman, and disbelieving in them is disbelief. Why so? What are the blessings of the angels upon the believers? Listen to the podcast and find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
There are many words in Arabic that translate as &amp;#8220;love&amp;#8221; in English; two of them are hubb and wudd. What is the difference between hubb (حَبَّ) and wudd (وَدَّ)? Hubb, which is from ح ب ب ، means to love. It is a love that you have for someone or something that you keep inside of you&amp;#8211;inner feelings of admiration and fondness. While wudd, from و د د، is a more intense form of hubb, a whole-hearted and deep love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 18:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-3/</guid>
      <description>Who are the Angels? Truly, the Angels are creations of Allah with certain names and responsibilities. What are some of these names? Everyone knows about the Angel of Death&amp;#8211;but what other angels exist with special responsibilities? How do angels benefit us? Listen to the podcast below and find out right now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 21:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-2/</guid>
      <description>What is the second most important pillar of faith? Did you ever think that it was angels? Well it is &amp;#8230; come learn why! What are angels? Who are they? Why should we study the creation of angels? Listen and find out &amp;#8230; because surely securing knowledge of this creation of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) lights up the hearts with eman.
Listen to this podcast to find out the reality of eman, in Ilm Fruits’ exclusive Light of Eman series!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Eman Session 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 02:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-of-eman-session-1/</guid>
      <description>Eman. So simple&amp;#8230;yet we have failed to understood its true place in our deen.
And the man asked, &amp;#8220;What is Eman?&amp;#8221; The Prophet replied, &amp;#8220;It is to believe in Allah and&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
What did the Prophet say about Eman? How does it relate to us? Listen to this podcast to find out the reality of eman, in Ilm Fruits&amp;#8217; exclusive Light of Eman series!
Don&amp;#8217;t miss out! Check the Light of Eman page for the schedule!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jahannam and Jaheem</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/jahannam-and-jaheem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 16:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/jahannam-and-jaheem/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Reminders of the akhirah can have a great effect on our hearts and bring us out of the ghaflah (heedlessness) we are in. By looking at two words, Jahannam and Jaheem from the Qur&amp;#8217;an, we are able to see what the real life is, the real ending and the real punishment. May Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) make our best deeds our last and may He (سبحانه وتعالى) make us among those who will enter Jannah without reckoning or punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is not Allah Alone Worthy of our Worship?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/is-not-allah-alone-worthy-of-our-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 10:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/is-not-allah-alone-worthy-of-our-worship/</guid>
      <description>My brothers and sisters in Islam, As-salamu &amp;#8216;alaikum!
To testify that there is One Creator who sustains, nourishes, and controls is not enough for the Muslim. The Muslim is one who believes and testifies that indeed Allah is the Creator, the Nourisher, the Sustainer, and also affirms that ONLY He is worthy of worship.
Our testimony of faith is not, &amp;#8216;La Rabba ill Allah&amp;#8217; (There is no Lord except Allah), because if this was the case then even the mushrikeen of the time of our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) believed and testified that Allah was the sole Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have You TRULY Testified?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-truly-testified/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2007 05:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-truly-testified/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to say &amp;#8216;La Illaha Ill Allah&amp;#8217;? Has one every truly sat back and wondered what makes this one testimony so special? What makes this the differentiation point between one who believes and one who doesn&amp;#8217;t? Truly, it is every Muslims responsibility to comprehend fully what this Kalimah entails, because without it, one has not fulfilled the conditions of this testimony.
Someone asked a scholar of the past, &amp;#8220;is not the Shahada the key to Jannah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Do they seek other than the Religion of Allah…”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-they-seek-other-than-the-religion-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 10:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-they-seek-other-than-the-religion-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Of the categories of tawheed, the most common one is that of making Allah One and Unique in His Lordship i.e Tawheed ar-Ruboobiyyah. The meaning of this is believe that only Allah creates, sustains, and nourishes the entire creation. Of the manifestations of this are:
 every object must have a creator no object can escape that which is decreed when in distress all of mankind calls out to his Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE Purpose of Creation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-purpose-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2007 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-purpose-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>Our purpose of creation is one and that is tawheed. Tawheed is making Allah One and Unique in His Lordship (Ruboobiyyah), in His Names and Attributes (Asmaa was Sifaat), and in His rights to be worshiped (Uloohiyyah). There are many blessings associated with tawheed, of them are:
 Jannah a means for sins to be forgiven the right that Allah has over us the reason for sending Prophets and Books the dangers of its opposite &amp;#8211; shirk  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where’s Our Dignity?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wheres-our-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 07:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wheres-our-dignity/</guid>
      <description>Of the beautiful Names of Allah is al-Aziz, the Mighty. Al-Aziz is exalted, perfect in Might, He is the One who grants us victory, and He is the one who hates to have his slaves be humiliated. Dignity, Power, and Glory comes from Allah and Allah alone, and no one can attain this without worshiping Allah. It&amp;#8217;s time to become a true Abdul-Aziz.
Listen to the podcast to learn how exactly you can become a true Abdul-Aziz!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Haleem</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-haleem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 00:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-haleem/</guid>
      <description>Of Allah&amp;#8217;s names, is Al-Haleem (الحليم). What does Al-Haleem mean?
It&amp;#8217;s a very very deep name—like all of Allah&amp;#8217;s names, it&amp;#8217;s very deep. It comes from the root hilm, and hilm means a wisdom and a forebearance that allows a person to control their anger. Hilm is an intelligence that, in our terms, allows someone to control their anger, even if their anger is justified. It allows you to, when you are justifiably angry, to control it and not manifest it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ahlul Sunnah Wal Jam’aah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ahlul-sunnah-wal-jamaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2007 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ahlul-sunnah-wal-jamaah/</guid>
      <description>We hear this phrase thrown around a lot these days&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;ahlul sunnah wal jam&amp;#8217;aah&amp;#8221; (literally, &amp;#8220;the people of the sunnah and the jam&amp;#8217;ah/group&amp;#8221;). But what does it really mean, and who are the people who are TRULY ahlul sunnah wal jam&amp;#8217;aah?
To find out the answer, we must ask those who defined those terms. Not your friendly neighborhood shaykh or imam; not your mom, your dad, your grandfather, or his grandfather; not even the tabi&amp;#8217;oon, or the companions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Ghafuwr and Al-Ghaffaar</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 08:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</guid>
      <description>Of Allah&amp;#8217;s greatest names is Al-Ghafuwr (الغَفُور). It&amp;#8217;s one of the most common names mentioned in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (91 times). The name itself is on the pattern that denotes a very powerful doer of an action.
Linguistic Meaning: The root of Al-Ghaffuwr and Al-Ghaffar is the verb is ghafara (غَفَرَ), which does NOT mean &amp;#8220;to forgive&amp;#8221;; rather, it means to shield and protect and cover. Like a helmet, which, in Arabic, is called a &amp;#8220;mighfaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Name</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 13:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</guid>
      <description>Question: I heard that there&amp;#8217;s one name of Allah, that if you use it to invoke Allah, your du&amp;#8217;a is accepted. Is this true?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;To Allah belongs a Grand Name, that, if you make du&amp;#8217;a with it, it will be responded to. And if you plead or request with it, it shall be answered.&amp;#8221; [Recorded in Abu Dawud, Tirmidhi, and others; Saheeh]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Upon Light</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-upon-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 07:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-upon-light/</guid>
      <description>Light Upon Light  Light Upon Light: Fundamentals of Faith 102 is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Yasir Qadhi.
Allah. The name conjures up many associations&amp;#8211;the Creator, the Sustainer, the only one to be worshipped. The All-Knowing, the All-Seeing, the All-Hearing. Ar-Rahmaan, Ar-Raheem.
But who is Allah? Do we really know Allah (سبحانه وتعال), in all His majesty and glory and might and mercy? Or&amp;#8211;like so many of the Muslims today&amp;#8211;do we only claim to know Allah, while in fact, we know almost nothing about Him&amp;#8211;the one who sent the Prophets as a mercy to us, who created us for nothing but His worship, out of His mercy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Qahhar – The Subduer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</guid>
      <description>ٱلۡقَهَّارُ &amp;#8211; Al Qahhar  The root word for ٱلۡقَهَّارُ is قَهر which is defined as:
 to compel something or someone against his/her wishes to subdue to overcome to force [1]  Thus, with regards to Allah (سبحانه وتعال), the noble name Al-Qahhar can be translated as &amp;#8220;the Subduer, i.e. the Subduer of His creatures by His sovereign authority and power and the Disposer of them as He pleases, with and against their will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you remember?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-you-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 19:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/do-you-remember/</guid>
      <description>Why are we on this earth? This time, this place. People, make the use of the situation based on a cycle. The EAT-WORK-SLEEP cycle, which I believe turns out to be boring. Monday work starts, lasts till friday. Then again the same old weekend, were some claim to enjoy.
Or lets look at life as a whole. A person is born, goes to school, goes to university/ college, gets a job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distance of One Mile</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</guid>
      <description>In a very beautiful hadith, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: __
 “There are seven whom Allah will shade in His Shade on the Day when there is no shade except His Shade:
 a just ruler; a youth who grew up in the worship of Allah, the Mighty and Majestic; a man whose heart is attached to the mosques; two men who love each other for Allah’s sake, meeting for that and parting upon that; a man who is called by a woman of beauty and position [for illegal intercourse], but be says: ‘I fear Allah’; a man who gives in charity and hides it, such that his left hand does not know what his right hand gives in charity; and a man who remembered Allah in private and so his eyes shed tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a Witness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/you-are-a-witness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 02:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/you-are-a-witness/</guid>
      <description>Humankind is witness to the blessings that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) has bestowed upon them, yet they look the other way. Humankind is witness to the world and everything in it, yet they deny the very Creator of it. Subhanallah.
Narrated Abu Hurairah (رضي الله عنه): The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) said: &amp;#8216;The son of Adam tells a lie against Me, though he hasn&amp;#8217;t the right to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 17:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rejected/</guid>
      <description>On the Authority of the Mother of the Faithful, Umm Abdullah Aa’isha (رضي الله عنها) who said:
&amp;#8220;The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, ‘Whoever innovates something in this matter of ours that is not from it will have it rejected.&amp;rsquo;&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Holy Qur’an:
“This day, those disbelieved have given up all hope of your religion, so fear them not, but fear Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control? I Don’t Think So.</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/control-i-dont-think-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/control-i-dont-think-so/</guid>
      <description>Do you control your eyes? If so, then stop yourself from blinking. Do you control your heart? If so, then stop yourself from feeling. Do you control your brain? If so, then stop yourself from thinking.
Can’t do it, can you? If we’re not in control then who is?
Who else besides Al-Khaliq, The Creator &amp;#8212; Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)
Reality Check … this dunya is not what it percieves to be, so next time we think we got things under control, we should think again, because more than likely we don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing the Prophet in a Dream</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seeing-the-prophet-in-a-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 19:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seeing-the-prophet-in-a-dream/</guid>
      <description>Abu Hurayrah, Abu Qatadah and Jabir Ibn Abdullah reported, Rasoolullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) stated &amp;#8221; He who saw me in a dream in fact saw me, for Satan can not assume my form.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
The hadith clearly states that the Rasool of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) can be seen in a dream, as Satan (may Allah&amp;#8217;s curse be upon him) cannot take his form. However, some points which should be noted concerning its meaning are as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Barakah of the Ka’bah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-barakah-of-the-kabah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 16:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-barakah-of-the-kabah/</guid>
      <description>A lot of Muslims, in their great love for the Ka&amp;#8217;bah (which is an admiral thing), make some mistakes because of their lack of understanding about barakah. We already mentioned that the Ka&amp;#8217;bah is one of the places that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) put barakah&amp;#8211;but what does that mean?
As a reminder, only Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) decides what things contain barakah, and what things give barakah, because all barakah is from Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Du’a</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-meaning-of-dua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 20:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-meaning-of-dua/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;#8220;du&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8221; is the verbal noun of the verb &amp;#8220;da&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8221;, which means &amp;#8220;to call out, to summon.&amp;#8221;
With that said, du&amp;#8217;a is a fundamental aspect of Islam, and without it, one&amp;#8217;s eman cannot be intact. Allah mentions du&amp;#8217;a in the Qur&amp;#8217;an to signify many things, such as:
 Worship: وَلاَ تَدْعُ مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ مَا لاَ يَنْفَعُكَ وَلاَ يَضُرُّكَ 
Translation: &amp;#8220;And do not call besides Allah that which will not harm you or benefit you&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; [Surah Yunus, 10:106].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light of Guidance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/light-of-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2006 02:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/light-of-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Light of Guidance  Light of Guidance is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Yasir Qadhi. The course focuses on three aspects: shirk, nifaq, and kufr. Dwelve into issues such as the three types of tawhid, the perfection of La Ilaha Illallah, fruits of eman, grave-worship, jinns, magic, atheism, intercession, and more!
Posts  &amp;lt;?php PostFinder(&amp;rdquo;\&amp;ldquo;Light of Guidance\&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;); ?&amp;gt;
Primary Categories   Aqeeda  References  Yasir Qadhi. Lecture. AlMaghrib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 02:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</guid>
      <description>Anytime Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) mention Paradise for an action, it means that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) holds that action in high regard. So perform these activities regularly, and with ihsaan! Inshallah in the coming days, we will expound and narrate some instances where Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or His messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم), promised paradise &amp;#8212; keys that we can use to unlock the doors and, inshallah, enter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth is One</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/truth-is-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 21:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/truth-is-one/</guid>
      <description>Truth is one and falsehood is many. How do we know? Just look at the Qur&amp;#8217;an! Allah makes a simile of truth as a singular light (noor), and falsehood as a plural of darkness (dhulumaat &amp;#8212; multiple).
What&amp;#8217;s more, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) once drew a stick in the dirt and said &amp;#8220;this is the Straight Path.&amp;#8221; He then drew lines that grew away from it, left and right, and said &amp;#8220;these are the paths of misguidance, and at the top of every one of these paths is a devil calling the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-a-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 02:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-a-hadith/</guid>
      <description>What exactly is a hadith? It&amp;#8217;s a saying of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم). The Science of Hadith defines a hadeeth as &amp;#8220;whatever is attributed to the Prophet, in terms of sayings, actions, approvals, and physical and character descriptions.&amp;#8221; 1
Ahadith are an important part of Islam. They complement and the Qur&amp;#8217;an, and provide us with numerous benefits and different types of information, including:
 Laws not directly stated in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amplify Your Du’a With Tawassul</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amplify-your-dua-with-tawassul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 22:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amplify-your-dua-with-tawassul/</guid>
      <description>What is Tawassul? Linguistically, it means that which brings you closer to an object. The Arabic is tawassul (توسّل) or wasiylah (وسيلة). Islamically, it means any good deed that brings you closer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)&amp;#8211;so every single good deed can be called tawassul&amp;#8211;though scholars use it specifically to mean things that increase our chances of having our du&amp;#8217;a accepted.
The Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah only sanction four types of tawassal (with a difference of opinion on the fifth).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase Your Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2006 01:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Now that you know what barakah is, you might ask, how can one increase the barakah in his or her life? Aside from visiting the places with barakah, and making use of times with barakah, what else can you do?
The answer is very simple. If you want Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to bless you, then do anything for the sake of Allah, upon the sunnah (methodology) of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shirk, the Destroyer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/shirk-the-destroyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2006 20:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/shirk-the-destroyer/</guid>
      <description>Most of the ayat in the Qur&amp;#8217;an that are directed to non-Muslims, are directed to mushrikeen&amp;#8211;those who commit shirk. In fact, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) spells out, in painful detail, just how dangerous shirk is. Read and remember.
The Unforgivable Sin  Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says, in Surah Nisaa:
إِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِ وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَلِكَ لِمَن يَشَاء وَمَن يُشْرِكْ بِاللّهِ فَقَدِ افْتَرَى إِثْمًا عَظِيمًا  Translation: Verily, Allah forgives not that partners should be set up with him in worship, but He forgives except that (anything else) to whom He pleases, and whoever sets up partners with Allah in worship, he has indeed invented a tremendous sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mu’min Tree</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-mumin-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2006 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-mumin-tree/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Ibrahim, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) gives us the metaphor of the kalimah (la ilaha ilallah) as a beautiful tree. The verse is:
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ ضَرَبَ اللّهُ مَثَلاً كَلِمَةً طَيِّبَةً كَشَجَرةٍ طَيِّبَةٍ أَصْلُهَا ثَابِتٌ وَفَرْعُهَا فِي السَّمَاء  Translation: Have you not seen how Allah has given the parable of a beautiful kalimah, like a beautiful tree, whose roots are firmly established, and whose branches tower in the sky? (Surah Ibrahim, verse 24)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrikeen Believed in Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mushrikeen-believed-in-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 20:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mushrikeen-believed-in-allah/</guid>
      <description>Belief in Allah  Check this out. The mushrikeen, now and in the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), believed in Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Remember, these are the people who rejected Islam, and who are among the worst of people.
In Surah Ankabut, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَلَئِن سَأَلْتَهُم مَّنْ خَلَقَ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَسَخَّرَ الشَّمْسَ وَالْقَمَرَ لَيَقُولُنَّ اللَّهُ
[&amp;#8230;]
وَلَئِن سَأَلْتَهُم مَّن نَّزَّلَ مِنَ السَّمَاء مَاء فَأَحْيَا بِهِ الْأَرْضَ مِن بَعْدِ مَوْتِهَا لَيَقُولُنَّ اللَّهُ  Translation: If indeed thou ask them who has created the heavens and the earth and subjected the sun and the moon (to his Law), they will certainly reply, &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge, Practice, Da’wah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 18:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</guid>
      <description>Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
Q: Allah grants knowledge to those He loves. What do you do to be among these people?  A: Strive. Show interest in the deen. Come closer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and He will come closer to you. There is a hadith on how to gain knowledge: &amp;#8216;ilm is only gained by studying. It&amp;#8217;s not gained by hiding in a cave and worshipping Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Studious study is the only way to gain knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tawhid Ar-Rububiyyah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tawhid-ar-rububiyyah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2006 19:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tawhid-ar-rububiyyah/</guid>
      <description>Tawhid Ar-Rububiyyah can be roughly translated as &amp;#8220;Unity/Oneness of Lordship&amp;#8221;. It pertains to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and His lordship.
Definition  Rububiyyah is from rabb (ربّ), which has three linguistic meanings:
 Owner: The rabb is the true and complete owner. In one hadith, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;if you find a camel in the desert, leave it till it meets its rabb (owner)&amp;#8221;. Obediance: The rabb is the one who is to be obeyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blessings of Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/blessings-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2006 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/blessings-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>The Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah both praise knowledge. There are many blessings of knowledge&amp;#8211;but first, we must define, &amp;#8220;what IS knowledge?&amp;#8221;
The Prophet said, in one hadith: &amp;#8220;If Allah wants to do a favor to somebody, He bestows on him, the gift of understanding the deen.&amp;#8221; [Bukhari 9/92/415]1 From this hadith, we know that knowledge, as defined in the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah, refers to knowledge of Islam, and not secular knowledge (such as Chemistry or Meteorology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Times Blessed with Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/times-blessed-with-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2006 22:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/times-blessed-with-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask “what times has Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) blessed with barakah?”
There are six blessed times:
 Ramadan: The month of Ramadan, in general, is blessed. Also, the night of Laylatul-Qadr is specifically also very blessed. These are ideal times to worship Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), because the reward is greater. The last ten nights of Ramadan are the most blessed nights of the year&amp;#8211;more then the days of Dhul Hijjah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places that Contain Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/places-that-contain-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2006 03:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/places-that-contain-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask “what places has Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) blessed with barakah?”
To start, the three blessed massajid:
 The Ka&amp;#8217;bah: it is the most blessed place on the Earth, more-so then the surrounding holy sites. Medina: The city is blessed with barakah, and also, masjid an-nabawi has been blessed with barakah. Masjid al-Aqsa: the masjid, located in Jerusalem, in blessed, as well as the surrounding area of Sham in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that Contain Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/things-that-contain-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 20:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/things-that-contain-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask &amp;#8220;so what has barakah in it?&amp;#8221;
 The Qur&amp;#8217;an: In many verses, the Qur&amp;#8217;an itself is called &amp;#8220;mubarak&amp;#8221;. There is nothing but good in it&amp;#8211;every letter, every verse, every surah, every prohibition, every command. The revelation, the recitation, the understanding, and the memorization, as well, are blessed&amp;#8211;because they are the speech of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). The Prophets: All prophets have barakah, especially the last, Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Barakah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 02:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Tabaarak (تَبَارَك) has many meanings. The root word (ba-ra-kaf; like barakah) means:
 To Remain/Linger. This is why a pool of water is called birkah in Arabic. Same word. To Nurture/Generate. Connotations are that it increases.  Under Shari&amp;#8217;ah, the divine law of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), tabaarak means: the presence of divine blessings in an object, and an increase of those blessings. It also means: an increase in the amount of good in something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Way to Increase Eman?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2006 16:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</guid>
      <description>Question: What is the best way for a person increase his or her eman?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The single greatest way to increase your eman is to gain knowledge. Study what eman is, study tawhid, the pillars of eman, etc. It automatically increases your eman.
Good deeds also increase eman&amp;#8211;each and every single good deed and act of worship you perform increases your eman. Fast a day. Read Qur&amp;#8217;an. Pray Tahajjud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (10): Ease and Light Crossing the Sirat</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 20:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-10/</guid>
      <description>19) Ease and Light Crossing the Sirat  Towards the end of Judgement Day&amp;#8211;a day that will last 50 000 years (Surah Al-Maarij, verse 4)1, after the judgement has been decreed, the people will have to cross the Sirat&amp;#8211;a bridge sharper then a sword and thinner then a hair2, that runs over Hell&amp;#8211;in order to get to Jannah. People will fall off&amp;#8211;there will be hooks like thorns of a size known only to Allah, to snag people into the Fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (9): Benefit From Advice</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 01:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-9/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
18) Benefit From Advice  In Surah Adh-Dhariyat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَذَكِّرْ فَإِنَّ الذِّكْرَى تَنفَعُ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ  Translation: And continue to remind, for surely the reminder profits the believers. (Surah Adh-Dhariyat, verse 55)1
Notice, here, who benefits from the reminders&amp;#8211;not all humankind, but believers. Why? Try this hypothethical situation on for size: there&amp;#8217;s a guy who&amp;#8217;s sinning&amp;#8211;say he&amp;#8217;s drinking beer in front of you inside his home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (8): Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2006 03:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-8/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
17) Love Here and in the Hereafter  In Surah Maryam, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ سَيَجْعَلُ لَهُمُ الرَّحْمَنُ وُدًّا  Translation: On those who believe and work deeds of righteousness, (Allah) The Most Gracious bestows love. (Surah Maryam, verse 96)1
That is: on those who have eman and perform good deeds, Allah decrees for them love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (7): Brotherhood</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 18:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-7/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
16) Brotherhood  In Surah Hujraat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّمَا الْمُؤْمِنُونَ إِخْوَةٌ فَأَصْلِحُوا بَيْنَ أَخَوَيْكُمْ وَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ لَعَلَّكُمْ تُرْحَمُونَ  Translation: The Believers are but a single Brotherhood &amp;#8230; (Surah Hujraat, verse 10)1
If you&amp;#8217;ve ever been to a different city, you walk into the grocery store, and nobody says anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (6): Khilafah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 21:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-6/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
15) The Khalifa  In Surah Noor, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَعَدَ اللَّهُ الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا مِنكُمْ وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ لَيَسْتَخْلِفَنَّهُم فِي الْأَرْضِ كَمَا اسْتَخْلَفَ الَّذِينَ مِن قَبْلِهِمْ وَلَيُمَكِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ دِينَهُمُ الَّذِي ارْتَضَى لَهُمْ وَلَيُبَدِّلَنَّهُم مِّن بَعْدِ خَوْفِهِمْ أَمْنًا يَعْبُدُونَنِي لَا يُشْرِكُونَ بِي شَيْئًا وَمَن كَفَرَ بَعْدَ ذَلِكَ فَأُوْلَئِكَ هُمُ الْفَاسِقُونَ  Translation: Allah has promised, to those among you who believe and work righteous deeds, that He will, of a surety, grant them in the land, , inheritance (of power), &amp;#8230; [when] they worship Me (alone) and not associate aught with Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (5): Glad Tidings of Angels Before Death</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2006 22:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-5/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
14) Glad Tidings of Angels before Death  In Surah Fussilat, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ قَالُوا رَبُّنَا اللَّهُ ثُمَّ اسْتَقَامُوا تَتَنَزَّلُ عَلَيْهِمُ الْمَلَائِكَةُ أَلَّا تَخَافُوا وَلَا تَحْزَنُوا وَأَبْشِرُوا بِالْجَنَّةِ الَّتِي كُنتُمْ تُوعَدُونَ  Translation: In the case of those who say, &amp;#8220;Our Lord is Allah&amp;#8221;, and, further, stand straight and steadfast, the angels descend on them [and say]: &amp;#8220;Fear ye not, nor grieve!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (4): A Good Life</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 16:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
13) A Good Life  In Surah Nahl, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
مَنْ عَمِلَ صَالِحًا مِّن ذَكَرٍ أَوْ أُنثَى وَهُوَ مُؤْمِنٌ فَلَنُحْيِيَنَّهُ حَيَاةً طَيِّبَةً وَلَنَجْزِيَنَّهُمْ أَجْرَهُم بِأَحْسَنِ مَا كَانُواْ يَعْمَلُونَ  Translation: Whoever works righteousness, man or woman, and has Faith, verily, to him will We give a new Life, a life that is good and pure and We will bestow on such their reward according to the best of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (3)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 16:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-3/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
9) Good Always Happens to You  In one hadith, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;How amazing is the situation of the believer. His affair is always for the best, and this is not true for anyone besides the believer. If good befalls him he is thankful and this is best for him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (2)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2006 00:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
4) Forgiveness of Sins  In Surah Furqan, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِلَّا مَن تَابَ وَآمَنَ وَعَمِلَ عَمَلًا صَالِحًا فَأُوْلَئِكَ يُبَدِّلُ اللَّهُ سَيِّئَاتِهِمْ حَسَنَاتٍ وَكَانَ اللَّهُ غَفُورًا رَّحِيمًا  Translation: [Whoever] repents, believes, and works righteous deeds, Allah will change the evil of such persons into good, and Allah is Oft-Forgiving, Most Merciful,&amp;#8221; (Surah Furqan, verse 70)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (1)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-1/</guid>
      <description>Allah says in the Qur’an, in Surah Ibrahim:
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ ضَرَبَ اللّهُ مَثَلاً كَلِمَةً طَيِّبَةً كَشَجَرةٍ طَيِّبَةٍ أَصْلُهَا ثَابِتٌ وَفَرْعُهَا فِي السَّمَاء
تُؤْتِي أُكُلَهَا كُلَّ حِينٍ بِإِذْنِ رَبِّهَا وَيَضْرِبُ اللّهُ الأَمْثَالَ لِلنَّاسِ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ  Translation: Have you not seen how Allah has given the parable of a beautiful kalimah, like a beautiful tree whose roots are firmly established, and whose branches tower in the sky? It gives its fruits at all times by the permission of it&amp;#8217;s Lord, and Allah sets forth parables for mankind in order that they may remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief: A Beautiful Tree</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-a-beautiful-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 22:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-a-beautiful-tree/</guid>
      <description>Allah says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, in Surah Ibrahim:
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ ضَرَبَ اللّهُ مَثَلاً كَلِمَةً طَيِّبَةً كَشَجَرةٍ طَيِّبَةٍ أَصْلُهَا ثَابِتٌ وَفَرْعُهَا فِي السَّمَاء
تُؤْتِي أُكُلَهَا كُلَّ حِينٍ بِإِذْنِ رَبِّهَا وَيَضْرِبُ اللّهُ الأَمْثَالَ لِلنَّاسِ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ  Translation: Have you not seen how Allah has given the parable of a beautiful kalimah, like a beautiful tree whose roots are firmly established, and whose branches tower in the sky? &amp;#8230; Allah sets forth parables for mankind in order that they may remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Aspects of Tawhid</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/three-aspects-of-tawhid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 15:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/three-aspects-of-tawhid/</guid>
      <description>Scholars of &amp;#8216;aqeeda divide tawhid into three aspects: tawhid ar-rububiyyah, tawhid al-uloohiyyah, and tawhid al-asmaa wal sifat.
Tawhid Ar-Rububiyyah is the tawhid of Lordship. It pertains to Allah&amp;#8217;s right as the Lord, and all that entails&amp;#8211;the Creator, the Sustainer.
Tawhid Al-Uloohiyyah is the tawheed of worship. It pertains to Allah&amp;#8217;s right to be worshipped, without any partners.
Tawhid Al-Asmaa wal Sifat is the tawheed of Allah&amp;#8217;s names and attributes&amp;#8211;such as that he is Ar-Rahman and Ar-Rahim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Ibadah, Natural Actions, Religious Actions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Ibadah. We hear the word all the time. But what does it mean?
Linguistically, &amp;#8216;ibadah means to show subserviance, or to be subserviant to.
From a shar&amp;#8217;ee perspective, &amp;#8216;ibadah has two meanings:
 The spiritual conscience of the worshipper&amp;#8211;what constitutes worship spiritually. The actions&amp;#8211;what consitutes worship in action.  And Ibn Tamiyyah says: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Ibadah includes all hidden and shown actions, statements, and beliefs beloved to Allah.&amp;#8221;
Of actions, there are two types: natural and religious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness for Shirk?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 05:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</guid>
      <description>Allah blessed me with the opportunity to listen to Shaykh Yasir Qadhi, who specializes in Aqeeda, speak about shirk. Here&amp;#8217;s what he said.
Question: What happens if you&amp;#8217;re Muslim and you&amp;#8217;ve committed shirk?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
In the Qur&amp;#8217;an, in many places, Allah says shirk is unforgivable.
إِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِ وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَلِكَ لِمَن يَشَاء وَمَن يُشْرِكْ بِاللّهِ فَقَدِ افْتَرَى إِثْمًا عَظِيمًا  Translation: Surely Allah does not forgive that anything should be associated with Him, and forgives what is besides that to whomsoever He pleases; and whoever associates anything with Allah, he devises indeed a great sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>