<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arabic on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/arabic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arabic on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 22:59:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/arabic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Nazi’at, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/tafseer-surah-naziat-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 22:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/tafseer-surah-naziat-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/footsteps-snow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Will we be returned exactly in our footsteps?&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1648&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is post #42 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, insha&amp;#8217;Allah we will take a whirlwind tour of the first third or so of Surah Naazi&amp;#8217;aat, a great and powerful surah of the Qur&amp;#8217;an. Then insha&amp;#8217;Allah we will go back and dive into more details (particularly in the Arabic side of things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالنَّازِعَاتِ غَرْقًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالنَّاشِطَاتِ نَشْطًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالسَّابِحَاتِ سَبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالسَّابِقَاتِ سَبْقًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُدَبِّرَاتِ أَمْرًا&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By those [angels] who extract with violence, and [by] those who remove with ease, and [by] those who glide [as if] swimming, and those who race each other in a race, and those who arrange [each] matter, &amp;#8230; [Surah Nazi&amp;#8217;at, verses 1-5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ayaat describe attributes of angels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ripping Out:&lt;/strong&gt; Gharq (غَرْق) means to rip out, to yank out, to extract harshly. If you had a tree and you uprooted it, roots and all, that would be gharq. This refers to the angels who remove the souls of the corrupt and the evil-doers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gently Pulling:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse two contrasts verse one by mentioning nasht (نَشْط), which is like a gentle pulling. This refers to the angels that remove the souls of the righteous believers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swimming:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse three refers to angels who &lt;em&gt;swim through the air&lt;/em&gt;; they are described as swimming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Racing:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse four refers to angels who are racing; racing the souls of the righteous to Jannah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Al-Mudabiraat:&lt;/strong&gt; Al-Mudabiraat are those angelswho settle the affairs of deen and dunya, in the dunya. They take care of floods, earthquakes, and other natural disasters, among other things. Their name, al-mudabiraat, also implies that they are thorough planners and executers of those plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are &lt;em&gt;aqsaam&lt;/em&gt; (oaths), which is typical in Mecci surahs. What is Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) swearing to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Analysis of Surah Balad</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-of-surah-balad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 03:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-of-surah-balad/</guid>
      <description>This is post #35 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In this post, we will insha&amp;#8217;Allah do a word-for-word breakdown of each surah, as space permits.
In the first ayah, Allah (subhannahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala) says:
 لَا أُقْسِمُ بِهَٰذَا الْبَلَدِ
 The first two words, laa uqsimu (لَا أُقْسِمُ) literally means &amp;#8220;I do not swear.&amp;#8221; Uqsimu is mudaari&amp;#8217; mutakallim waahid, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Tawbah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
This is a translation from the original article in Arabic.
1- It is a cause to receive the Love of Allah azza wa jal. The Most High says:
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ التَّوَّابِينَ وَيُحِبُّ الْمُتَطَهِّرِينَ Truly, Allah loves those who turn unto Him in repentance and loves those who purify themselves. (2:222)
2- It is a cause of success. The Most High says:
وَتُوبُوا إِلَى اللَّهِ جَمِيعًا أَيُّهَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ لَعَلَّكُمْ تُفْلِحُونَ  And all of you beg Allah to forgive you, O believers, that you may be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Analysis of Surah Qaari’ah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-of-surah-qaariah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-of-surah-qaariah/</guid>
      <description>A faraash&amp;#8211;a moth.  This is post #31 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
As per the poll on our twitter account, there was consensus on their being a post on grammatical analysis of Surah Qaari&amp;#8217;ah. So here you go insha&amp;#8217;Allah.
Standard Disclaimer: I am not an Arab (as in, fluent in Arabic) nor have I double-checked this in books of &amp;#8216;ulama discussing grammar; there is sometimes difference of opinion in grammar, as well; so take it as such insha&amp;#8217;Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Qadar: What’s Better Than 1000 Months?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qadar-whats-better-than-1000-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qadar-whats-better-than-1000-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is post #25 in our series on Tafseer of Juz ‘Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-of-revelation&#34;&gt;Reason of Revelation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) told the companions about a man of the previous nations; a man who lived and fought jihad for over 1000 months (roughly 83 years, 4 months). (In case you didn&amp;#8217;t know, the previous nations lived longer than us&amp;#8211;like Prophet Nuh (alayhi salaam), who did da&amp;#8217;wah for nearly 1000 years.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The companions were amazed, and they said: how can we compete with him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And subhanallah, this is a gem. &lt;em&gt;Look at the companions.&lt;/em&gt; They &lt;strong&gt;prioritized and competed for the akhirah.&lt;/strong&gt; Subhanallah to the point that, they don&amp;#8217;t just try to do &amp;#8220;some good deeds before I die;&amp;#8221; not enough. They competed with each other&amp;#8211;but even that was not enough. Rather, &lt;span class=&#34;gem&#34;&gt;they competed with all of the Muslims, ever, starting from the time of Prophet Adam, until the Day of Judgment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to really look at ourselves and see, how much are we like them? Or are we just vying for bigger houses, better cars&amp;#8211;more dunya?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Tawheed</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-tawheed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 19:19:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-tawheed/</guid>
      <description>This is post #23 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
Allah says, in Surah Tawheed, also known as Surah Ikhlas:
 قُلْ هُوَ اللَّهُ أَحَدٌ
اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ
لَمْ يَلِدْ وَلَمْ يُولَدْ
وَلَمْ يَكُن لَّهُ كُفُوًا أَحَدٌ
 Translation: Say, &amp;#8220;He is Allah , [who is] One, Allah , the Eternal Refuge [As-Samad], He neither begets (gives birth to) nor is born, Nor is there to Him any equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Explanation of Surah Takweer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-explanation-of-surah-takweer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 18:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-explanation-of-surah-takweer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #17 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/sun-in-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1177&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  When the sun is &lt;em&gt;kuwwirat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re going to digress a bit and jump back to Surah Takweer. This post is based on Shaykh Nouman Khan&amp;#8217;s tafseer, which heavily emphasizes the Arabic language. I hope you will find, as I found it, as a glimpse of a previously-unseen world, a depth of knowledge that just drips from the Arabic language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in surah Takweer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;إِذَا الشَّمْسُ كُوِّرَتْ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; When the sun is &lt;em&gt;kuwwirat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230; [verse 1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of gems that we learn even from this first ayah:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idhaa + Past-Tense:&lt;/strong&gt; Idhaa is an indicator of future-tense &amp;#8220;when (something will happen).&amp;#8221; Yet, kuwwirat is past-tense; why? This combination means &lt;strong&gt;something is so certain, it&amp;#8217;s like past-tense.&lt;/strong&gt; So Allah is saying &amp;#8220;when this happens,&amp;#8221; yet it&amp;#8217;s certain that it WILL happen; as certain as the past is past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nominal Sentence:&lt;/strong&gt; The default in Arabic is to put the verb first&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;kuwwirat ash-shamsu.&amp;#8221; To reverse this into &amp;#8220;ash-shamsu kuwwirat,&amp;#8221; shows emphasis, and makes it a tougher, stronger sentence. This hints at the audience&amp;#8211;Mushrikeen in Mecca, the worst and most obstinate of them, who are listening to this revelation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/strong&gt; Allah could have said, &amp;#8220;When I wrap up the sun,&amp;#8221; but He didn&amp;#8217;t. Why? If you&amp;#8217;re biased against someone (say a political party), &lt;em&gt;no matter what they say&lt;/em&gt;, even before they open their mouth, you say, &amp;#8220;psshh.&amp;#8221; But here, passive-voice highlights the maf&amp;#8217;ool, the recipient of the action&amp;#8211;the sun, the stars&amp;#8211;instead of the doer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the meaning of kuwwirat, kawwara means to wrap something around something; it&amp;#8217;s used in the context of a turban, something long, that&amp;#8217;s wrapped around your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah is applying the same meaning here&amp;#8211;that the light of the sun, something that&amp;#8217;s long, will be kuwwirat, wrapped up. Wrapped up meaning, something will cover it, and it will no longer be visible; and it will be wrapped slowly, part by part disappearing&amp;#8211;the same way that Allah described the day as wrapping around the night and the night wrapping around the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something scary&amp;#8211;that you see the sun wrapped up, and losing its light. But &lt;em&gt;there&amp;#8217;s more&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Lahab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-lahab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 16:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-lahab/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is post #7 in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
Most of us know Surah Lahab. It&amp;#8217;s one of the first one Muslim children learn these days. We&amp;#8217;re going to breeze through the tafseer, then dive into one of the miracles, and finish up with some Arabic analysis.
Allah says:
 تَبَّتْ يَدَا أَبِي لَهَبٍ وَتَبَّ
مَا أَغْنَى عَنْهُ مَالُهُ وَمَا كَسَبَ
سَيَصْلَى نَاراً ذَاتَ لَهَبٍ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Analysis for First Revelation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-for-first-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-for-first-revelation/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
The first five ayaat of Surah Iqraa are:
 اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ
خَلَقَ الْإِنسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ
اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ
الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ
عَلَّمَ الْإِنسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ
 Word-for-word translations are pretty common these days (like this one, which has Surah Iqraa), so I&amp;#8217;m going to touch lightly on that, and do a bit more grammar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’anic Oath: Tallahi!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quranic-oath-tallahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 16:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quranic-oath-tallahi/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Aqsaam (oaths) in the Qur&amp;#8217;an are a very fascinating subject that we should study and focus on more. There are a few components needed for a qasm (oath) to occur. One of them is the harf qasm, a letter that shows there is an oath being taken.
There are a few letters in the Qur&amp;#8217;an that are used as harf qasm, for example, Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala says &amp;#8220;wal &amp;#8216;aadiyaati dhabhaa&amp;#8221;. The harf qasm in this oath is the letter wow (و).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’an vs Kitaab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 01:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
The two most common names for the Book of Allah are: Qur&amp;#8217;an and Kitaab.
We learn when studying the Qur&amp;#8217;an that even the words chosen are a revelation from Allah with divine wisdom. So, in that case, what do these two names mean and what is the difference between them?
The word &amp;#8216;Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8217; is said to be from two roots, one of them qaaf-ra-hamza, this root qara&amp;#8217;a means to recite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOW is the Time to Learn Arabic!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/now-is-the-time-to-learn-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 16:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/now-is-the-time-to-learn-arabic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bismillah walhamdulillah, was Salaatu was Salaamu &amp;#8216;alaa Rasoolillaah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;On the Day of Judgment, the Qur&amp;#8217;an and its people who used to act by it in the world shall be brought, being lead by Surat ul-Baqarah and Al-e-Imraan, which shall be arguing on behalf of their &lt;span&gt;companions&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (Reported by Muslim)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all strive to become a companion of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, but who are its true companions? The companions of the Qur&amp;#8217;an are those who studied it, memorized it, implemented it and lived by it. It is not possible, in the least bit, for one to become a companion of the Qur&amp;#8217;an and not know Arabic. Learning the language is the starting point of a life long journey with the Qur&amp;#8217;an. Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala chose this blessed language, as He states 11 times throughout the Qur&amp;#8217;an: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;A Book, whereof the verses are explained in detail as an &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, for people who know.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (41:3), &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;An &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, without any crookedness, so that they may have Taqwa.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (39:28), &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;We have sent it down as an &lt;span&gt;Arabic&lt;/span&gt; Qur&amp;#8217;an, in order that you may gain understanding.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (12:2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do not know the language of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, they will be deprived of its true sweetness, of its blessings and most importantly, understanding the words of Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala. It is a cause of much grief and sadness to know that the majority of our ummah has lost the connection with the Book of Allah because the language has been lost, as the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Allah raises up peoples by this Book, and puts down by it others.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (Saheeh Muslim) We have abandoned this book, and the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam will testify to Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala on the day of judgment: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;And the Messenger will say, O my Rabb, indeed my people deserted this Qur&amp;#8217;an!&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (25:30)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The righteous companions and scholars of the past have testified to the importance of learning this language and they themselves, who were native Arab speakers, were concerned with studying this language. Umar radi Allahu anhu said, &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Learn Arabic for it is a part of your deen&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; (Iqtidaa&amp;#8217; al-Siraat al-Mustaqeem, &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;207&lt;/sub&gt;) It is also reported that Ubay ibn Ka&amp;#8217;b radi Allahu anhu said, &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Learn Arabic just as you learn to memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#8221; (Ibn Abî Shaybah, &lt;em&gt;Al-Mu&lt;span&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;annaf&lt;/em&gt; Vol.7 p150)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us want to take the proper steps to learn Arabic, but do not know where to start. What is the solution? Where do we begin? The best option is to study overseas, however many of us do not have that option to learn Arabic, so inshaAllah we&amp;#8217;ll cover in this article some easy steps one can take to begin the process of learning Qur&amp;#8217;anic Arabic if they cannot travel to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ismul Jalaalah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Ismul Jalaalah, The Grand Name: Allah الله. This is Allah&amp;#8217;s Personal Name. His Identifying Name. This Name only belongs to Allah, no one else can have besides Allah. Allah is the Title, the Name, of the One True Ilaah. The Name of Allah, you cannot play around with: there is no plural, there is no feminine. The Name Allah appears over 3000 times in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
When we mentioned the Name &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221; linguistically, we don&amp;#8217;t say &amp;#8220;the word Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the Name Allah&amp;#8221; because it is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an is Mubaarak</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-quran-is-mubaarak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 11:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-quran-is-mubaarak/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah subhanahu wa ta’ala says in Surah Saad verse 29,كِتَابٌ أَنْزَلْنَاهُ إِلَيْكَ مُبَارَكٌ لِيَدَّبَّرُوا آيَاتِهِ وَلِيَتَذَكَّرَ أُولُو الأَلْبَابِ  “(This is) a Mubaarak Book which We have sent down to you, that they may reflect upon its signs, and that men of understanding may remember.” (Saad: 38:29)  Mubaarak is that which is full of barakah. And barakah is from the root, ba ra kaaf (ب ر ك), and barakah is that which lasts long and has the ability to increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the Qur’an, full of Dhikr!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/by-the-quran-full-of-dhikr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 19:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/by-the-quran-full-of-dhikr/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
In one of the most beautiful beginnings of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala starts surah Saad with a powerful reminder. He says:
صۚ وَالْقُرْآنِ ذِي الذِّكْرِ
Saad. And by the Qur&amp;#8217;an, full of dhikr! [Surah Saad, verse 1]
This ayah begins with a letter, which are known as: huroof muqatta&amp;#8217;aat, the disjointed letters. There are many opinions as to what these letters mean, but the greatest and strongest opinion is that none but Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala knows their meanings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Delight</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 03:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
What is the greatest gift you could ever receive? That you could ever want? That would bring you the greatest happiness and delight?&amp;#8230;..Think about it.
Got an idea? &amp;#8230;.good.
Most of us will be thinking of Jannah and all of its delights. But the most pleasurable thing in Jannah is not having spouses, or servants that will serve you, or drinking milk and honey. No rather, there is something MUCH GREATER for the Dwellers of Jannah that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala is keeping for them&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubhanAllah: A Pure Negation (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah was-salatu was-salam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam
Continuing in our discussion of the oft-repeated words and phrases in our salat, this week inshallah we will focus on looking at: SubhanAllah
This is another word that is very common in the Muslim&amp;#8217;s vocabulary. We all have heard the word, we all say it in our prayers daily (inshallah), yet how many of us truly understand its meaning?
Commonly this word is translated as, &amp;#8220;Glory be to Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;All Glory is to Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Tasbeeh?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 14:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we now know what hamd means, let&amp;#8217;s move on to tasbeeh!
Tasbeeh means to say subhanAllah just as tahmeed means to say alhamdulillah.
  Tasbeeh is comprised of two words: Subhan and Allah: سبحان الله
Subhan which is derived from tasbeeh is from seen-ba-ha (س-ب-ح) and it means to glorify, praise, magnify, extol Allah, by tongue or by heart. It includes:
1-To say He has no flaw in His Perfection Far above any imperfection</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooba!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 01:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah ta’ala says:
الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ طُوبَىٰ لَهُمْ وَحُسْنُ مَآبٍ  Those who have believed and done righteous deeds – ‘Tooba’ is theirs and a good return. (Suratur Ra’ad, ayah 29)
Allah ta’ala promises ‘Tooba’ to the believers in this ayah. We also know this word for the famous hadeeth of the strangers, the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam states: fa Tooba lil ghurabaa’, so Tooba to the strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Hamd?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 22:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
As Muslims, the phrase &amp;#8220;alhamdulillah&amp;#8221; الحمد لله (all praise and thanks is for Allah) is an integral part of our deen; we are taught to say it from both the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah. Linguistically, Hamd is from ha-meem-daal ( حمد or ح م د) and it is to mention the good attribute of a person, such an attribute that is the at the level of perfection. Hamd is based on mahabbah (love) and ta&amp;#8217;dheem (greatness).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Peace</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Sitting in a halaqah–in a khutbah–in an AlMaghrib class, learning about the deen of Allah– the emanrush, your heart just flutters with tranquility. With satisfaction. With humility. With peace.
Why do we only feel this way in these gatherings?
Allah azza wa jal provides the answer:
He says in Surah Ra’d ayah 28:الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ وَتَطْمَئِنُّ قُلُوبُهُم بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ أَلاَ بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ تَطْمَئِنُّ الْقُلُوب
Those who have believed and whose hearts find satisfaction in the remembrance of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raging and Roaring</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 23:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:إِذَا رَأَتْهُمْ مِنْ مَكَانٍ بَعِيدٍ سَمِعُوا لَهَا تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِير 
When it sees them from a far place, they will hear its raging and its roaring. Suratul Furqan, verse 12
What is the &amp;#8220;it&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;them&amp;#8221; in this verse referring too? When the hell fire sees the disbelievers. Hell fire will see them from a far place, and they will hear it تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِيرًا , raging with fury and roaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reading Light: Importance of Tafseer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 00:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur’an,
كِتَابٌ أَنزَلْنَاهُ إِلَيْكَ مُبَارَكٌ لِّيَدَّبَّرُوا آيَاتِهِ وَلِيَتَذَكَّرَ أُوْلُوا الْأَلْبَابِ  &amp;#8220;(This is) a Book which We have sent down to you, full of blessings, so that they may ponder over its verses, and that men of understanding may remember.” Surah Saad: verse 29.
(linguistic explanation of the word yaddabaroo is in the comments)
It is the science of tafseer which is the fruit of ‘pondering over its verses’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Only …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Suratul Anbiya:
لَوْ يَعْلَمُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا حِينَ لَا يَكُفُّونَ عَن وُجُوهِهِمُ النَّارَ وَلَا عَن ظُهُورِهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يُنصَرُونَ  Translation: If only those who disbelieved knew when they will not be able to ward off the Fire from their faces, nor from their backs; and they will not be helped. [Surah Suratul Anbiya, verse 39]
The word for ward off is &amp;#8220;yakuffoona&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;يَكُفُّونَ&amp;#8221; and this is from the root word &amp;#8220;ka-fa-fa&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;kaff&amp;#8221; which means palm/hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you Stand with Allah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
حدثنا زهير بن حرب وعثمان بن أبي شيبة وإسحاق بن إبراهيم قال إسحاق أخبرنا وقال الآخران حدثنا جرير عن منصور عن أبي وائل عن عبد الله قال قال رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم إن الصدق يهدى إلى البر وإن البر يهدى إلى الجنة وإن الرجل ليصدق حتى يكتب صديقا وإن الكذب يهدى إلى الفجور وإن الفجور يهدى إلى النار وإن الرجل ليكذب حتى يكتب كذابا  Translation: Narrated &amp;#8216;Abdullah: The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: Truthfulness (sidq) leads to righteousness (birr), and righteousness leads to Paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following vs. Obeying</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 15:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-e-Imran ayaat 31-32:
قُلْ إِن كُنتُمْ تُحِبُّونَ اللّهَ فَاتَّبِعُونِي يُحْبِبْكُمُ اللّهُ وَيَغْفِرْ لَكُمْ ذُنُوبَكُمْ وَاللّهُ غَفُورٌ رَّحِيمٌ
قُلْ أَطِيعُواْ اللّهَ وَالرَّسُولَ فإِن تَوَلَّوْاْ فَإِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يُحِبُّ الْكَافِرِينَ  Translation: Say: If you should love Allah, then follow me (so) Allah will love you and forgive your sins. And Allah is Al-Ghafuwr (the All-Forgiving), Ar-Raheem (the All-Mericful). Say, Obey Allah and His Messenger. But if you turn away then indeed, Allah does not love the disbelievers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Duaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 20:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
How many times have we heard this duaa in our lives: Rabbana aatina fid-dunya hasanah, wa fil-akhirati hasanah, wa qinaa athaban naar. Have we ever contemplated how complete this duaa is?
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says
فَمِنَ النَّاسِ مَن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا وَمَا لَهُ فِي الآخِرَةِ مِنْ خَلاَقٍ وِمِنْهُم مَّن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا حَسَنَةً وَفِي الآخِرَةِ حَسَنَةً وَقِنَا عَذَابَ النَّارِ  Translation: And among the people is he who says, &amp;#8220;our Lord, give us in this world,&amp;#8221; and he will have in the Hereafter no share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth’s Fill in Gold</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earths-weight-in-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2007 19:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earths-weight-in-gold/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُواْ وَمَاتُواْ وَهُمْ كُفَّارٌ فَلَن يُقْبَلَ مِنْ أَحَدِهِم مِّلْءُ الأرْضِ ذَهَبًا وَلَوِ افْتَدَى بِهِ أُوْلَـئِكَ لَهُمْ عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌ وَمَا لَهُم مِّن نَّاصِرِينَ  Translation: Indeed, those who disbelieve and die while they are disbelievers &amp;#8211; never would the [whole] capacity of the earth in gold be accepted from one of them if he would [seek to] ransom himself with it. For those there will be a painful punishment, and they will have no helpers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Museebah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 12:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-Baqarah:
وَلَنَبْلُوَنَّكُمْ بِشَيْءٍ مِّنَ الْخَوْفِ وَالْجُوعِ وَنَقْصٍ مِّنَ الأَمْوَالِ وَالأنفُسِ وَالثَّمَرَاتِ وَبَشِّرِ الصَّابِرِينَ
الَّذِينَ إِذَا أَصَابَتْهُم مُّصِيبَةٌ قَالُواْ إِنَّا لِلّهِ وَإِنَّا إِلَيْهِ رَاجِعونَ  Translation: And We shall surely test you with something of fear and hunger and a loss of wealth and lives and fruits, but give good tidings to the patient. Those who when disaster strikes them, say, &amp;#8220;Indeed we belong to Allah and indeed to Him we will return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
There are many words in Arabic that translate as &amp;#8220;love&amp;#8221; in English; two of them are hubb and wudd. What is the difference between hubb (حَبَّ) and wudd (وَدَّ)? Hubb, which is from ح ب ب ، means to love. It is a love that you have for someone or something that you keep inside of you&amp;#8211;inner feelings of admiration and fondness. While wudd, from و د د، is a more intense form of hubb, a whole-hearted and deep love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizq Without Measure</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
كُلَّمَا دَخَلَ عَلَيْهَا زَكَرِيَّا الْمِحْرَابَ وَجَدَ عِندَهَا رِزْقاً قَالَ يَا مَرْيَمُ أَنَّى لَكِ هَذَا قَالَتْ هُوَ مِنْ عِندِ اللّهِ إِنَّ اللّهَ يَرْزُقُ مَن يَشَاءُ بِغَيْرِ حِسَابٍ  هُنَالِكَ دَعَا زَكَرِيَّا رَبَّهُ قَالَ رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِن لَّدُنْكَ ذُرِّيَّةً طَيِّبَةً إِنَّكَ سَمِيعُ الدُّعَاءِ  Translation: Every time he entered Al-Mihrab to her, he found her supplied with sustenance. He said: &amp;#8220;O Maryam (Mary)! From where have you got this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words beginning with Fa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/words-beginning-with-fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 14:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/words-beginning-with-fa/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Learning Arabic as a second language may be difficult for many, so I decided to share some tips that assist with learning the meanings of words and their structures.
Words that begin with ف usually will always mean something that breaks open, separates, or breaks apart. Check out these examples:
الفجر (Al-Fajr) from ف ج ر means the dawn, but it literally means when the daylight breaks/crack through the darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision in Vowels</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/precision-in-vowels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/precision-in-vowels/</guid>
      <description>To give your recitation a quick boost, try &amp;#8216;Itmaam-ul-Harakaat&amp;#8217;. No, it&amp;#8217;s not a medicine from Yemen. &amp;#8216;Itmaam&amp;#8217; simply means completion &amp;amp; &amp;#8216;harakaat&amp;#8217; could be loosely translated to mean vowels. It means fine-tuning the vowels. Unlike English, unitary vowels in Arabic are not letters &amp;#8211; thus not written out explicitly. Instead, they are shown with either of the following 3 marks above or below a letter.
Fathah: straight stroke on top of a letter, pronounced like the &amp;#8216;a&amp;#8217; as in &amp;#8220;bat&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Calling Ya</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-calling-ya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 10:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-calling-ya/</guid>
      <description>Arabic has something called the &amp;#8220;calling ya&amp;#8221; in it. The closest thing we have in English is the &amp;#8220;calling o&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;as in &amp;#8220;o my teacher&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;Oh God!&amp;#8221; (As you can tell from the examples, we don&amp;#8217;t use it much anymore these days&amp;#8211;though, in Arabic, it&amp;#8217;s quite common.)
The rules are quite simple&amp;#8211;just like English, it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;O so-and-so&amp;#8221;. So for example, you could say &amp;#8220;ya ummiy&amp;#8221; (o my mother) or &amp;#8220;ya taajiru&amp;#8221; (o merchant).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thumma, Wa, and Fa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thumma-wa-and-fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2007 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thumma-wa-and-fa/</guid>
      <description>There are three conjunctions you can use in Arabic (among others)&amp;#8211;wa (and), thumma (then), and fa (which is difficult to translate, think of it as &amp;#8220;and&amp;#8221;). They are all used to group multiple items. What are the differences between these three?
Wa indicates grouping, but doesn&amp;#8217;t specify order or timing. For example: Ahmed and Ghufran and Yusuf travelled to the masjid. It doesn&amp;#8217;t indicate what order they arrived in, or anything about how long the people who came first waited for the people who came after then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaana as Emphasis</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/kaana-as-emphasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 18:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/kaana-as-emphasis/</guid>
      <description>The word kaana is the past-tense masculine singular third-person (he) form of the verb to-be. So you can translate it as &amp;#8220;he was&amp;#8221;. (And the khabr takes the same rules as with any other verb.)
So what does it mean when Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) uses kaana to describe Himself? For example, in surah Nisaa, He says:
إِنَّ اللّهَ كَانَ غَفُوراً رَّحِيماً  Translation: And seek the Forgiveness of Allah; surely, Allah is Oft-forgiving, Most Merciful [Surah Nisaa, 4:106]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mubtada and Khabr</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/mubtada-and-khabr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2007 12:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/mubtada-and-khabr/</guid>
      <description>In Arabic, default kind of sentence is called a nominal sentence. It looks something like this:
 Ahmad is rich The masjid is big I am a Muslim  It has two parts&amp;#8211;the mubtada (the subject &amp;#8212; eg. Ahmad), and the khabr (the predicate&amp;#8211;information about the mubtada &amp;#8212; eg. rich, big, a Muslim).
What are the rules of grammar as they apply to the mubtada and the khabr? There are three:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laysa (Not)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/laysa-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 22:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/laysa-not/</guid>
      <description>Laysa in Arabic means &amp;#8220;not&amp;#8221; (eg. that is not a pen). Unlike the other negations maa and laa, laysa is conjugated as a verb, depending on what you&amp;#8217;re negating.
For example:
 the duck is not big (al-battatu laysat kabiyratan) the cat is not lazy (al-qittu laysa bi kaslaana)  Whenever you use laysa, the mubtada and khabr change: the mubtada becomes ismu laysa, and the khabr becomes khabru laysa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjectives for Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/adjectives-for-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 17:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/adjectives-for-allah/</guid>
      <description>Allah says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
الْحَمْدُ للّهِ رَبِّ الْعَالَمِينَ الرَّحْمـنِ الرَّحِيمِ
مَالِكِ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ  You might ask, why do rabb, Ar-Rahmaan, Ar-Raheem, and Maalik all have kasra on them? Why not dumma (the default), or fatha?
The answer is that, wallahu &amp;#8216;alim, they are na&amp;#8217;at (adjactives) for Allah&amp;#8211;words that describe His greatness.
For example, Ar-Rahmaan means &amp;#8220;the source of mercy&amp;#8221; (that&amp;#8217;s why, scholars say, you cannot name your son Rahman).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadhaa Kitaabun vs. Haadhal Kitaabu</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/hadhaa-kitaabun-vs-haadhal-kitaabu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 02:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/hadhaa-kitaabun-vs-haadhal-kitaabu/</guid>
      <description>One question that plagues many new students of the Arabic language is the difference between hadhaa kitaabun and hadhaal kitaabu &amp;#8230;
The difference is best demonstrated by example: hadhaa kitaabun kabiyrun means &amp;#8220;this is a big book,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hadhaal kitaabul kabiyru&amp;#8221; means &amp;#8220;this big book &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
Get the difference? The first (hadhaa kitaabun) is talking about any book. &amp;#8220;This is a book.&amp;#8221; Nothing special. The second&amp;#8211;hadhaal kitaabu&amp;#8211;is talking about a specific book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Colours</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/arabic-colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 23:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/arabic-colours/</guid>
      <description>For those of you studying al-lugatul arabiyyah, inshallah here is an easy visual way to learn six basic colours: red, blue, green, yellow, black, and white. (You can set it as your computer desktop, so every time you pop onto your computer, instant practice!)
The top colour is the mascline form, and the bottom colour is the feminine form. (Read more about Arabic word gender here.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe and Beautify Your Writing</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/observe-and-beautify-your-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/observe-and-beautify-your-writing/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who regularly write Arabic (and, incidentally, you can generalize this to any language inshallah), you might look at your writing and say, &amp;#8220;man, that is ugggggleeeeeee!&amp;#8221;
So how do you go about beautifying it? The key here is that you can recognize nice Arabic writing when you see it&amp;#8211;and I don&amp;#8217;t mean calligraphy.
The solution is surprisingly simple. Grab a mushaf (or, if you have them, one of the three Medinah University Arabic books), Apply your observational skills, and you can easily inshallah detect a few clues on how to improve (or even how to write them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inanimate Object Plurals</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/inanimate-object-plurals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 10:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/inanimate-object-plurals/</guid>
      <description>In Arabic, masculine plurals generally follow a couple of different patterns. Sometimes they acquire a waw-noon at the end (eg. muslim becomes muslimuwna)&amp;#8211;these are called &amp;#8220;sound plurals&amp;#8221; (because the original word is still intact). Some acquire letters inside their form (eg. qalam becomes aqlaam)&amp;#8211;these are called &amp;#8220;broken plurals&amp;#8221;.
Feminine words, Allahu &amp;#8216;alim, they also have sound and broken forms. One example of a sound feminine plural is muslimaat (plural of muslimah).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Du’a Dissected</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/death-dua-dissected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 13:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/death-dua-dissected/</guid>
      <description>When someone dies, we say &amp;#8220;inna lillahi wa inna ilayhi rajioon.&amp;#8221; It means, roughly translated, &amp;#8220;We belong to Allah and to Him we return.&amp;#8221;
Inshallah here, we&amp;#8217;ll do a brief (grammatical) dissection of the phrase, so you can understand the words better (and not mix them up / mispronounce them). If you hover your mouse over underlined words, you&amp;#8217;ll see the Arabic inshallah.
Inna: Inna is really inna-na. The first part is &amp;#8220;very&amp;#8221;, the last part is &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;but Arabs like to simplify, so they just write it as inna (with only two noons).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Your Arabic</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/accelerate-your-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/accelerate-your-arabic/</guid>
      <description>Want to learn Arabic&amp;#8211;or for that matter, any language&amp;#8211;quickly? Transcend beyond what you learn in class? Fly past your peers in terms of knowledge and understanding? Want to achieve all this without spending hours of time or hundreds of dollars?
Well, the solution is here&amp;#8211;and it&amp;#8217;s already available to you! All you need is a pen, some paper, and a mushaf (copy of the Qur&amp;#8217;an)&amp;#8211;and, most importantly, your brain!
Read  Read and recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ArabicGems</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabicgems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 15:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabicgems/</guid>
      <description>For those who have a little bit of understanding about the Arabic language, or wish to deepen their understanding, you may wish to venture into the ArabicGems blog.
This blog covers different gems gleaned from the Qur&amp;#8217;an based on the Arabic language. Subhanallah, it really helps you realize the miraculous nature of the Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8211;how every phrase or even word articulates waves of meaning, and how translations don&amp;#8217;t even begin to convey everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number and Counted / ‘Adad and Ma’duwd</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/number-and-counted-adad-and-maduwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/number-and-counted-adad-and-maduwd/</guid>
      <description>Arabic has specific grammar rules for &amp;#8216;Aadad and Ma&amp;#8217;duwd&amp;#8211;the number and the counted.
Note: These rules apply for numbers from three to ten. One and two are special-they count as adjectives, not numbers, because the form of the word implies the number.
In English, we say &amp;#8220;three cars&amp;#8221;. Three is the number (&amp;#8216;adad), and cars is the counted (ma&amp;#8217;duwd).
What are the grammatical rules of &amp;#8216;adad and ma&amp;#8217;duwd?
Similar to time modifiers, &amp;#8216;adad and ma&amp;#8217;duwd work like possessive case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Modifiers / Duruwf Zamaan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/time-modifiers-duruwf-zamaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 01:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/time-modifiers-duruwf-zamaan/</guid>
      <description>The Arabic language contains &amp;#8220;time modifiers&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;words like &amp;#8220;before&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;after&amp;#8221;. In Arabic, these are called Duruwf Zamaan, and grammatically, they act like the possessive case.
While there are tons of these in Arabic, there are two you run into pretty often in the Qur&amp;#8217;an and ahadith: ba&amp;#8217;da (after) and qabla (before).
Grammatically, the modifier comes before the thing it modifies&amp;#8211;the same as in English. And since the modifier acts like the possessor in the possessive case, the modified receives kasra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possessive Case / Mudaf &amp; Mudaf Ilayh</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/possessive-case-mudaf-mudaf-ilayh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 18:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/possessive-case-mudaf-mudaf-ilayh/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#8217;re already familiar with possessive case in English&amp;#8211;when we show ownership of something. For example, we might say, &amp;#8220;this is Amer&amp;#8217;s book&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;this is the book of Amer.&amp;#8221;
The possessive case has two elements:
 The possessor, i.e. the one who owns the thing. In this case, Amer. The possessed, i.e. the thing being owned. In this example, the book.  The possessive case in Arabic is the same. The possessed is called the mudaf, the possessor the mudaf ilayh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Key to Learning Arabic</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-learning-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 11:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-learning-arabic/</guid>
      <description>Arabic is an integral part of Islam. After all, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) revealed the Qur&amp;#8217;an in Arabic, and all the ahadeeth of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), not to mention the key works of early scholars, all are in Arabic.
Many of us embark down the path to learn Arabic. But what elements do you need to succeed&amp;#8211;aside from patience, persistence, practise, and a pure intention to seek only the pleasure of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emphasis in the Qur’an</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emphasis-in-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 15:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emphasis-in-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>Why is emphasis important? It proves truthfulness. For example, if you says &amp;#8220;Khalid stopped by today&amp;#8221; and your friend says &amp;#8220;Khalid didn&amp;#8217;t stop by today,&amp;#8221; and you say &amp;#8220;I swear by Allah that he stopped by today,&amp;#8221; that proves your truthfulness.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) doesn&amp;#8217;t need any emphasis&amp;#8211;what He says is always true! Yet He still emphasizes. Whenever He emphasizes something, pay close attention, and realize that what He says immediately afterward is very important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madd: Fard and Mustahab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madd-fard-and-mustahab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 16:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madd-fard-and-mustahab/</guid>
      <description>Madd (pronounced like &amp;#8220;mud&amp;#8221;), literally means &amp;#8220;extension&amp;#8221;. In recitation of the Qur&amp;#8217;an (tajweed), madd is when you extend and stretch a vowel sound (aah, ooh, etc.).
There are two types of madd: fard (obligatory: you have to recite it) and mustahab (recommended: you should recite it). The general rule is that a madd inside a word is fard, while a madd that connects two words is mustahab.
For example, in Surah Baqarah, Allah says:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huruwful Jarr: Prepositions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/huruwful-jarr-prepositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2006 22:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/huruwful-jarr-prepositions/</guid>
      <description>In English, we have words like &amp;#8220;from&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;to&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;with&amp;#8221;, etc. These are called prepositions. They exist in Arabic, too&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;huruful jaar&amp;#8221; (حُرُوقُ الجَرّ).
Huruwful jarr modify the words immediately after them, which are called &amp;#8220;majruwr&amp;#8221; (مَجرُور).
In Arabic Grammar, majurwr words always take kasra (either single or double). (The one exception is feminine names, which take fatha.)
So for example, if we have a book (kitaabun), then we add the preposition with (bi), it becomes &amp;#8220;bi kitaabin&amp;#8221; (بِ كِتَابٍ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Default Dumma and Definitivity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/default-dumma-and-definitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2006 15:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/default-dumma-and-definitivity/</guid>
      <description>In Arabic grammar, the default harakaat that goes on all words is dumma (ُ or ٌ, the &amp;#8220;oo&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;oon&amp;#8221; sound). When you don&amp;#8217;t know the vowel, apply dumma. Other harakaat are for other cases&amp;#8211;for example, posessive case takes kasra (ِ or ٍ, the &amp;#8220;ee&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;een&amp;#8221; sound).
Harakaat are two types&amp;#8211;short (aa, ee, and oo) and long (aan, een, and oon).
The second point to remember is definitivity. A definitive object means a specific object, not just any old object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Word Gender</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabic-word-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2006 23:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabic-word-gender/</guid>
      <description>Masculine and Feminine  In Arabic, all words are one of two genders: masculine, or feminine. There is no &amp;#8220;it&amp;#8221;, no third, gender-neutral gender like English has.
The main thing to remember is that when you don&amp;#8217;t know the gender, the default is the masculine gender. You also use the masculine gender for mixed groups (eg. if you&amp;#8217;re talking to a group of men and women).
The main sign of a word being feminine (remember, if you don&amp;#8217;t know, the default is masculine) is a specific form of the letter ta, called ta-marbuta (التَّأ المَربُوطَة), or &amp;#8220;tied-up ta&amp;#8221;, which looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Grammar: It’s All in the Vowels</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabic-grammar-its-all-in-the-vowels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2006 02:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/arabic-grammar-its-all-in-the-vowels/</guid>
      <description>Arabic Grammar consists almost entirely of putting harakaat on letters.
Arabic writing is typically written without the harakaat. How is it possible to read? One must learn slowly, piece by piece, and read with understanding. Arabic is not like English&amp;#8211;you have to actively read and consciously think while you read about what it means. (At least, when you start out.)
Why are harakaat important? Harakaat determine the meaning of words and sentences entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When is a Ya a Ya?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-is-a-ya-a-ya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2006 01:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-is-a-ya-a-ya/</guid>
      <description>In Arabic, there is the letter Ya: ي. It is pronounced similar to the letter Y in English.
However, there&amp;#8217;s also another type of ya&amp;#8211;the ya without dots, which looks like this: ى. As for that ya, sometimes pronounced as a ya, and sometimes, as an alif (ا).
For example, the word على (ayn-lam-ya) can be read as &amp;#8216;ala (on top: عَلَى) or as &amp;#8216;Ali (as in the name: عَلِي). So how do you know when to pronounce it as a ya, and when to pronounce it as an alif?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qalqala: Mnemonic and Mistakes</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/qalqala-mnemonic-and-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2006 01:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/qalqala-mnemonic-and-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>Mnemonic: Something used to help you remember.
Qalqala is best described as an &amp;#8220;echo noise&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;bouncing noise&amp;#8221;. There are five qalqala letters. If any of them appears with a sukoon on top, you perform qalqala. (Prime example, if you have no idea what qalqala is: the end of the last word of every verse in Surah Ikhlass.)
Qalqala letters: qaff (ق), ba (ب), taw (ط), jeem (ج), and dal (د).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Pronounciation in Surah Fatiha</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-pronounciation-in-surah-faitha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 03:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-pronounciation-in-surah-faitha/</guid>
      <description>Surah Fatiha contains almost all the Arabic letters that the English language lacks: &amp;#8216;Ayn (ع), Saad (ص), Daad (ض), Taw (ط), Qaf (ق), and 7a (ح). Once you learn to pronounce these letters correctly, you practice them 17 times a day, every day, in every state of mind. Bi ithnillah, once you learn them, practice, and you will master them quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tajweed Review Website</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tajweed-review-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 03:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tajweed-review-website/</guid>
      <description>If you know your tajweed (Qur&amp;#8217;anic rules of beautifying recitation) but feel a bit rusty or need to review them, this website explains it very well. The website helps more if you already know tajweed but need a refresher. It&amp;#8217;s very difficult to learn tajweed without a real, human teacher.
May Allah accept our reading of the Qur&amp;#8217;an as &amp;#8216;ibadah. Ameen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Arabic from the Qur’an</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-arabic-from-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 01:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/learn-arabic-from-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>One way to learn Arabic is to memorize the Qur&amp;#8217;an with a word-by-word translation.
emuslim.com provides such a tool. Once you memorize a few (approximately 20-30) verses, you&amp;#8217;ll find that other verses become decipherable, and familiar words leap at you everywhere you turn.
I recommend this method to everyone&amp;#8211;for some, it&amp;#8217;s the only way to memorize Qur&amp;#8217;an.
Related Links: emuslim English word-for-word translation </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Arabic Language</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-in-arabic-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 01:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-in-arabic-language/</guid>
      <description>Islamic-Knowledge.com&amp;#8217;s Lessons in Arabic Language website provides an online self-paced course for people to learn Arabic, in Arabic. It follows the famous three Medina Arabic books page by page, and displays translations and transliterations for every word used.
Unlike other online courses, this course teaches entirely in Arabic (minus the transliteration), similar to the way they teach Arabic at Al-Medina university. Although more difficult to learn than an English course, it forces the reader to think in Arabic, an advantage not offered by many other courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MadinahArabic.com: Open the Portal to Learning Arabic</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madinaharabiccom-open-the-portal-to-learning-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2006 04:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/madinaharabiccom-open-the-portal-to-learning-arabic/</guid>
      <description>MadinahArabic.com teaches Arabic in the style of the Madinah Book Series, used to teach Arabic at Al-Medina university. The series style caters to English-speakers. The website follows a similar teaching paradigm.
The course walks you through the process step by step. They seperate the material into two sections: Arabic Reading Course, which teaches letters, and Arabic Language Course, which teaches grammar and vocabulary.
The course offers a self-paced and comprehensive approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>