<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seeking Knowledge on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/seeking-knowledge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seeking Knowledge on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 16:01:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/seeking-knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Legacy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-lost-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 16:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-lost-legacy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
We live in an era where knowledge is abundant and is available at our finger tips in variety of formats (audio, video, ebooks&amp;#8230;) and on variety of devices and platforms (tablets, smartphones, laptops&amp;#8230;.). However, we lack the enthusiasm, passion, dedication and commitment to seeking knowledge. Here are few of the inspiring stories of past to rekindle that spark.
 Imam Zafar said &amp;#8220;We used to sit down and take our spots for the circle of Imam Ali Madini after the Asar prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacons of Light</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post from I Got it Covered, a blog about hijab, Islam, and life. You can find the original article here.
In the time of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab, radiAllahu anhu, the second Khalifah, it was mandatory upon all the young girls to learn Surat an-Noor.
From the beauty of this Surah is that it begins with, &amp;#8220;[This is] a surah which We have sent down and made [that within it] obligatory and revealed therein verses of clear evidence that you might remember&amp;#8221; [Surat an-Noor: 1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Statement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/making-a-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 22:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/making-a-statement/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is the third post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
From the opening ceremonies, to the first move of world leaders, people like to send a message. The intense revelation of the Qur’an is no different. The timing, style and content, sends a message to the final Prophet (saw) and to all of humanity.
Allah (swt) starts the revelation commanding the Prophet to read &amp;#8220;Recite in the name of your Lord who created.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>