<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Day of Judgment on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/day-of-judgment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Day of Judgment on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 22:59:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/day-of-judgment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Nazi’at, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/tafseer-surah-naziat-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 22:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/tafseer-surah-naziat-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/footsteps-snow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Will we be returned exactly in our footsteps?&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1648&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is post #42 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, insha&amp;#8217;Allah we will take a whirlwind tour of the first third or so of Surah Naazi&amp;#8217;aat, a great and powerful surah of the Qur&amp;#8217;an. Then insha&amp;#8217;Allah we will go back and dive into more details (particularly in the Arabic side of things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالنَّازِعَاتِ غَرْقًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالنَّاشِطَاتِ نَشْطًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالسَّابِحَاتِ سَبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالسَّابِقَاتِ سَبْقًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُدَبِّرَاتِ أَمْرًا&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By those [angels] who extract with violence, and [by] those who remove with ease, and [by] those who glide [as if] swimming, and those who race each other in a race, and those who arrange [each] matter, &amp;#8230; [Surah Nazi&amp;#8217;at, verses 1-5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ayaat describe attributes of angels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ripping Out:&lt;/strong&gt; Gharq (غَرْق) means to rip out, to yank out, to extract harshly. If you had a tree and you uprooted it, roots and all, that would be gharq. This refers to the angels who remove the souls of the corrupt and the evil-doers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gently Pulling:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse two contrasts verse one by mentioning nasht (نَشْط), which is like a gentle pulling. This refers to the angels that remove the souls of the righteous believers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swimming:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse three refers to angels who &lt;em&gt;swim through the air&lt;/em&gt;; they are described as swimming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Racing:&lt;/strong&gt; Verse four refers to angels who are racing; racing the souls of the righteous to Jannah.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Al-Mudabiraat:&lt;/strong&gt; Al-Mudabiraat are those angelswho settle the affairs of deen and dunya, in the dunya. They take care of floods, earthquakes, and other natural disasters, among other things. Their name, al-mudabiraat, also implies that they are thorough planners and executers of those plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are &lt;em&gt;aqsaam&lt;/em&gt; (oaths), which is typical in Mecci surahs. What is Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) swearing to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Naba’, Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-naba-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 18:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-naba-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is post #40 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In the previous post, we discussed the first 16 verses of Surah Naba&amp;#8217;. The remaining 24 verses discuss the Day of Judgment, Paradise, and Hellfire; you should read them to extract the details. Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;re going to touch on a few points that are interesting.
First, a recap&amp;#8211;verse 16 talked about (a continuing discussion of) some of the blessings of Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) in the dunya on the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Ghashiyah: Heaven and Hell</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-ghashiyah-heaven-and-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 17:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/tafseer-surah-ghashiyah-heaven-and-hell/</guid>
      <description>This is post #38 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
Allah (&amp;#8216;azza wa jal) says in Surah Al-Ghaashiyah:
 هَلْ أَتَاكَ حَدِيثُ الْغَاشِيَةِ
 Translation: Has there reached you the report of the Overwhelming [event]? [Surah Ghashiya, verse 1]
The surah starts with a question, to make you think. The companions would say: Allahu wa rasuluhu a&amp;#8217;lam (know better), out of humbleness, even know they had an answer in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Qaari’ah: The Striking Calamity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qaariah-the-striking-calamity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 19:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qaariah-the-striking-calamity/</guid>
      <description>This is post #30 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
Allah says, in Surah Qaari&amp;#8217;ah:
 الْقَارِعَةُ
مَا الْقَارِعَةُ
وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الْقَارِعَةُ
 Translation: The Striking Calamity &amp;#8211; What is the Striking Calamity? And what can make you know what is the Striking Calamity? [Surah Qaariah, verses 1-3]
As we mentioned, the phrase in verse three&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;wa maa adaraaka maa &amp;#8230;,&amp;#8221; is a phrase that means that, you cannot understand this thing&amp;#8211;Al-Qaari&amp;#8217;ah, the striking calamity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do YOU Encourage Good?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/do-you-encourage-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 19:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/do-you-encourage-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #18 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series). Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;ll be kicking up the post frequency to three times a week in order to finish before Ramadan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يُكَذِّبُ بِالدِّينِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَذَلِكَ الَّذِي يَدُعُّ الْيَتِيمَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا يَحُضُّ عَلَى طَعَامِ الْمِسْكِينِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Have you seen the one who denies the Repayment? For that is the one who drives away the orphan, and does not encourage the feeding of the poor. [Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, verses 1-3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the connection here&amp;#8211;verse one, the one who denies Ad-Deen, the Day of Repayment. And verse two and three? He drives away orphans, He doesn&amp;#8217;t encourage feeding of the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not that he &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;#8217;t feed&lt;/em&gt; the poor. It&amp;#8217;s that he &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;#8217;t encourange&lt;/em&gt; feeding the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Explanation of Surah Takweer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-explanation-of-surah-takweer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 18:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-explanation-of-surah-takweer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #17 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/sun-in-space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1177&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  When the sun is &lt;em&gt;kuwwirat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re going to digress a bit and jump back to Surah Takweer. This post is based on Shaykh Nouman Khan&amp;#8217;s tafseer, which heavily emphasizes the Arabic language. I hope you will find, as I found it, as a glimpse of a previously-unseen world, a depth of knowledge that just drips from the Arabic language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in surah Takweer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;إِذَا الشَّمْسُ كُوِّرَتْ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; When the sun is &lt;em&gt;kuwwirat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230; [verse 1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of gems that we learn even from this first ayah:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idhaa + Past-Tense:&lt;/strong&gt; Idhaa is an indicator of future-tense &amp;#8220;when (something will happen).&amp;#8221; Yet, kuwwirat is past-tense; why? This combination means &lt;strong&gt;something is so certain, it&amp;#8217;s like past-tense.&lt;/strong&gt; So Allah is saying &amp;#8220;when this happens,&amp;#8221; yet it&amp;#8217;s certain that it WILL happen; as certain as the past is past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nominal Sentence:&lt;/strong&gt; The default in Arabic is to put the verb first&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;kuwwirat ash-shamsu.&amp;#8221; To reverse this into &amp;#8220;ash-shamsu kuwwirat,&amp;#8221; shows emphasis, and makes it a tougher, stronger sentence. This hints at the audience&amp;#8211;Mushrikeen in Mecca, the worst and most obstinate of them, who are listening to this revelation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passive Voice:&lt;/strong&gt; Allah could have said, &amp;#8220;When I wrap up the sun,&amp;#8221; but He didn&amp;#8217;t. Why? If you&amp;#8217;re biased against someone (say a political party), &lt;em&gt;no matter what they say&lt;/em&gt;, even before they open their mouth, you say, &amp;#8220;psshh.&amp;#8221; But here, passive-voice highlights the maf&amp;#8217;ool, the recipient of the action&amp;#8211;the sun, the stars&amp;#8211;instead of the doer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the meaning of kuwwirat, kawwara means to wrap something around something; it&amp;#8217;s used in the context of a turban, something long, that&amp;#8217;s wrapped around your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah is applying the same meaning here&amp;#8211;that the light of the sun, something that&amp;#8217;s long, will be kuwwirat, wrapped up. Wrapped up meaning, something will cover it, and it will no longer be visible; and it will be wrapped slowly, part by part disappearing&amp;#8211;the same way that Allah described the day as wrapping around the night and the night wrapping around the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something scary&amp;#8211;that you see the sun wrapped up, and losing its light. But &lt;em&gt;there&amp;#8217;s more&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the War-Horses Pant …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/when-the-war-horses-pant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 16:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/when-the-war-horses-pant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #15 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/horse-saddle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1159&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah begins Surah Aadiyaat by saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالْعَادِيَاتِ ضَبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُورِيَاتِ قَدْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُغِيرَاتِ صُبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَأَثَرْنَ بِهِ نَقْعًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَوَسَطْنَ بِهِ جَمْعًا&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By the &amp;#8216;aadiyaat, when they pant, and the muwriyraat striking (when their hoves strike the ground and make sparks), and the mughiyraat, at dawn (when they raid), stirring up thereby [clouds of] dust, arriving thereby in the center collectively, &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a qasam (oath), a big oath that spans five ayaat. I&amp;#8217;m going to dive into word-for-word translation, because no translation can do justice (without paragraphs of brackets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;Aadiyaat (عَادِيَات) are horses (plural: sound feminine plural, in fact). Not those horses you see Canadian Mounties riding; but real, true, WAR horses. If you&amp;#8217;ve ever seen war-horses (send us a picture!), they have a special, particular intensity to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dabhaa (ضَبْحًا) means to pant. Pant meaning, if you&amp;#8217;ve ever run in a 100-meter race, or tried to run until you&amp;#8217;re tired, and you start breathing heavily through your mouth&amp;#8211;that&amp;#8217;s panting. Why are the &amp;#8216;aadiyaat panting? Because they are &lt;em&gt;charging&lt;/em&gt; into battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll see lots of war concepts here. The Arabs at the time of the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) knew these things very, very well; and when Allah testifies, these things he testifies by&amp;#8211;nobody would deny them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muwriyaat (مُورِيَات) are also war-horses&amp;#8211;the ones that strike. Strike meaning, when they run, their hooves strike up sparks on the ground. I definitely don&amp;#8217;t encourage watching movies, so if you&amp;#8217;ve ever read seerah stories, or perhaps Lord of the Rings, or similar books, you might find these kinds of concepts in their battles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mughiyraat (مُغِيرَات) are the raiding horses. In the time of the Prophet, they would have raids; you would see a whole army of horses and riders sweeping into a city, and they&amp;#8217;d kill everybody and destroy it. Mughiyraat are those raiding horses that they rode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reality of Honour and Life</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-reality-of-honour-and-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 16:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-reality-of-honour-and-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/unpacked-suitcase.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1112&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;font-size: 80%; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  What have you packed for the Hereafter?
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is our 11th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah Fajr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;فَأَمَّا الْإِنسَانُ إِذَا مَا ابْتَلَاهُ رَبُّهُ فَأَكْرَمَهُ وَنَعَّمَهُ فَيَقُولُ رَبِّي أَكْرَمَنِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَأَمَّا إِذَا مَا ابْتَلَاهُ فَقَدَرَ عَلَيْهِ رِزْقَهُ فَيَقُولُ رَبِّي أَهَانَنِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; And as for man, when his Lord tries him and [thus] is generous to him and favors him, he says, &amp;#8220;My Lord has honored me.&amp;#8221; But when He tries him and restricts his provision, he says, &amp;#8220;My Lord has humiliated me.&amp;#8221; [Surah Fajr, verses 15-16]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll notice here, Allah is commenting on the mentality of the human race. When Allah gives &amp;#8230; the human being says: &amp;#8220;My Lord has honoured me.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;#8217;s all about wealth &amp;#8230; money &amp;#8230; dunya. This is the metric we use. You see the president of a country? You&amp;#8217;re very respectful. If the same president was a homeless bum asking you for change? You wouldn&amp;#8217;t even look at him. We equate money with respect and honour &amp;#8230; as Allah points out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the flip side? When Allah constrains the rizq, the human being says: &amp;#8220;My lord has humiliated me.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Only …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Suratul Anbiya:
لَوْ يَعْلَمُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا حِينَ لَا يَكُفُّونَ عَن وُجُوهِهِمُ النَّارَ وَلَا عَن ظُهُورِهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يُنصَرُونَ  Translation: If only those who disbelieved knew when they will not be able to ward off the Fire from their faces, nor from their backs; and they will not be helped. [Surah Suratul Anbiya, verse 39]
The word for ward off is &amp;#8220;yakuffoona&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;يَكُفُّونَ&amp;#8221; and this is from the root word &amp;#8220;ka-fa-fa&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;kaff&amp;#8221; which means palm/hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>