<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orphans on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/orphans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orphans on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 18:24:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/orphans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Duhaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 18:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is our 12th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/breakfast-on-bed.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1118&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  Islam is about social service and shukr (thankfulness).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insha&amp;#8217;Allah in this post, we&amp;#8217;re going to discuss three points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The close relationship between Allah and His prophet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A glimpse of Paradise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A core theme of social services in Islam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) received revelation prior to Surah Duhaa. Then for a while, nothing. Umm Jameelah, the wife of Abu Lahab, came to him and said: &amp;#8220;I hope your shaytaan has finally left you.&amp;#8221; Because the Arabs used to say, if someone was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good at something, that they had a shaytaan helping them. (No doubt like some of the musicians today.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still nothing came. The people began to talk &amp;#8230; and they said, maybe his Lord has left him. Maybe He has abandoned him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so Allah revealed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Duhaa, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالضُّحَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَى&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By duhaa (the morning brightness after Fajr), and [by] the night when it covers with darkness, your Lord has not taken leave of you, [O Muúammad], nor has He detested [you].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[This hadith is found in Bukhari and Muslim, and is quoted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://tafsir.com/default.asp?sid=93&amp;amp;tid=58628&#34;&gt;Tafseer ibn Katheer&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows us two things: first, that the people &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; when revelation came; that it was a big deal, and everybody knew about it. And second, &lt;span class=&#34;gem&#34;&gt;the immense love of Allah for His prophet.&lt;/span&gt; How close their relationship&amp;#8211;that even something as small as this stress, Allah revealed verses on behalf of the prophet, to reassure him. Subhanallah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, Allah &lt;em&gt;swears&lt;/em&gt; by duhaa&amp;#8211;by the brightness of the day right after the sun has come up&amp;#8211;and by the night, as it covers up the day with darkness. (This shows the greatness of these creations&amp;#8211;that Allah swears by them. Who would deny these things? Nobody!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>