<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ibadah on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/ibadah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ibadah on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/ibadah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Do List After Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Wikipedia
Ramadan ended. (May Allah accept all our prayer, fasting, du&amp;#8217;a, and good deeds during this blessed month &amp;#8212; ameen!) How should we, as Muslims, act now?
We graduated from the school of Ramadan; can life simply return to normal?
Our scholars mention a few points about this:
 Allah says, in surah Baqarah, that Ramadan was prescribed on us in the hope that we gain taqwa. Did we achieve that goal of the school of Ramadan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Boy – Ya Ghulam!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/o-boy-ya-ghulam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 22:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/o-boy-ya-ghulam/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives.
Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Click here to show evidences/reference links
Sunnah&amp;#8217;s of Eating:
 Pronounce the Tasmiya (Bismilla) [Bukhari :: Book 7 :: Volume 65 :: Hadith 288]   If you forget to say Bismillah, before starting, say this supplication. [At-Tirmidhee 5/506]   Eat with the right hand   Eat from what is infront of you   If some food drops, clean it and then eat it [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5044]   Eat with three fingers [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5040]   Eat together [Dawud :: Book 27 : Hadith 3755]   Not finding faults in food [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5121]   After Eating:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 5</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 20:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Making Dua:
 Raise your hands Glorify and praise Allah, in the beginning and at the end Send salutations on Prophet (May Allah Peace and Blessing be on him) in the beginning and at the end Cry while making dua  Adhaan:
 Respond to it (see the first dua here) Make salutation on the prophet (May Allah Peace and Blessing be on him) Make dua (last one on this page)  Breakfast:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcdonald, KFC, Moon Sighting…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 23:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</guid>
      <description>Muslims, living in the Muslim Countries, generally tend to have limited exposure to Fiqh and its rulings. There is usually one dominant madhab and that&amp;#8217;s all people know about. Rarely, if ever, people are exposed to other madahibs. However, the situation for many of us living in west, like Canada, is quite different.
Because of the diversity of muslims, from various countries, cultures and backgrounds, we are exposed to many madhabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 15:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Continuing in the ten ways to achieve the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, here are the last five points as per ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallauh:
 Sixth, observing Allaah’s kindness, goodness and bounties, both hidden and open.
 It is to be aware of the vast amounts of Mercy Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala has engulfed His slaves with. It is to recognize and accept the blessings of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala and to show thanks for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanking Allah in times of a Calamity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 15:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Umer radhiAllah anhu used to say:
 &amp;#8220;If Allah strikes me with calamity I will thank Allah for four things: 1) that the test was not in my deen 2) the calamity could have been worse 3) it is an expiation for my sins 4) any loss after losing the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam is nothing”
 The greatest man that lived after the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam and Abu Bakr as-Siddiq radhiAllah anhu, Umer ibn al-Khattab radhiAllah anhu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are on camera!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 19:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</guid>
      <description>Imagine this. You are speeding on the road. The police officer catches you, pulls you over and gives you a speeding ticket. What would your reaction be, next time you are driving especially driving through the same road. You would naturally slow down! Or you are stealing from your prayer (i.e. racing through it), you glance over and it seems like your friends might be looking at you. Your reaction&amp;#8230;. In these and in countless other situations, we refrain from doing bad because we fear that we might be caught or someone might be looking at us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 03:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Eid Mubarak! As the sahaba would tell each other: May Allah accept our good deeds and your good deeds (from Ramadan). Ameen!
Ramadan is still fresh in your mind; the long days of fasting, the pain in your legs and back from taraweeh, and most of all, that biting regret that you didn&amp;#8217;t do enough.
Would you like to make the next Ramadan even better? With only five minutes worth of effort?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan for the Last 10 Nights of Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/plan-for-the-last-10-nights-of-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 20:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/plan-for-the-last-10-nights-of-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is coming to a close. Like the last half-kilometer of a 10km race, the finish-line is in sight. This is the time to pull out all the stops and to sprint, flat-out. This is the time when Laylatul-Qadar, the night where deeds are multiplied by more than one thousand, hides.
Are you ready for it?
Maybe you felt like Ramadan breezed by. Maybe you felt like you didn&amp;#8217;t do enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Resource Bonanza!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#8217;s better than a chest of gold and jewels? A post full of Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah!  Bismillah.
This is a guest post by an author who compiled a wide number of resources related to fasting, reciting Qur&amp;#8217;an, and sincerity of intention. This is a great resource of ahadith and ayaat related to fasting. May Allah grant them a great reward (ameen!) and forgive any mistakes I have made in re-formatting it and linking all the sources to their citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Project Unveiled: Salah Support</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 16:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we&amp;#8217;ve been working in the background for a while to launch a new project. Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who helped out, may Allah keep giving you reward for it insha&amp;#8217;Allah long after your bones are dust&amp;#8211;allahumma ameen!
First, check yourself, and fill out the poll below:
[poll id=&amp;#8221;3&amp;#8243;]
If you haven&amp;#8217;t guessed, our new project is: Salah Support, a forum where you can find resources on salah&amp;#8211;everything from videos on how to pray, to ebooks on khushoo&amp;#8217;, to creative alarms for Qiaaym-ul-Layl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Ramadan Opinion Do I Pick?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 21:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</guid>
      <description>Sight the moon, and if you cannot, then count the days &amp;#8230;  Ramadan is coming, alhamdulillah. Ramadan, a time when all the shayateen are chained up, as the Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said:
 Narrated Abu Huraira (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu): Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said, &amp;#8220;When the month of Ramadan starts, the gates of the heaven are opened and the gates of Hell are closed and the devils are chained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Shields of Protection From Supernatural Forces</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/3-shields-of-protection-from-supernatural-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/3-shields-of-protection-from-supernatural-forces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is post #22 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/forest-night-light.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;a blinding light emitting from a forest at night&#34; title=&#34;a blinding light emitting from a forest at night&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1233&#34; /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;The protection of Allah is easily earned and very, very powerful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muslims love talking about Jinns and black magic. Yet, when it comes to inoculating themselves from supernatural forces, Muslims are often either ignorantly doing &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of what they need to do, or proverbially standing on the interstate highway, woefully oblivious of thousands of cars speeding by at near-miss distances. And many of us, or people we know, personally &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet even the newest Muslim is often quickly equipped with powerful shields of protection against these forces. What are they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say: O You Kafiroon …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 20:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is post #20 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Kafiroon, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;قُلْ يَا أَيُّهَا الْكَافِرُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَا أَعْبُدُ مَا تَعْبُدُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنَا عَابِدٌ مَّا عَبَدتُّمْ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَكُمْ دِينُكُمْ وَلِيَ دِينِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Say, &amp;#8220;O disbelievers, I do not worship what you worship. Nor are you worshippers of what I worship. Nor will I be a worshipper of what you worship. Nor will you be worshippers of what I worship. For you is your religion, and for me is my religion.&amp;#8221; [Surah Kafiroon]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mushrikeen (polytheists) of Mecca tried many, many different techniques to get the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) to stop spreading Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this ayah was revealed, they decided to make a pact with him. They said, &amp;#8220;Look, how about this&amp;#8211;you worship our gods for one year, and we&amp;#8217;ll worship your God for one year.&amp;#8221; And to sweeten the deal: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ll go first.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they applied the Broken Record technique. Whenever the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) would try to speak to them about Islam, they would only repeat this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he, salallahu alayhi wa sallam, refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who are wondering why&amp;#8211;although it seems on the surface like a fair trade, it&amp;#8217;s not. Allah &lt;strong&gt;does not forgive shirk&lt;/strong&gt;, worshipping other than him; not even a single sujood, or a single du&amp;#8217;a, none of it is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So clearly, this is not a contract the Messenger of Allah could engage with. So he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he &lt;em&gt;refused&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the Mushrikeen said, &amp;#8220;ok, how about this&amp;#8211;just &lt;em&gt;speak highly&lt;/em&gt; of our gods, and we&amp;#8217;ll do the same for you.&amp;#8221; A smaller compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whenever people approached them, they would say, &amp;#8220;Well, we&amp;#8217;re trying to compromise (like &lt;em&gt;we&amp;#8217;re&lt;/em&gt; the good ones in this deal&amp;#8211;even though we kill our daughters and murder on whims and &amp;#8230;), but he&amp;#8217;s not agreeing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) went to the ka&amp;#8217;bah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/kabah-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; title=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1206&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mushrikeen were there. And in front of &lt;strong&gt;everybody&lt;/strong&gt; he said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Who Show Off in Their Salah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is post #19 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, Allah says:
 فَوَيْلٌ لِّلْمُصَلِّينَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَن صَلَاتِهِمْ سَاهُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ يُرَاءُونَ
وَيَمْنَعُونَ الْمَاعُونَ
 Translation: So woe to those who pray; those who are heedless of their prayer, those who make show [of their deeds]; And withhold [simple] assistance (al-ma&amp;#8217;oon). [Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, verses 4-7]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Laziness and Incapability</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) used to make a du&amp;#8217;a:
 اللّهُمَّ إنِّي أعُوذُبِكَ مِن العَجزِ وَ الكَسلٍTransliteration: Allahumma inniy a&amp;#8217;oothubika min al-ajzi wal-kasli
Translation: O Allah, I seek refuge in you from incapability and laziness.  Why is this du&amp;#8217;a important? For two reasons:   Laziness is an attribute of munafiqeen. If this wasn&amp;#8217;t bad enough, being lazy leads to procrastination, which leads to its own set of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask the Readers: Questions about Salah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ask-the-readers-questions-about-salah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 15:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ask-the-readers-questions-about-salah/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who provided feedback. It seems like there&amp;#8217;s a lot of demand for this kind of thing. Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;ll see more posts like this in the future.
Bismillah.
Salah. We cannot emphasize the importance of salah&amp;#8211;the dividing line of Islam and Kufr. The first thing asked about on the Day of Judgment. The last thing the Messenger of Allah mentioned before he passed away.
Maybe you&amp;#8217;ve been Muslim a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness After Forgiveness After Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 17:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s a beautiful du&amp;#8217;a that Allah mentions near the end of Surah Baqarah:
وَاعْفُ عَنَّا وَاغْفِرْ لَنَا وَارْحَمْنَا  Translation: So do &amp;#8216;affuw on us. And forgive us. And have mercy on us. [Surah Baqarah, verse 286]
Allah mentions three things, in order:
 &amp;#8216;Affuw &amp;#8216;annaa: Affuw linguistically means to erase something; to obliterate something; to completely destroy something and leave no traces of it whatsoever. This du&amp;#8217;a is saying: make affuw of our sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 01:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</guid>
      <description>Below is a fantastic presentation on Eid, based on the sunnah. It outlines the dos and don&amp;#8217;ts of Eid. Learn it, share it, and enjoy!
Eid mubarak to you and your families, on behalf of Ilm Fruits!
SWF from: http://www.outstandingmuslim.com/Eid101/engage.html </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Qiyaam-ul-Layl Alarms</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 16:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We all know that we should pray tahajjud, aka qiyaam-ul-layl. It&amp;#8217;s well established in the deen that this is a very, very rewarding thing to do (but it&amp;#8217;s not fard, so don&amp;#8217;t sweat it if you&amp;#8217;re not doing it). Some motivational factors for this include:
 The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) used to pray Qiyaam-ul-Layl until his legs swelled. When asked why&amp;#8211;since Allah has forgiven all his past and future sins, he said: Should I not be a grateful slave?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reasons Behind Seasons</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Why did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) create seasons? All of this&amp;#8211;snow, leaves changing, hot summer days and freezing winter nights. In some countries&amp;#8211;like Canada, and the US&amp;#8211;you have places where Isha time starts around 11pm, or 12am (midnight), and Fajr starts arond 2-3am! You also have days where Isha starts at 6pm, and Fajr starts around 7am.
What can we learn from this?
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) gives this away when he narrates: &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) made the night short so you can pray, and the day short so you can fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ismul Jalaalah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Ismul Jalaalah, The Grand Name: Allah الله. This is Allah&amp;#8217;s Personal Name. His Identifying Name. This Name only belongs to Allah, no one else can have besides Allah. Allah is the Title, the Name, of the One True Ilaah. The Name of Allah, you cannot play around with: there is no plural, there is no feminine. The Name Allah appears over 3000 times in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
When we mentioned the Name &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221; linguistically, we don&amp;#8217;t say &amp;#8220;the word Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the Name Allah&amp;#8221; because it is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praying Isha While The Imam Prays Taraweeh</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 17:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s well-known in our communities, alhamdulillah, that you can pray &amp;#8216;Isha behind an imam praying Taraweeh. (Which happens if you run late, very late, indeed!) But we&amp;#8217;re just going to dive a bit into the details of how and why this is.
Note: We do not issue fatwa! For that, please consult Islam Question and Answer!
First of all, there is a difference of opinion among the scholars about whether this is permissible or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Due Reward: Surah Ikhlas – Pt.5 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-due-reward-surah-ikhlas-pt5-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-due-reward-surah-ikhlas-pt5-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
SubhanAllah! How fast Ramadan came and how fast it went. It truly saddens my heart to see this blessed month go away, to see it slipping away, to have to say good-bye. In a few days, the shayateen will be let loose and the difficulties will emerge. Ya Rabbi! Give this ummah the strength to fight the shayateen and keep us steadfast in the deen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unborn: Surah Ikhlas – Pt. 3 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
First and foremost, Ramadan Kareem! May Allah azza wa jal give us all the opportunity to take advantage of this blessed month and to make it a means of us attaining His Paradise. Ameen.
Due to Ramadan, I&amp;#8217;ve found myself to be quite busy. Nonetheless, I do apologize for not having written anything for the past few makes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones in Need: Surah Ikhlas – Pt. 2 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-ones-in-need-surah-ikhlas-pt-2-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-ones-in-need-surah-ikhlas-pt-2-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum!
Continuing in our journey of understanding the 112th chapter of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, Allah says: اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ Allah, the Self-Sufficient [Surah Ikhlas V.2]
 Recall, the greatest name of the Lord of the heavens and the earth is Allah. This is the name that He has chosen to name Himself with, and it is the grand name to which all His other Names and Attributes are attributed to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Command Like No Other: Surah Ikhlas – Pt.1 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-command-like-no-other-surah-ikhlas-pt1-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2008 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-command-like-no-other-surah-ikhlas-pt1-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Alhamdolilah. We started this initiative to bring people closer to their salat and by the grace of Allah azza wa jal the numbers are increasing and so are the results. May Allah continue to shower His Mercy into this project and make our hearts humble towards Him.
This week and inshallah for the coming weeks we will concentrate our efforts in attempting to understand the surahs we often recite in the salat (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praise of Beauty (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praise-of-beauty-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 15:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praise-of-beauty-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum, Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah.
Rifa&amp;#8217;ah ibn Rafi&amp;#8217; said: We were praying behind the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam and when he raised his head at the end of the rak&amp;#8217;ah he said:
 &amp;#8220;Allah listens to him who praises Him&amp;#8221;

A man behind him said:  &amp;#8220;O our Lord! To You belongs all praise, abundant good praise, inherently blessed&amp;#8221;   
When he finished he asked, &amp;#8220;Who was the speaker just now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varying the Supplications (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/varying-the-supplications-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 15:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/varying-the-supplications-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah wa&amp;#8217;lhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
For the most part, or at least from my personal experience, from childhood salat was always made to seem very rigid; one way of doing it, no variation, very systematic. And since we were never taught these variations, salat just ended up becoming a thoughtless set of actions, repeating the same things over and over again. However, as I grew older I realized that there is a lot of variation in salat, a lot that we can do to really build that relationship Allah throughout our salat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubhanAllah: A Pure Negation (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah was-salatu was-salam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam
Continuing in our discussion of the oft-repeated words and phrases in our salat, this week inshallah we will focus on looking at: SubhanAllah
This is another word that is very common in the Muslim&amp;#8217;s vocabulary. We all have heard the word, we all say it in our prayers daily (inshallah), yet how many of us truly understand its meaning?
Commonly this word is translated as, &amp;#8220;Glory be to Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;All Glory is to Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Praise of Perfection (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum,
There are certain words and phrases which we pronounce in our salat repeatedly, yet more than likely we do not know what they mean. This is the state of our salat these days&amp;#8230;nothing more than actions of the limbs. O Muslims! Remember faith (eman) is belief in the heart, statements upon the tongue, and actions of the limbs. All three are required for a completeness of faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Home away from Home (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-home-away-from-home-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-home-away-from-home-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>By dear brother and sisters in Islam, Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullah
In this blessed month of Ramadan, it is only beneficial to us to increase our worship of Allah azza wa jal. Surely, this month is full of blessings like no other. O Muslims! Take advantage of this month, because the reality is we don&amp;#8217;t know if we will see another one.
Our beloved Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam has said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Forgiveness (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/pure-forgiveness-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 15:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/pure-forgiveness-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters in Islam our beloved Prophet alayhi salatu wasalam has told us:
  &amp;#8220;The angels keep on asking Allah&amp;#8217;s forgiveness for anyone of you, as long as he is at his mu&amp;#8217;sallah (praying place) and does he does not pass wind. They say, &amp;#8216;O Allah! Forgive him, O Allah! be Merciful to him.&amp;#8221; [Bukhari]   Gems
   Angels are a great sign of Mercy from Allah and how beautiful it is that Allah has given every single Muslim the ability to feel the mercy just by staying in his place of prayer   How great is it that the angels ask Allah for forgiveness for you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A River of Purity (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-river-of-purity-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 15:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-river-of-purity-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet of Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam has coined an amazing analogy in regards to salat. The analogy is depicted in a conversation between the Prophet and the Companions radhiAllah anhum, in which the Prophet alayhi salatu wasalam said:
 &amp;#8220;Do you think that if there was a river by the door of one of you and he bathed in it five times a day that there would remain any dirt on him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tajweed: Different Stops</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tajweed-different-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 14:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tajweed-different-stops/</guid>
      <description>In this great month of Ramadan, people will be reciting the Qur&amp;#8217;an more, insha&amp;#8217;Allah. While we recommend everybody to get a colour-coded Arabic-text mushaaf&amp;#8211;because it makes it easy to recite with 100% perfect tajweed once you learn the rules&amp;#8211;sometimes, deciphering some of the symbols can be a bit tricky.
In this first post, we&amp;#8217;re going to insha&amp;#8217;Allah discuss different stops in the mushaf. You may have seen these stop symbols: tiny little letters (meem, qaaf+lam, jeem, saad+lam, lam+alif) written above the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local or International Sighting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 16:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</guid>
      <description>As yet another Ramadan comes, the question arises? should we follow the opinion of the local moonsighting, or the international moonsighting? Great arguments erupt, people insulting each other left and right, breaking ties, breaking families &amp;#8230;
Brothers and sisters, ya Muslims, WAKE UP!! Realize that all the opinions which are backed by the scholars are correct!
What? All of them?
Yes. all of them.
How does that work? In Islam, we have scholars (&amp;#8216;ulama), and we have people who have the knowledge and tools and responsibility to give fatwa (mujtahidoon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salat101 now on Ilmfruits!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/salat101-now-on-ilmfruits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 15:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/salat101-now-on-ilmfruits/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
In efforts to bring people closer to their salat a service was created entitled, &amp;#8220;Salat101&amp;#8243;. Alhamdolilah, by the grace of Allah azza wa jal this has been a great success and inshallah it will be now available on Ilmfruits!
Periodically, we will send out tips and tricks which inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala will aid us all in attaining ihsan in our salat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levels of Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 15:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
Truly, patience is a characteristic of the Muslim that is required on many levels:
 Patience in worshiping Allah Patience in abstaining from wrong actions Patience at times of trials  These are the three levels we should constantly be monitoring, for verily it is these levels of patience that will bring us success. My dear brothers and sisters, Ramadan is only days away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is they who are Guided</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
My dear brothers and sisters in this beautiful religion of Islam, sometimes we have to sit back and ponder about life and ponder about the purpose of it. Sometimes we know the purpose, yet we fall of track due to the play and amusement of this world. Nonetheless, we should never despair of the mercy of our Lord, for verily He is the Most Merciful and Most Forgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Complain only to Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
I start by asking a very simple question: Where does patience stand within our lives today?
SubhanAllah, what a beautiful trait it is yet we rarely see the implementation of it. Such a beautiful tree by which the sweetest of fruits cultivate and bless our lives, yet we just let it slip away as a &amp;#8220;thing of the past&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Two More?!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/just-two-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 16:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/just-two-more/</guid>
      <description>In Suratul-Furqaan (Surah 25), ayah 63, Allah begins a description of what is translated as &amp;#8220;the slaves of Ar-Rahmaan (Allah)&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8230;عِبَادُ الرَّحْمَنِ  In ayah 64, He describes these &amp;#8220;slaves&amp;#8221; by saying:
َالَّذِينَ يَبِيتُونَ لِرَبِّهِمْ سُجَّداً وَقِيَاماً …  This is translated as: those who spend the night before their Lord, prostrating (in sujood) and standing.
Tafsir ibn Kathir explains this ayah, and compares it to ayahs 17-18 from Suratuth-Thaariyaat (Surah 51):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comfortable?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/comfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 22:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/comfortable/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
‏حدثنا ‏ ‏سويد ‏ ‏أخبرنا ‏ ‏عبد الله ‏ ‏أخبرنا ‏ ‏أبو العلاء ‏ ‏عن ‏ ‏عطية ‏ ‏عن ‏ ‏أبي سعيد ‏ ‏قال ‏
‏قال رسول الله ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏كيف أنعم وصاحب القرن قد ‏ ‏التقم ‏ ‏القرن واستمع الإذن متى يؤمر بالنفخ فينفخ فكأن ذلك ثقل على ‏ ‏أصحاب النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏فقال لهم قولوا حسبنا الله ونعم الوكيل على الله توكلنا  The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said, &amp;#8220;How can I feel comfort while the angel responsible for The Trumpet has placed The Trumpet to his mouth and lowered his forehead, awaiting when he will be commanded (by Allah to blow in it)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day of Arafah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-day-of-arafah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 16:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-day-of-arafah/</guid>
      <description>Arafah: the main day of Hajj. The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said in one hadith: &amp;#8220;Hajj IS Arafah.&amp;#8221; [Sunan Abu Dawud, book 10, #1944] How true that is&amp;#8211;if you go to Arafah, but miss everything else, your Hajj is sound; and if you do everything else, but miss Arafah, your Hajj is not valid.
How much more important can you get than that?
Arafah, the day when millions of poeple gather in one place at one time to praise and supplicate to Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Plans for Friday?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 16:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Check out this hadith:
‏إِنَّ مِنْ أَفْضَلِ أَيَّامِكُمْ يَوْمَ الْجُمُعَةِ فَأَكْثِرُوا عَلَيَّ مِنْ الصَّلاَةِ فِيهِ
فَإِنَّ صَلاَتَكُمْ مَعْرُوضَةٌ عَلَيَّ قَالَ فَقَالُوا يَا رَسُولَ اللَّهِ
وَكَيْفَ تُعْرَضُ صَلاَتُنَا عَلَيْكَ وَقَدْ أَرَمْتَ ‏- ‏قَالَ يَقُولُونَ بَلِيتَ
‏قَالَ إِنَّ اللَّهَ تَبَارَكَ وَتَعَالَى حَرَّمَ عَلَى الأَرْضِ أَجْسَادَ الأَنْبِيَاءِ صَلَّى اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِمْ
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Surely, among the best of your days is Friday; so increase in (invoking Allah&amp;#8217;s) salaat upon me during it, for your (invocations for Allah&amp;#8217;s) Salaat (upon me) will be displayed to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hajj Black Dots</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/hajj-black-dots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/hajj-black-dots/</guid>
      <description>Take a look at the following picture. What do you see?
 
Most people will say they see the black dot. Not the whole field of white dots.
That&amp;#8217;s people for you! Despite all the white dots around us&amp;#8211;our health, wealth, youth, our household, our family, our fine clothing&amp;#8211;we only see the black dots. That guy at work who&amp;#8217;s always talking on the phone. That punk at school who keeps stealing your cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success is For the Believers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 18:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the first few verses of Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon:
قَدْ أَفْلَحَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ فِي صَلَاتِهِمْ خَاشِعُونَ  Translation: Successful are the Believers! Those who establish their salaah with khushoo. [Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon, verses 1-2]
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) carries on to mention many other characteristics of the believer in this surah&amp;#8211;however, the thing to focus on, the thing to ponder about, is that the FIRST characteristic that Allah chooses to describe a believer by&amp;#8211;a person who establishes the salaah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Duaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 20:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
How many times have we heard this duaa in our lives: Rabbana aatina fid-dunya hasanah, wa fil-akhirati hasanah, wa qinaa athaban naar. Have we ever contemplated how complete this duaa is?
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says
فَمِنَ النَّاسِ مَن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا وَمَا لَهُ فِي الآخِرَةِ مِنْ خَلاَقٍ وِمِنْهُم مَّن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا حَسَنَةً وَفِي الآخِرَةِ حَسَنَةً وَقِنَا عَذَابَ النَّارِ  Translation: And among the people is he who says, &amp;#8220;our Lord, give us in this world,&amp;#8221; and he will have in the Hereafter no share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Alcohol Najas?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 12:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;#8220;khamr&amp;#8221; in Arabic refers to intoxicants (in general), but also specifically to alcohol. We all know drinking alcohol is haraam&amp;#8211;but is alcohol itself najas? People use alcohol in medicine, in lens-cleaners, even in foods. What have scholars said about this?
Summary: Allahu &amp;#8216;alim, both sides&amp;#8211;those that say alcohol is najas, and those that don&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8211;have strong proofs. Having said that, all four madhahib say alcohol is najas. The main proof&amp;#8211;and there are a few proofs&amp;#8211;is the ayah:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tawaf 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tawaf-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2008 22:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tawaf-101/</guid>
      <description>What is tawaf, how do you do it, and what&amp;#8217;s the best way to go about it?
Tawaf, Islamically, means circling around the Ka&amp;#8217;bah for Hajj in the way the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) did and told us to do. The requirements of tawaf are simple&amp;#8211;be in a state of wudoo.
The mechanics of tawaf are:
 You walk around the ka&amp;#8217;bah, seven times Start at the Black Stone corner (from outside, it has a green light); raise your hand towards the Black Stone and say &amp;#8220;Allahu Akbar&amp;#8221; (or, if you can reach it, touch the black stone and say Allahu Akbar) For men, if possible, you walk quickly (raml, in Arabic) the first three times Make du&amp;#8217;a, recite Qur&amp;#8217;an, or make dhikr as you walk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worship</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</guid>
      <description>We go through life praying, giving to the poor, fasting, and other forms of worship which are prescribed by Allah. However, when was the last time we sat back and really tried to understand what it means to worship Allah? Why do we worship Him? Listen to the podcast for more details on this crucial aspect of Islam&amp;#8211;worship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasting in Muharram</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/fasting-in-muharram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 07:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/fasting-in-muharram/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
The sacred month of Muharram is now upon us, and a new year has begun alhamdulillah. InshaAllah I wanted to remind you all and myself of the great sunnan this month has for us:
Rasulllah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The best of fasting after Ramadaan is the month of Allah, Muharram, and the best of prayer after the obligatory prayers is prayer at night (qiyaam al-layl).&amp;#8221; [Saheeh Muslim, #1163]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Purification Water</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 09:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</guid>
      <description>Can you re-use water used for purification&amp;#8211;wudoo or ghusl? This issue doesn&amp;#8217;t apply to most people unless they&amp;#8217;re stuck somewhere without much water&amp;#8211;like Cambodia, where they get water once a year, during flood season, and keep it for nine months.
(Before you read this, read about the three-fold categorization of water; in summary, water can either be purifying (tuhoor), pure (taahir), or impure (najas), and we can only use purifying water for wudoo and ghusl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utensils and Vessels</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</guid>
      <description>What utensils and vessels (called inaa&amp;#8217; in Arabic, which includes cups, plates, utensils, and the like&amp;#8211;though we&amp;#8217;ll call it &amp;#8220;utensils&amp;#8221; for simplicity) are halal to eat from? This is important&amp;#8211;your du&amp;#8217;a is at stake! If you eat from haraam, Allah will not accept your du&amp;#8217;a.
Scholars agree that all utensils made from pure and clean things&amp;#8211;other then silver and gold, because we&amp;#8217;re prohibited from eating from those&amp;#8211;are pure and clean. So throw out your silverware, even if it&amp;#8217;s only partially silver; gold plating is not allowed, either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Hajj Jackpots</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-hajj-jackpots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 21:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/five-hajj-jackpots/</guid>
      <description>Hajj is an amazing act of ibadah&amp;#8211;one that requires everything: mind, body, and wealth. People invest so much time, so much energy, and so much money into Hajj&amp;#8211;and for what? What do they get out of it?
For a properly-intentioned, well-planned and correctly-executed Hajj&amp;#8211;one free of, for example, arguing, pushing, and harming other Muslims, full of patience&amp;#8211;there are five jackpots you cash out on when you perform Hajj:
 Deeds: The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever performs Hajj to this house&amp;#8211;the Ka&amp;#8217;bah&amp;#8211;and does not commit any obscenity and wrongdoing, he, or she, will come out as the day he or she was born,pure and free from sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Hajj Gems</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/amazing-hajj-gems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 03:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/amazing-hajj-gems/</guid>
      <description>Did you know:
 The literal meaning of hajj is ‘desire’?   Hajj is one of the main five pillars and all muslims desire to go for hajj.   We should hasten to do it/plan for it as early as possible. [1]   Hajj is expensive, but ALHAMDULILAH we have been given glad tidings: by the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), who said, it eliminates poverty and sin!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Go Hajj Shopping!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/lets-go-hajj-shopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 18:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/lets-go-hajj-shopping/</guid>
      <description>Hajj is coming. Less then two weeks remaining! But what&amp;#8217;s the deal with Hajj shopping? Everybody tells you to take different things. Take suitcases. No, don&amp;#8217;t take suitcases. Take lots of clothes. No, take a few clothes. Take medicine.
Confusion abounds.
How would you like a sneak peak at the shopping list of someone who attended Hajj several times in the last few years? Someone who changed their focus from attending Hajj to helping others excel at Hajj?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dua: The Weapon of the Believer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-the-weapon-of-the-believer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 17:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/dua-the-weapon-of-the-believer/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of life is to worship Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and dua is the crux of worship.
Dua: The Weapon of the Believer Video
Dua: Goes hand-in-hand with tawakkul (trust and hope in Allah (سبحانه وتعالى))
Dua is the essence of worship: calling to The One, the Only One who can actually help you and Who actually deserves to be called upon. The One who is As-Samad, The Satisfier of every need; upon Whom everything depends but He depends on no one and nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purification Act</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 10:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</guid>
      <description>The Purification Act  The Purification Act is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Abdul-Bary Yahya. If you think you know wudoo, think again! This course teaches you the ins and outs of tahara (purity and purification) and salaah (prayer)&amp;#8211;everything from whether one adhaan or two is more correct, to the proper way to purify dog-slobber from your best china, to whether a pigskin football (or for that matter, a leather jacket) is najas or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>