<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taqwa on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/taqwa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taqwa on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:26:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/taqwa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Practical Steps to Taqwa, Step 1: Muhasabah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/four-practical-steps-to-taqwa-step-1-muhasabah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/four-practical-steps-to-taqwa-step-1-muhasabah/</guid>
      <description>Photo Credit: Pienw (Flickr)
The first practical step to gaining taqwa is accountability, known as muhasabah in Arabic; taking account of your actions. We see this concept from the beginning of Islamic history.:
In the Qur&amp;#8217;an In Surah Al-Hashr, Allah says:
 يا ايها الذين امنوا اتقوا الله ولتنظر نفس ما قدمت لغد واتقوا الله ان الله خبير بما تعملون
 Translation: O you who have believed, fear Allah .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacons of Light</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 16:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/beacons-of-light/</guid>
      <description>The following is a guest post from I Got it Covered, a blog about hijab, Islam, and life. You can find the original article here.
In the time of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab, radiAllahu anhu, the second Khalifah, it was mandatory upon all the young girls to learn Surat an-Noor.
From the beauty of this Surah is that it begins with, &amp;#8220;[This is] a surah which We have sent down and made [that within it] obligatory and revealed therein verses of clear evidence that you might remember&amp;#8221; [Surat an-Noor: 1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are on camera!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 19:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-are-on-camera/</guid>
      <description>Imagine this. You are speeding on the road. The police officer catches you, pulls you over and gives you a speeding ticket. What would your reaction be, next time you are driving especially driving through the same road. You would naturally slow down! Or you are stealing from your prayer (i.e. racing through it), you glance over and it seems like your friends might be looking at you. Your reaction&amp;#8230;. In these and in countless other situations, we refrain from doing bad because we fear that we might be caught or someone might be looking at us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>