<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qampa on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/qampa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qampa on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 12:07:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/qampa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Alcohol Najas?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 12:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;#8220;khamr&amp;#8221; in Arabic refers to intoxicants (in general), but also specifically to alcohol. We all know drinking alcohol is haraam&amp;#8211;but is alcohol itself najas? People use alcohol in medicine, in lens-cleaners, even in foods. What have scholars said about this?
Summary: Allahu &amp;#8216;alim, both sides&amp;#8211;those that say alcohol is najas, and those that don&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8211;have strong proofs. Having said that, all four madhahib say alcohol is najas. The main proof&amp;#8211;and there are a few proofs&amp;#8211;is the ayah:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utensils and Vessels</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</guid>
      <description>What utensils and vessels (called inaa&amp;#8217; in Arabic, which includes cups, plates, utensils, and the like&amp;#8211;though we&amp;#8217;ll call it &amp;#8220;utensils&amp;#8221; for simplicity) are halal to eat from? This is important&amp;#8211;your du&amp;#8217;a is at stake! If you eat from haraam, Allah will not accept your du&amp;#8217;a.
Scholars agree that all utensils made from pure and clean things&amp;#8211;other then silver and gold, because we&amp;#8217;re prohibited from eating from those&amp;#8211;are pure and clean. So throw out your silverware, even if it&amp;#8217;s only partially silver; gold plating is not allowed, either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fard vs. Wajib</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/fard-vs-wajib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 09:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/fard-vs-wajib/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people&amp;#8211;especially new Muslims&amp;#8211;break their heads on this conundrum. What is the difference between fard and wajib? Are they the same? Are they different? What&amp;#8217;s the scoop? Why do some people say fard, while others say wajib for the same things?
The answer is simple. According to the majority of scholars, fard and wajib mean the EXACT same thing. There is no difference. They are interchangable. (Recall that fard means: an action that, if performed, entails reward, and if neglected, entails punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Name</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 13:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</guid>
      <description>Question: I heard that there&amp;#8217;s one name of Allah, that if you use it to invoke Allah, your du&amp;#8217;a is accepted. Is this true?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;To Allah belongs a Grand Name, that, if you make du&amp;#8217;a with it, it will be responded to. And if you plead or request with it, it shall be answered.&amp;#8221; [Recorded in Abu Dawud, Tirmidhi, and others; Saheeh]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge, Practice, Da’wah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 18:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/knowledge-practice-dawah/</guid>
      <description>Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
Q: Allah grants knowledge to those He loves. What do you do to be among these people?  A: Strive. Show interest in the deen. Come closer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), and He will come closer to you. There is a hadith on how to gain knowledge: &amp;#8216;ilm is only gained by studying. It&amp;#8217;s not gained by hiding in a cave and worshipping Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Studious study is the only way to gain knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Way to Increase Eman?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2006 16:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/best-way-to-increase-eman/</guid>
      <description>Question: What is the best way for a person increase his or her eman?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The single greatest way to increase your eman is to gain knowledge. Study what eman is, study tawhid, the pillars of eman, etc. It automatically increases your eman.
Good deeds also increase eman&amp;#8211;each and every single good deed and act of worship you perform increases your eman. Fast a day. Read Qur&amp;#8217;an. Pray Tahajjud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness for Shirk?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 05:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</guid>
      <description>Allah blessed me with the opportunity to listen to Shaykh Yasir Qadhi, who specializes in Aqeeda, speak about shirk. Here&amp;#8217;s what he said.
Question: What happens if you&amp;#8217;re Muslim and you&amp;#8217;ve committed shirk?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
In the Qur&amp;#8217;an, in many places, Allah says shirk is unforgivable.
إِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِ وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَلِكَ لِمَن يَشَاء وَمَن يُشْرِكْ بِاللّهِ فَقَدِ افْتَرَى إِثْمًا عَظِيمًا  Translation: Surely Allah does not forgive that anything should be associated with Him, and forgives what is besides that to whomsoever He pleases; and whoever associates anything with Allah, he devises indeed a great sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>