<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 16:30:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 – Manners of Sneezing and Yawning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 16:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
 This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. In the last post, we talked about the manners of sleeping. In this post, we will look at the Sunnahs of sneezing and yawning:
 Narrated Abu Huraira: The Prophet said, &amp;ldquo;Allah loves sneezing but dislikes yawning; so if anyone of you sneezes and then praises Allah, every Muslim who hears him (praising Allah) has to say Tashmit to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we focus on the sunnah of making ablution and coming out of the washroom. Here is the sunnah for this week:
After the fard salahs:
 After slautation, say Allahu Akbar in loud voice Say &amp;#8220;Astagfirullah&amp;#8221; thrice in low voice Recite &amp;#8220;Ayat Kursi&amp;#8221; Read the morning and evening supplications after farjar and asar prayers (Another Link) Recite other Adhkars and Supplications Pray the two rakahs of ishraq after the fajar prayer (The Messenger of Allah [SAWS] said, “Whoever prays the dawn prayer (fajr) in a group and then sits and does dhikr until the sun rises, then prays two rakas, shall have the like of the reward of a hajj and an umra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Uncle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</guid>
      <description>And We have not sent you, [O Muhammad], except as a mercy to the worlds. [21:107]
In the last post, we looked at how our beloved prophet (SAW) set for us an excellent example as a father. Inshallah, continuing with the theme, in this post, we will explore two more roles: **uncle and the master.
**
Treatment with niece
 After the Taif Campaign, one of the captives As-Shaima, the daughter of Al-Harith As-Sadiya, the Messenger’s foster sister was brought to the Messenger of Allah (peace be upon him) , she introduced herself to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beautiful Qualities of Yahya alayhi salam</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Allah subhaanhu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (the meaning of which is):
 &amp;#8220;(It was said to his son): &amp;#8220;O Yahya (John)! Hold fast the Scripture [the Taurat (Torah)].&amp;#8221; And We gave him wisdom while yet a child. And (made him) sympathetic to men as a mercy (or a grant) from Us, and pure from sins [i.e. Yahya (John)] and he was righteous, and dutiful towards his parents, and he was neither an arrogant nor disobedient (to Allah or to his parents).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanking Allah in times of a Calamity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 15:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Umer radhiAllah anhu used to say:
 &amp;#8220;If Allah strikes me with calamity I will thank Allah for four things: 1) that the test was not in my deen 2) the calamity could have been worse 3) it is an expiation for my sins 4) any loss after losing the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam is nothing”
 The greatest man that lived after the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam and Abu Bakr as-Siddiq radhiAllah anhu, Umer ibn al-Khattab radhiAllah anhu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Four Priorities of the Muslim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</guid>
      <description>Abu Barzah al-Aslami radi Allahu anhu reported that Allah’s Messenger sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, “The two feet of the servant will not cease (from standing before Allah) on the Day of Judgment until he is asked about four things: on his life and how he spent it; on his knowledge and what he did with it; on his wealth and where he earned it and how he spent it; and on his body and in what way he utilized it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Resource Bonanza!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#8217;s better than a chest of gold and jewels? A post full of Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah!  Bismillah.
This is a guest post by an author who compiled a wide number of resources related to fasting, reciting Qur&amp;#8217;an, and sincerity of intention. This is a great resource of ahadith and ayaat related to fasting. May Allah grant them a great reward (ameen!) and forgive any mistakes I have made in re-formatting it and linking all the sources to their citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice from an Older Brother: Study your Deen</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/advice-from-an-older-brother-study-your-deen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2007 08:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/advice-from-an-older-brother-study-your-deen/</guid>
      <description>From a lecture given at MIST Nationals 2006 by Abu Ammaar Yasir Qadhi
Friday July 21st, 2006
Knowledge and Studying your Deen  &amp;#8220;I am here in front of you today, and if I were to choose again, I would go back and do the same thing and do religious studies. I can&amp;#8217;t even remember what courses I took when I was at UH. My main motivation for choosing to do Islamic studies was that I realized I needed to do something for the ummah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 Ways to Keep Your Husband’s Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/60-ways-to-keep-your-husbands-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 08:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/60-ways-to-keep-your-husbands-love/</guid>
      <description>60 Ways to Keep Your Husband&amp;#8217;s Love   Behave like a female, i.e. all the tenderness of a female&amp;#8211;a man doesn’t want a man for his wife! Dress pleasantly/attractively. If you are a home-maker, don’t stay in your sleeping suit all day. Smell good! Don’t lay out all your problems on your husband as soon as he walks in. Give him a little mental break. Don’t keep asking him, “what are you thinking?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Tips Towards Being a Successful Husband</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ten-tips-towards-being-a-successful-husband/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 02:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ten-tips-towards-being-a-successful-husband/</guid>
      <description>Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, &amp;#8220;the best amongst you are the ones who are best to their wives.&amp;#8221; So dear Muslim brother! Your obligations towards your wife are not limited to earning money and supporting her financially. A wife needs love from her husband, and emotional support too!
10 Tips on How to Be a Successful Husband  Note: Additions in brackets are notes from a sister.
Prepared by Muhammad Alshareef, reprinted from Islamway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping Out Your Fellow Brother</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/helping-your-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 17:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/helping-your-brother/</guid>
      <description>Ibn `Umar (May Allah be pleased with them) reported: The Messenger of Allah (sa) said:
“A Muslim is a brother of (another) Muslim, he neither wrongs him nor does hand him over to one who does him wrong. If anyone fulfils his brother&amp;#8217;s needs, Allah will fulfil his needs; if one relieves a Muslim of his troubles, Allah will relieve his troubles on the Day of Resurrection…&amp;#8221; [Bukhari and Muslim]. Subhanallah!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</guid>
      <description>Innal-Hamdu lillah was-Salaatu was-Salaam `alaa Rasoolillah
&amp;ldquo;Lucky escape &amp;hellip; hmmm &amp;hellip; Nah! It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t my time to go yet; Allah saved me and gave me a little longer &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Driving home from work after having a late staff meeting, it was an ordinary evening not much traffic on the road. I got onto the dual carriage, I was in the right lane doing around 60-70 miles an hour, then all of a sudden *BANG* the bonnet of my car flew open and smashed against my car windscreen, *SMASH* all the glass cracked and from the great impact, my back view mirror had completely broken off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Days of the Year</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Are you a student, or working? Are you depressed or frustrated that you could not take the advantage of the last ten nights of Ramadan? There were midterms, assignments, and projects for all the working folk, all those cliched reasons, or maybe you did take advantage. Here is another chance. Its on our doorsteps, the most beloved days to Allah, the first ten days of Dhul Hijjah.
It was reported by Ibn ‘Abbas (رضي الله عنه) that the Rasoolullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;There are no days in which righteous deeds are more beloved to Allah than these ten days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptions of the Believers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/descriptions-of-the-believers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 19:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/descriptions-of-the-believers/</guid>
      <description>How does it feel after reading Qur&amp;#8217;an? Does it make a difference in us? How much do we implement it regularly, or even within the same day of reading an ayah?
When learning from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and the seerah of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), Allah mentions a believers qualities in the Qur&amp;#8217;an. The believers hearts become fearful and their eyes tear. This is a sign of the true believers, as Allah describes them in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/love-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 02:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/love-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Want to earn the love of Allah? Imagine! To be loved by the greatest, the self-sufficient, the lord of the universe! Who doesn&amp;#8217;t want that? Read on inshallah and find out how to achieve that lofty goal!
Love of Allah  Ibn al-Qaiyim (رحمالله) mentioned ten causes that result in Allah&amp;#8217;s (سبحانه وتعالى) love for His slave and the slave&amp;#8217;s love for his Lord. [These ten are:]
First, recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an while pondering over its meanings and what is meant by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s a Bird, It’s a Plane, It’s … MuminMan?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muminman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 00:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muminman/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s a bird, it&amp;#8217;s a plane, it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8230; MuminMan?  By night, a city slicker patrols the streets. Seen but not seen, he&amp;#8217;s just another face in the crowd, unnoticed with trendy glasses and the slickest new Nike running shoes. He breezes in and out through bars and clubs. He chills with his friends. And if she&amp;#8217;s not mad, maybe he&amp;#8217;ll call his girlfriend for a date. Just your ordinary homeboy or girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Concerns You?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-concerns-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 12:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-concerns-you/</guid>
      <description>Concerns of a med student:
Ahmed: I&amp;#8217;ve been trying so hard to make it into that post med program.
Friend: Hey, what about meeting with Dr.Muneeb. Just go ask him what you need to get in, he is THE BEST doctor.
Ahmed: You think I havent already? I am practically following ALL his footsteps to the best to my ability &amp;#8230; just sometimes I get concerned if I&amp;#8217;m still going to make it or not &amp;#8230; hope I can achieve all the marks I need before its too late.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Please Everyone</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Today I have learned a valuable lesson, and I believe its a lesson that all of you readers can benefit from. The lesson itself is very simple, but realizing the importance and understanding the implications it may have in one’s life is what matters the most. The lesson is: you can‘t please everyone. Sounds so simple, right? Many of us are reading this and saying, well duh! So then, if its so obvious why do we keep persisting in our efforts to doing so?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Feel the Pain.</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/i-feel-the-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 08:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/i-feel-the-pain/</guid>
      <description>We feel the pain. We are hurting. We are crying. Reality has kicked in. Up until a month ago, everything was just a blur, didn’t know the effect and seriousness of the situations around the world. Up until a month ago, don’t even know if I felt for those around the world. However, when it creeps up into your own country, your own city, your own community, your own _family_–you feel everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruit of Ilm: Where has it Gone?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruit-of-ilm-where-has-it-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2006 19:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruit-of-ilm-where-has-it-gone/</guid>
      <description>We all are sitting in a world in which the value of knowledge is at its all-time high. Many of us, or our parents, invest a good amount of income towards this so-called &amp;#8220;educational system&amp;#8221; entitled “University” or “College”. Many of us invest hours upon hours, days upon days, week after week indulged in books and lectures learning about Limits, Laws of Neutrality, Psychological Human Behaviour, or, my favourite, Pareto Optimal (:S).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Tips for a Happy and Successful Marriage</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ten-tips-for-a-happy-and-successful-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2006 13:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ten-tips-for-a-happy-and-successful-marriage/</guid>
      <description>The following is some amazing nasiha adapted from an article by Dr. Aisha Hamdan (additional notes are italicized). Read it inshallah ta’ala and benefit from it. Props to The Muslimah Corner for finding it. You can find the original here.
  The young and excited bride-and-groom-to-be, ecstatic about the upcoming wedding and marriage, and the joy that it will bring. Three to six months later, reality sets in, and both spouses realize that marriage is no easy task, but one that takes a great deal of effort and patience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wife</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2006 02:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-wife/</guid>
      <description>The following is a beautiful little speech by Shaykh Abdullah Adhami, entitled &amp;#8220;A Wife&amp;#8221;. Read it inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala and benefit from it. Props to Beautiful Islam for the original.
  By getting married you are not just getting a wife, you are getting your whole world. From now until the rest of your days your wife will be your partner, your companion, and your best friend.She will share your moments, your days, and your years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Cup? What’s That?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/world-cup-whats-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/world-cup-whats-that/</guid>
      <description>While FIFA World Cup blares over TV, reports on the radio, articles in the paper, we see our friends, our family, our co-workers, all of them glued to this new world.
Here are eleven reasons to unglue them (and yourself!) inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala:
 I will be questioned on the Day of Judgement about how I squandered and wasted my time. Who are those guys running around like headless chickens kicking that ball?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sins: Tawbah and Repetition</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/sins-tawbah-and-repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 11:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/sins-tawbah-and-repetition/</guid>
      <description>Scholars say: there are no major sins with tawbah, and there are no minor sins with repetiton. What does that mean? The one who commits major sins and performs tawbah is forgiven; and the one who commits minor sins repeatedly is overcome by them, and they reach the level of major sins.
Ibn Mas&amp;#8217;ud (رضي الله عنه) said: A believer treats a sin as if it is a mountain over his head that may fall on him any moment; whereas a dissolute person looks at it as a fly that hovers around his nose and he waves it away with his hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</guid>
      <description>This article by Steve Pavlina explains how to effectively manage your life by focusing on tasks based on their long-term effects.
The article defines three categories of tasks, and allocates your daily time to each of them proportionally based on their expected benefit.
 &amp;#8220;A&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in five or more years, such as learning a new language. &amp;#8220;B&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in two or more years, such as training for a marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>