<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akhlaaq on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/akhlaaq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akhlaaq on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 12:44:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/akhlaaq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Examples of How Rasulullah Treated Children</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/10-examples-of-how-rasulullah-treated-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 12:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/10-examples-of-how-rasulullah-treated-children/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Farazk007
The sunnah contains many examples of how rasulullah (ﷺ) dealt with children.
Why is this important? Because he&amp;#8217;s our uswah, our role-model, our example to follow. Many of his companions met him once or twice, saw him doing something once or twice, and as a result, would keep doing that thing until they died. Not because he told them to, but because they loved him, and sought to follow him as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attributes of a Successful Parent</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/attributes-of-a-successful-parent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 20:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/attributes-of-a-successful-parent/</guid>
      <description>The sunnah mentions several characteristics of successful parents. Let&amp;#8217;s dive into some of them.
Hilm (Forebearance) and Hayaa (Modesty)  حَدَّثَنَا أَبُو إِسْحَاقَ الْهَرَوِيُّ، حَدَّثَنَا الْعَبَّاسُ بْنُ الْفَضْلِ الأَنْصَارِيُّ، حَدَّثَنَا قُرَّةُ بْنُ خَالِدٍ، حَدَّثَنَا أَبُو جَمْرَةَ، عَنِ ابْنِ عَبَّاسٍ، أَنَّ النَّبِيَّ ـ صلى الله عليه وسلم ـ قَالَ لِلأَشَجِّ الْعَصَرِيِّ ‏ &amp;#8220;‏ إِنَّ فِيكَ خَصْلَتَيْنِ يُحِبُّهُمَا اللَّهُ الْحِلْمَ وَالْحَيَاءَ ‏&amp;#8221;‏ ‏.‏
 Translation: It was narrated from Ibn ‘Abbas that the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said to Ashajj Ansari: &amp;#8220;You have two characteristics that Allah likes: Forbearance and modesty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elephant Theory</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/the-elephant-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 19:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/the-elephant-theory/</guid>
      <description>As we mentioned with the sandwich theory, with children, always separate the behaviour from the person. Never say things like, &amp;#8220;I hate you&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8217;re a loser,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;idiot,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;stupid,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;I wish I never had you!&amp;#8221; Some of us heard this from our own parents. Are we now our own parents? Are we passing on this disease? This DNA has to be out.
The elephant theory is quite simple: young elephants are trained, with one leg that&amp;#8217;s shackled to a cement block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sandwich Theory</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/the-sandwich-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 19:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/the-sandwich-theory/</guid>
      <description>The sandwich theory encapsulates the idea of how to advice others (children, spouse, etc.) with the goal of minimizing resistance. Human beings naturally resist being told that they&amp;#8217;re doing something wrong and need to change.
The sandwich theory is simple: a sandwich consists of a nice, soft bun, followed by meat, followed by another soft bun. The heart of the sandwich (or burger) is really the meat.
How do you implement this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twelve Things About the Terrible Twos</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/twelve-things-about-the-terrible-twos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 23:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/twelve-things-about-the-terrible-twos/</guid>
      <description>Definition and Asl Definition: &amp;#8220;Terrible twos&amp;#8221; occur when children are between the ages of one and three years old. This is usually when children throw a lot of tantrums, and rebel, saying &amp;#8220;no!&amp;#8221; to many things you tell them. How can you effectively deal with this situation?
First, understand the root (asl): children cannot keep their strong emotions inside. They cry, they scream, they stomp, they fling themselves on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Responsibility of Children &#43; 21 Theory</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-responsibility-of-children-21-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 23:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-responsibility-of-children-21-theory/</guid>
      <description>Responsibility: Reward and Punishment It&amp;#8217;s our responsibility to take are of our children, especially their akhirah &amp;#8212; their eternal life. Allah says:
Translation: O you who have believed, protect yourselves and your families from a Fire whose fuel is people and stones [&amp;#8230;] (Surah At-Tahrim, verse 66)
This ayah illustrates our responsibility: protect yourselves, and your children, from Hellfire &amp;#8212; a fire whose fuel is stones and men. Would you raise your children, knowingly, that they are going to be firewood, or fuel for the fire?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pass Tests: Lessons from the Du’a of Prophet Ibrahim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/how-to-pass-tests-lessons-from-the-dua-of-prophet-ibrahim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 11:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/how-to-pass-tests-lessons-from-the-dua-of-prophet-ibrahim/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Al-Anbiyaa, Allah says:
Translation: Every soul will taste death. And We test you with evil and with good as trial; and to Us you will be returned. (Surah Al-Anbiya, verse 35)
In this verse, Allah uses the word &amp;#8220;nablukum&amp;#8221; (نبلوكم). This is a present-tense (mudaari&amp;#8217;) form of the word &amp;#8220;balaa.&amp;#8221; From the grammar itself, scholars note, this means that Allah says that he will test you again and again and again, continuously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect: A Lesson from Al-Abbas</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 03:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</guid>
      <description>Someone asked Al-Abbas (radiallahu anhu), the uncle of rasulullah, a question: are you akbar than rasulullah?
In Arabic, literally, this means &amp;#8220;are you greater than rasulullah.&amp;#8221; But the obvious connotation is that the questioner asks about age: are you older than him?
Al-Abbas said:
 رسول الله أكبر مني و لكن ولدت قبله
Rasulullah is greater than me, but I was born before him.
 He wanted to set the record set, and give a clear message to all of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 22:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</guid>
      <description>I hope that you had an awesome productive last week, applying and implementing the Sunnah Items, we discussed in the last post. Here is the sunnah for this week:
On Coming Out of Washroom:
 Exit with Right Foot first Say the dua  Making Ablution:
 Say Bismillah Do the Mishwaak Run water through the fingers Put water in the nose Say the Sahada after finishing Say the dua Pray 2 rakahs of tayatul whudoo  Tip of the Week:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 15:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we started a new series. The goal of the series is to learn and implement the sunnah in our lives. We started with the sunnah of our beloved Prophet (May Allah&amp;#8217;s peace and blessings be upon him) on waking up. I hope all of you have been practicing that sunnah. Here is the sunnah for this week:
Entering the Washroom:
 Enter with slippers/shoes Make the dua Enter with Left foot  After Entering the Washroom:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 22:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Allah Subhannallah, tells us in the Quran:
 لَّقَدْ كَانَ لَكُمْ فِي رَسُولِ اللَّـهِ أُسْوَةٌ
حَسَنَةٌ لِّمَن كَانَ يَرْجُو اللَّـهَ وَ
وَذَكَرَ اللَّـهَ كَثِيرًا
 Translation:
There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.[Surah Al-Ahzab, verses 21]
The oxford dictionary defines the word &amp;#8216;role model&amp;#8216; as &amp;#8220;A person looked to by others as an example to be imitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beautiful Qualities of Yahya alayhi salam</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Allah subhaanhu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (the meaning of which is):
 &amp;#8220;(It was said to his son): &amp;#8220;O Yahya (John)! Hold fast the Scripture [the Taurat (Torah)].&amp;#8221; And We gave him wisdom while yet a child. And (made him) sympathetic to men as a mercy (or a grant) from Us, and pure from sins [i.e. Yahya (John)] and he was righteous, and dutiful towards his parents, and he was neither an arrogant nor disobedient (to Allah or to his parents).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Shams: One Man’s Sin</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-shams-one-mans-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 10:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-shams-one-mans-sin/</guid>
      <description>This is post #26 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
The noble she-camel, prized in the Arab society, was actually one of the signs Allah sent to a nation. What did they do with it?  Surahs are usually named by something unique in their content. But the sun (ash-shams) is mentioned in several surahs; so why is this one called Surah Shams?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Abasa: What Really Matters?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-abasa-what-really-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 21:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-abasa-what-really-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/imperial-crown.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;imperial crown&#34; title=&#34;imperial crown&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1280&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  It&amp;#8217;s not dunya status that matters. Allah teaches us this again in Surah Abasa&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s the one with taqwa.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is post #24 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would you feel if someone you love corrected you, in public, in front of everyone else? Would you feel condemned, or criticized? Would you take it more seriously than someone you don&amp;#8217;t like criticizing you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what if &lt;strong&gt;Allah, the Lord of the Universe,&lt;/strong&gt; criticized you &amp;#8230; in public?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek out the Benefit (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/seek-out-the-benefit-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/seek-out-the-benefit-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum!
What a beautiful month in which we can come together and build our salat. Ramadan Mubarak! We ask Allah to accept all our deeds from this blessed month and to give us the tawfeeq to push ourselves in pleasing Him, Subhana. To begin our journey, we remind ourselves of the saying our our beloved Prophet alayhi salatu wa salam; may not be directly related to prayers, nonetheless it is important:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levels of Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 15:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
Truly, patience is a characteristic of the Muslim that is required on many levels:
 Patience in worshiping Allah Patience in abstaining from wrong actions Patience at times of trials  These are the three levels we should constantly be monitoring, for verily it is these levels of patience that will bring us success. My dear brothers and sisters, Ramadan is only days away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is they who are Guided</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
My dear brothers and sisters in this beautiful religion of Islam, sometimes we have to sit back and ponder about life and ponder about the purpose of it. Sometimes we know the purpose, yet we fall of track due to the play and amusement of this world. Nonetheless, we should never despair of the mercy of our Lord, for verily He is the Most Merciful and Most Forgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Complain only to Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
I start by asking a very simple question: Where does patience stand within our lives today?
SubhanAllah, what a beautiful trait it is yet we rarely see the implementation of it. Such a beautiful tree by which the sweetest of fruits cultivate and bless our lives, yet we just let it slip away as a &amp;#8220;thing of the past&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you Stand with Allah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
حدثنا زهير بن حرب وعثمان بن أبي شيبة وإسحاق بن إبراهيم قال إسحاق أخبرنا وقال الآخران حدثنا جرير عن منصور عن أبي وائل عن عبد الله قال قال رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم إن الصدق يهدى إلى البر وإن البر يهدى إلى الجنة وإن الرجل ليصدق حتى يكتب صديقا وإن الكذب يهدى إلى الفجور وإن الفجور يهدى إلى النار وإن الرجل ليكذب حتى يكتب كذابا  Translation: Narrated &amp;#8216;Abdullah: The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: Truthfulness (sidq) leads to righteousness (birr), and righteousness leads to Paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Teacher</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 18:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an,
هُوَ الَّذِي بَعَثَ فِي الْأُمِّيِّينَ رَسُولًا مِّنْهُمْ يَتْلُو عَلَيْهِمْ آيَاتِهِ وَيُزَكِّيهِمْ وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الْكِتَابَ وَالْحِكْمَةَ وَإِن كَانُوا مِن قَبْلُ لَفِي ضَلَالٍ مُّبِينٍ  Translation: It is He who has sent among the unlettered a Messenger from themselves reciting to them His verses and purifying them and teaching them the Book and wisdom although they were before in clear error. [Suratul Jumu&amp;#8217;ah, verse 2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Character</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/good-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 02:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/good-character/</guid>
      <description>The following ahadeeth are from Ibn Hajr al-Asqalaanee&amp;#8217;s Bulooghul-Maram (Attainment of the Objective according to Evidence of the Ordinances&amp;#8211;page 480+ in the English translation). They touch on the importance of good Islamic character: being truthful, avoiding lying, the evil of a suspicious mind, heedlessness, not protecting each other&amp;#8217;s honour, etc.
As a good reminder to the sincere heart, even if you have been blessed with guidance to the Sunnah and hold yourself to be from Ahlul-Haqq, the Shaytaan will not leave you alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zina</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 18:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/zina/</guid>
      <description>We live in a world in which the concept of haya between man and women is lost. We forget that at every step Shaytaan waits to pounce, to guide us to evil. Living in the West, going to University, we see a lot of evil, and we see the plan of Shaytaan at work; Muslim men and Muslim women forgetting their boundaries and falling into the fitnah of society. Every wonder what would happen if you die in a state of disobedience to Allah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Do You Not Love that Allah Should Forgive You?”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 17:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</guid>
      <description>SubhanAllah, we all know the story about the accusations that were forged against &amp;#8216;Aishah (رضالله عنها), but in addition to that story, the tafsir for Surat An-Nur (Surah 24), ayah 22, reveals another story&amp;#8211;a story of forgiveness, a story of compassion, a story demonstrating the superiority of those who act for the sake of Allah (may Allah make us of them).
  Mistah was the cousin of As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Guarantees of Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/three-guarantees-of-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 22:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/three-guarantees-of-paradise/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I guarantee a house in Jannah (Paradise) for one who gives up arguing, even if he is in the right; and I guarantee a house in the middle of Jannah for one who abandons lying even when joking / for the sake of fun; and I guarantee a house in the highest part of Jannah for one who has good manners.&amp;#8221; [Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) &amp;#8211; reported by Imam Abu Dawud]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umm Sulaym and the Death of her Son</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-sulaym-and-the-death-of-her-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2007 07:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-sulaym-and-the-death-of-her-son/</guid>
      <description>Remember the story of the companion Umm Sulaym (رضي الله عنها), what an amazing thing about how a wife is with her husband. Her husband, Talha, was out working, and it so happened that day that their son, 10 years old, died.
She had a decision to make: when he comes home should she tell him right away, or should she just bear it and make him happy first and then when he is comfortable and settled in, then tell him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Points From Marriage 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/five-points-from-marriage-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2007 08:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/five-points-from-marriage-101/</guid>
      <description>Safi Khan, in his &amp;#8220;Marriage 101&amp;#8243; lecture CD (available from here), mentions many points; of the best, he mentions the following:
 For Brothers: use extreme compassion and mercy towards your wives! Almost all relationships could benefit from more mercy and compassion. For Sisters: struggle not to complain! Once complaints start, they only get worse, and in the end, they can spoil your marriage. For Both: have a common goal&amp;#8211;to serve Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), to worship Him, and to enter Jannah together, without reckoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typical</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 08:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</guid>
      <description>Typ‧i‧cal: Conforming to a particular type. For someone to be &amp;#8220;typical&amp;#8221;, he/she would be one who conforms to his society and behaves much like his environment.
Typical in the 21st century: clubbing, flirting, sex, drugs, alcohol, stealing, cheating, swearing, injustice, premarital relations, immodesty, and the list goes on and on.
So who&amp;#8217;s typical? Is it the one who refrains from all the above, or the one indulges in it? Is it the one who&amp;#8217;s perceived weird when he speaks out against someone swearing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/keys-to-paradise-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 23:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/keys-to-paradise-2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Whoever wishes to be delivered from the fire (of Hell) and enter the garden (of Paradise) should die with faith in Allah and the Last Day and should treat the people as he wishes to be treated by them.&amp;#8221;
[Muhammad &amp;#8211; Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) as recorded in Sahih Muslim]
1. Make a list of people you deal with:
 Parents Friends Co-workers  _2. Write how you would want to be treated in each of those roles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speak Good or Stay Silent</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/speak-good-or-stay-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/speak-good-or-stay-silent/</guid>
      <description>Abu Hurayrah relates that Allah’s Messenger (peace be upon him) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should speak a good word or remain silent. And whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should show hospitality to his neighbor. And whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should show hospitality to his guest.&amp;#8221; [Sahih al-Bukhari and Sahih Muslim]
_Speak good, or stay silent
Treat your guest, and don’t be violent</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 Ways to Keep Your Husband’s Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/60-ways-to-keep-your-husbands-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 08:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/60-ways-to-keep-your-husbands-love/</guid>
      <description>60 Ways to Keep Your Husband&amp;#8217;s Love   Behave like a female, i.e. all the tenderness of a female&amp;#8211;a man doesn’t want a man for his wife! Dress pleasantly/attractively. If you are a home-maker, don’t stay in your sleeping suit all day. Smell good! Don’t lay out all your problems on your husband as soon as he walks in. Give him a little mental break. Don’t keep asking him, “what are you thinking?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Tips Towards Being a Successful Husband</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ten-tips-towards-being-a-successful-husband/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2007 02:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ten-tips-towards-being-a-successful-husband/</guid>
      <description>Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, &amp;#8220;the best amongst you are the ones who are best to their wives.&amp;#8221; So dear Muslim brother! Your obligations towards your wife are not limited to earning money and supporting her financially. A wife needs love from her husband, and emotional support too!
10 Tips on How to Be a Successful Husband  Note: Additions in brackets are notes from a sister.
Prepared by Muhammad Alshareef, reprinted from Islamway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Nature is Insatiable</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 02:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</guid>
      <description>Human Nature is Insatiable  Human nature is insatiable. No matter how much you get, you will never be happy with it. That is the way we have been created. The key to happiness is not to get it all, but rather, to be content with little.
&amp;#8220;O Allah, I seek refuge in Thee from incapacity, from sloth, from cowardice, from miserliness, from decrepitude, and from the torment of the grave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victory Comes With Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 12:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said to his cousin: &amp;#8220;And know that victory comes with patience, relief with affliction, and ease with hardship. 1
Even in the battle of Qadisiyyah, after fighting through the whole day, the Muslim leader said &amp;#8220;just be patient, and keep fighting.&amp;#8221; Even into the night, when most armies stop fighting at night! But subhanallah, what happened? By the next morning, the Muslims had won.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QMajd Issue 1: Rules of Engagement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/qmajd-issue-1-rules-of-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 05:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/qmajd-issue-1-rules-of-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who haven&amp;#8217;t heard of the AlMaghrib institute, you&amp;#8217;re missing out&amp;#8211;they give some mashallah amazing double-weekend Islamic classes.
Qabeelat Majd (QMajd) is the Toronto branch. Mashallah, through the dedicated efforts of some dozen or so people, they finally published their first newsletter! It&amp;#8217;s for the Rules of Engagement class (click to learn more about the class), so it covers the subject of akhlaaq&amp;#8211;manners, etiquettes, dealings with Allah, with people, with yourself&amp;#8211;and contains such fruitful topics as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losers!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2007 21:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/losers/</guid>
      <description>I walked by as I noticed a bunch of people moved by music, indulged in gossip, purchased tickets from each other &amp;#8230; until I spotted my younger sister, Ayesha. I signed, looking at them, as I commented to her, &amp;#8220;&amp;#8230;bunch of losers.&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8220;What makes you think they are all losers?&amp;#8221; questioned Ayesha.
&amp;#8220;Well, look at all the things they are indulged in? They&amp;#8217;re obviously losers,&amp;#8221; I responded, as we both noticed other people carrying on with their activities disapprovingly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imam Abu Hanifa: A True Tradesman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2006 11:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</guid>
      <description>Once, a women came to Abu Hanifa (رحمالله) to sell a silk garment. Abu Hanifa asked &amp;#8221; How much is it?&amp;#8221; She replied, &amp;#8220;one hundred.&amp;#8221; He said, &amp;#8220;It is worth more than a hundred. How much?&amp;#8221;
So the woman increased the price by hundred, and again, and when it reached four hundred, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;It should be more than that.&amp;#8221; The woman said, &amp;#8221; you are mocking me.&amp;#8221;
So, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;bring a man to value it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Ain’t Cheap</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/talk-aint-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2006 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/talk-aint-cheap/</guid>
      <description>One of the diseases we experience in our culture is cheap talk. People say things all the time, whether they mean it or not. Worse, people lie as easily as they breathe&amp;#8211;sometimes, even as often&amp;#8211;and sometimes, under the guise of &amp;#8220;just kidding!&amp;#8221;
But is talk cheap? Let&amp;#8217;s look at some evidence from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah.
 Shahada: People enter Islam when they take the shahada&amp;#8211;in other words, when they say certain words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Call of Jahiliyyah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-call-of-jahiliyyah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 17:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-call-of-jahiliyyah/</guid>
      <description>Once a young man from the Muhajiruwn and a young man from the Ansaar quarreled. So the muhajirun called out for help stating: &amp;#8220;O Muhajiruwn!&amp;#8221; And the ansaari said: &amp;#8220;O Ansaar!&amp;#8221; The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) heard this and said: &amp;#8221;Is it with the call off jahiliyyah that you are calling out, and I am present amongst you!&amp;#8221; (Bukhari)
Allah loves Muhajiruwn and Ansaar. Allah states (interpretation of the meaning) : &amp;#8220;And [those Allah grants mercy on includes] the first to embrace Islam from the Muhajiruwn and the Ansaar, and those who followed them in goodness, beliefs and actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract the Honey, but do not Break the Hive</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/extract-the-honey-but-do-not-break-the-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 00:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/extract-the-honey-but-do-not-break-the-hive/</guid>
      <description>The following is an excerpt from &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t be Sad&amp;#8221; by Shaykh Aaidh ibn Abdullah Al-Qarni.
Extract the Honey, but do not break the Hive  Everything that has gentleness within it is beautified, and whatever lacks it is spoiled. When you meet someone, giving them a bright smile and a kind word, you are displaying a characteristic of the truly successful person, a characteristic that even a bee exhibits. When a bee lands on a flower (doing so for a practical purpose) it does not destroy it, because Allah rewards gentleness with that which He does give for harshness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules of Engagement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Rules of Engagement  Rules of Engagement is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad ibn Faqih. The course teaches and emphasizes ethics, morality, rights, character attributes, and manners&amp;#8211;everything from the rights of children before they&amp;#8217;re born to the cause for the decline and destruction of socieities to the literally dozens of virtues one earns from sabr! The course focuses a lot on self-development, self-improvement, and dealing with others, as well as improving oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Mortem Parental Rights</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/post-mortem-parental-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 01:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/post-mortem-parental-rights/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so you parents have rights upon you while they live. Most of us know that. What about after they&amp;#8217;ve left this life? Is it possible they might still have some rights due from you?
The answer is a resounding yes! Their rights, after they die, are:
 Janaazah: That you (or someone in the community) washes their body, buries them, etc., and you pray their janaazah prayer with the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing on Behalf of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 12:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Never, ever, EVER say such-and-such is haram/halal/fard/etc. without knowledge. To say so, is to sign on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). And who dares to do that without knowledge? This is the job of the mujtahiduwn &amp;#8212; those who research fiqh issues and then issue fatawa. Notice, the best of them always say, &amp;#8220;this is the final ruling, and Allah knows best.&amp;#8221; Why? Because they are signing on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parental Appreciation 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/parental-appreciation-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2006 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/parental-appreciation-101/</guid>
      <description>Want to appreciate your parents more? Maybe give them the respect and honour they really deserve? Here&amp;#8217;s an easy way to do it!
Have you ever been in a position where someone did you a really big favour&amp;#8211;big to you, anyway&amp;#8211;and you really, really appreciated it? Think back in your life. Chances are you thanked the person a lot for days after it&amp;#8211;and, what&amp;#8217;s more, you changed the way you treated them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Umar and the Eloquent Woman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, in a long hadith: &amp;#8220;A believer should speak good or keep silent!&amp;#8221; We all know this hadith, right?
But how do we implement this hadith? What if someone does something wrong? What if they deprive us of our rights? Should we still keep silent, or give them 80 lashes with our tongues?
Check this out&amp;#8211;this incident ocurred during the life of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), second Khalifa of Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burnt Food: An Opportunity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/burnt-food-an-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 19:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/burnt-food-an-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>Common reactions among many types of people when their spouse burns their food, or forgets the salt, or oversalts, or otherwise destroys it, are statements such as &amp;#8220;what&amp;#8217;s wrong with you, don&amp;#8217;t you know how to cook&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;didn&amp;#8217;t your mother/father ever teach you anything&amp;#8221; and so on.
Remain patient, as the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) remained when his wives cooked food he didn&amp;#8217;t like. He sat, and said nothing at all, nor did he eat from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>