<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tahara on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/tahara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tahara on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 18:47:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/tahara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Mursal Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 18:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</guid>
      <description>In the sciences of hadith, there&amp;#8217;s something called a &amp;#8220;mursal&amp;#8221; hadith. What exactly is a mursal hadith? What is it&amp;#8217;s status? What are the fiqh rulings on mursal ahadith? And why does it matter?
(Ok, for the answer to the last question, read and learn about the science of hadith. In a sentence: Scholars have devised an extremely rigorous process to determine which hadith are authentic, and which are not. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to spend your whole life following a &amp;#8220;hadith,&amp;#8221; only to find out it really wasn&amp;#8217;t legit, do you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Peace</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Sitting in a halaqah–in a khutbah–in an AlMaghrib class, learning about the deen of Allah– the emanrush, your heart just flutters with tranquility. With satisfaction. With humility. With peace.
Why do we only feel this way in these gatherings?
Allah azza wa jal provides the answer:
He says in Surah Ra’d ayah 28:الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ وَتَطْمَئِنُّ قُلُوبُهُم بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ أَلاَ بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ تَطْمَئِنُّ الْقُلُوب
Those who have believed and whose hearts find satisfaction in the remembrance of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Alcohol Najas?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 12:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/is-alcohol-najas/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;#8220;khamr&amp;#8221; in Arabic refers to intoxicants (in general), but also specifically to alcohol. We all know drinking alcohol is haraam&amp;#8211;but is alcohol itself najas? People use alcohol in medicine, in lens-cleaners, even in foods. What have scholars said about this?
Summary: Allahu &amp;#8216;alim, both sides&amp;#8211;those that say alcohol is najas, and those that don&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8211;have strong proofs. Having said that, all four madhahib say alcohol is najas. The main proof&amp;#8211;and there are a few proofs&amp;#8211;is the ayah:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusing Purification Water</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 09:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/reusing-purification-water/</guid>
      <description>Can you re-use water used for purification&amp;#8211;wudoo or ghusl? This issue doesn&amp;#8217;t apply to most people unless they&amp;#8217;re stuck somewhere without much water&amp;#8211;like Cambodia, where they get water once a year, during flood season, and keep it for nine months.
(Before you read this, read about the three-fold categorization of water; in summary, water can either be purifying (tuhoor), pure (taahir), or impure (najas), and we can only use purifying water for wudoo and ghusl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utensils and Vessels</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/utensils-and-vessels/</guid>
      <description>What utensils and vessels (called inaa&amp;#8217; in Arabic, which includes cups, plates, utensils, and the like&amp;#8211;though we&amp;#8217;ll call it &amp;#8220;utensils&amp;#8221; for simplicity) are halal to eat from? This is important&amp;#8211;your du&amp;#8217;a is at stake! If you eat from haraam, Allah will not accept your du&amp;#8217;a.
Scholars agree that all utensils made from pure and clean things&amp;#8211;other then silver and gold, because we&amp;#8217;re prohibited from eating from those&amp;#8211;are pure and clean. So throw out your silverware, even if it&amp;#8217;s only partially silver; gold plating is not allowed, either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Purity and the Qur’an</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/my-purity-and-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/my-purity-and-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>Use the following chart as a quick reference
  Type   Description   Can I recite from memory?   Can I touch a mushaf?   Comments     Menstruation   The periodic blood that flows as a discharge from womens body   Ok according to stronger opinion.   No     There is another opinion that forbids reciting Qur&amp;#8217;an during menstruation   May read Qur&amp;#8217;an that is printed with tafseer/ translation (given that the non-Qur&amp;#8217;anic text is more than the Qur&amp;#8217;anic text)   May read Qur&amp;#8217;an from the computer screen       Janaba   The state of a person after sexual discharge, whether it was due to intercourse, an erotic dream or anything else   No   No   You can touch a mushaf (a copy of the Qur&amp;#8217;an &amp;#8212; more Arabic then anything else) if there&amp;#8217;s something in between you and it, such as a cloth     Minor Impurity   The state of a person after wudoo is broken   Yes   No   There is another opinion that allows touching a mushaf in this state    There are differences of opinion in some of these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purification Act</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 10:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</guid>
      <description>The Purification Act  The Purification Act is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Abdul-Bary Yahya. If you think you know wudoo, think again! This course teaches you the ins and outs of tahara (purity and purification) and salaah (prayer)&amp;#8211;everything from whether one adhaan or two is more correct, to the proper way to purify dog-slobber from your best china, to whether a pigskin football (or for that matter, a leather jacket) is najas or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sock-Wiping Test</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-sock-wiping-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 02:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-sock-wiping-test/</guid>
      <description>Stuck with only a chest-high sink for wudoo? Maybe you feel really tired and just want to make wudoo quickly so you can pray and sleep?
Then you&amp;#8217;re in luck! Pass this quick test, and you can just wipe over your socks for wudoo!
 Wudooified feet: Were you in a state of purity (post-wudoo) before you put on your socks? Permanent socks: Did you leave your socks on after losing wudoo?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>