<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gems on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/gems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gems on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 16:29:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/gems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Caller Footsteps</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

 “There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.” [33:21].
 No matter what stage of life we are going through, or whatever roles we are trying to fill: be it be as father, husband, son, friend, leader and others, we will always find guidance in the life of our beloved Prophet(peace be upon him).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 – Manners of Sneezing and Yawning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 16:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
 This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. In the last post, we talked about the manners of sleeping. In this post, we will look at the Sunnahs of sneezing and yawning:
 Narrated Abu Huraira: The Prophet said, &amp;ldquo;Allah loves sneezing but dislikes yawning; so if anyone of you sneezes and then praises Allah, every Muslim who hears him (praising Allah) has to say Tashmit to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Siwaak a Day</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/a-siwaak-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 17:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/a-siwaak-a-day/</guid>
      <description>This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. I hope everyone had emaan rushed Ramadhan and you were able to apply the things we learned in this series.
Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Using Siwak:
 Performing Prayers [Bukhari :: Book 2 :: Volume 13 :: Hadith 12] Entering the house [Aaishah was asked what the Messenger of Allaah (peace and blessings of Allaah be upon him) did when he first came home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Uncle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</guid>
      <description>And We have not sent you, [O Muhammad], except as a mercy to the worlds. [21:107]
In the last post, we looked at how our beloved prophet (SAW) set for us an excellent example as a father. Inshallah, continuing with the theme, in this post, we will explore two more roles: **uncle and the master.
**
Treatment with niece
 After the Taif Campaign, one of the captives As-Shaima, the daughter of Al-Harith As-Sadiya, the Messenger’s foster sister was brought to the Messenger of Allah (peace be upon him) , she introduced herself to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beautiful Qualities of Yahya alayhi salam</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 15:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/the-beautiful-qualities-of-yahya-alayhi-salam/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Allah subhaanhu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (the meaning of which is):
 &amp;#8220;(It was said to his son): &amp;#8220;O Yahya (John)! Hold fast the Scripture [the Taurat (Torah)].&amp;#8221; And We gave him wisdom while yet a child. And (made him) sympathetic to men as a mercy (or a grant) from Us, and pure from sins [i.e. Yahya (John)] and he was righteous, and dutiful towards his parents, and he was neither an arrogant nor disobedient (to Allah or to his parents).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 15:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-3/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Continuing in the ten ways to achieve the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, here are the last five points as per ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallauh:
 Sixth, observing Allaah’s kindness, goodness and bounties, both hidden and open.
 It is to be aware of the vast amounts of Mercy Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala has engulfed His slaves with. It is to recognize and accept the blessings of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala and to show thanks for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 15:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Here are ten ways to attain the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, as per Ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallah:
 First, reciting the Qur’an while pondering over its meanings and what is meant by it.
 Allah says, the meaning of which is: &amp;#8220;Then do they not reflect upon the Qur&amp;#8217;an? If it had been from [any] other than Allah , they would have found within it much contradiction&amp;#8221; [4:82]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
We live this life yearning to be amongst those whom Allah loves. On top of that, we wish and pray that Allah gives us the opportunity to be amonst the blessed who sincerly love Him. Truly, this only comes from His Will and we should beg him for that opportunity day and night.
Here is a a beautiful du&amp;#8217;a that we have been taught by the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Father</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 03:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.&amp;#8221; [33:21]
Inshallah in this post and in future posts, we will be looking at seerah. We will look at how the prophet (SAW) set an excellent example for us in different roles; be it be as a husband, father, friend, leader and other such roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanking Allah in times of a Calamity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 15:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/thanking-allah-in-times-of-a-calamity/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Umer radhiAllah anhu used to say:
 &amp;#8220;If Allah strikes me with calamity I will thank Allah for four things: 1) that the test was not in my deen 2) the calamity could have been worse 3) it is an expiation for my sins 4) any loss after losing the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam is nothing”
 The greatest man that lived after the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam and Abu Bakr as-Siddiq radhiAllah anhu, Umer ibn al-Khattab radhiAllah anhu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness – Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</guid>
      <description>ALLAH IS AS HE DESCRIBES HIMSELF WITH NO ADDITIONS BEYOND WHICH WE DO NOT PONDER NOR PUT CONDITIONS
Continuing in our explanation of the poem and our discussion of the branches tawheed, we now move into the second branch which is the oneness, uniqueness, and exclusiveness of Allah’s Names and Attributes (tawheed al-asma was-sifat). There are five points we will discuss; three points in this post and the remaining two in the next post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness: Poem with Explanation – Part 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-poem-with-explanation-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 03:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-poem-with-explanation-part-1/</guid>
      <description>ALLAH, THE LORD OF THE HEAVENS AND THE EARTH
THE CREATOR, SUSTAINER, ABOVE GIVING BIRTH
ALLAH IS AS HE DESCRIBES HIMSELF WITH NO ADDITIONS
BEYOND WHICH WE DO NOT PONDER NOR PUT CONDITIONS
HE IS ALLAH, THE MOST HIGH WHO DOES NOT SLEEP
NOR DOES HIS CREATION TAKE PART IN HIS MAJESTY
IT IS ALLAH ALONE WHO IS WORTHY OF WORSHIP
A STATEMENT OF TRUTH REVEALED TO THE MUSHRIKS  &amp;#8220;ALLAH, THE LORD OF THE HEAVENS AND THE EARTH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Four Priorities of the Muslim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</guid>
      <description>Abu Barzah al-Aslami radi Allahu anhu reported that Allah’s Messenger sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, “The two feet of the servant will not cease (from standing before Allah) on the Day of Judgment until he is asked about four things: on his life and how he spent it; on his knowledge and what he did with it; on his wealth and where he earned it and how he spent it; and on his body and in what way he utilized it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Not Despair? Reflections on Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</guid>
      <description>Why not despair? The Islamic meaning of sabr is to stop ourselves from despairing and panicking, to stop our tongues from complaining, and to stop our hands from striking our faces and tearing our clothes at times of grief and stress.
To have _sabr_ is to first realize within your own heart that a) there is a god that exists b) that this god is worthy of all my worship c) that this god is indeed characterized by attributes of perfectness and majesty, which can only be ascribed to god and no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ins and Outs of Halloween</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-ins-and-outs-of-halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 19:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-ins-and-outs-of-halloween/</guid>
      <description>So who&amp;#8217;s down for a party this Saturday? Let&amp;#8217;s do it! Meet at the closest masjid near your house at 7:45pm. Forget about these kiddish Halloween parties, be a person of dignity and honour, be amongst the party of Allah.
وَيُدْخِلُهُمْ جَنَّاتٍ تَجْرِي مِن تَحْتِهَا الْأَنْهَارُ خَالِدِينَ فِيهَا رَضِيَ اللَّهُ عَنْهُمْ وَرَضُوا عَنْهُ أُوْلَئِكَ حِزْبُ اللَّهِ أَلَا إِنَّ حِزْبَ اللَّهِ هُمُ الْمُفْلِحُونَ  And We will admit them to gardens beneath which rivers flow, wherein they abide eternally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Tawbah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 22:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/benefits-of-tawbah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
This is a translation from the original article in Arabic.
1- It is a cause to receive the Love of Allah azza wa jal. The Most High says:
إِنَّ اللَّهَ يُحِبُّ التَّوَّابِينَ وَيُحِبُّ الْمُتَطَهِّرِينَ Truly, Allah loves those who turn unto Him in repentance and loves those who purify themselves. (2:222)
2- It is a cause of success. The Most High says:
وَتُوبُوا إِلَى اللَّهِ جَمِيعًا أَيُّهَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ لَعَلَّكُمْ تُفْلِحُونَ  And all of you beg Allah to forgive you, O believers, that you may be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 01:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</guid>
      <description>Below is a fantastic presentation on Eid, based on the sunnah. It outlines the dos and don&amp;#8217;ts of Eid. Learn it, share it, and enjoy!
Eid mubarak to you and your families, on behalf of Ilm Fruits!
SWF from: http://www.outstandingmuslim.com/Eid101/engage.html </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naseeha From Our Brother Sa’ad Gaya</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/naseeha-from-our-brother-saad-gaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 20:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/naseeha-from-our-brother-saad-gaya/</guid>
      <description>Below is some naseeha from our brother, Sa&amp;#8217;ad Gaya. Sa&amp;#8217;ad was one of those 18 individuals thrown in jail as part of the &amp;#8220;Toronto 18 terrorist plot.&amp;#8221; Despite evidence that the entire plot was spurred by a CSIS mole, despite an increasing lack of any credible evidence, several of these 18 brothers are still languishing in a jail cell.
  My Dear Brothers and Sisters,
I write these words not as one who has any superiority over you , whether in knowledge or deeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things” that Loved the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
عن انس قال النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏لا يؤمن ‏ ‏أحدكم حتى أكون أحب إليه من والده وولده والناس أجمعين ‏ 
Anas radi Allahu anhu narrated that the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, &amp;#8220;None of you truly believes (has emaan) until I am more beloved to him than his father, his child and all of mankind.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Loving the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam is a part of emaan, and Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala has made it obligatory for us to love the Messenger alayhi salaam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qur’an vs Kitaab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 01:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/quran-vs-kitaab/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
The two most common names for the Book of Allah are: Qur&amp;#8217;an and Kitaab.
We learn when studying the Qur&amp;#8217;an that even the words chosen are a revelation from Allah with divine wisdom. So, in that case, what do these two names mean and what is the difference between them?
The word &amp;#8216;Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8217; is said to be from two roots, one of them qaaf-ra-hamza, this root qara&amp;#8217;a means to recite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reasons Behind Seasons</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Why did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) create seasons? All of this&amp;#8211;snow, leaves changing, hot summer days and freezing winter nights. In some countries&amp;#8211;like Canada, and the US&amp;#8211;you have places where Isha time starts around 11pm, or 12am (midnight), and Fajr starts arond 2-3am! You also have days where Isha starts at 6pm, and Fajr starts around 7am.
What can we learn from this?
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) gives this away when he narrates: &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) made the night short so you can pray, and the day short so you can fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking News</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/breaking-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 22:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/breaking-news/</guid>
      <description>The news is out. Its a BIG one. Media won&amp;#8217;t broadcast it. People wouldn&amp;#8217;t talk about it. The most deadly serial killer is out after a month of imprisonment. He is back to take the revenge. He could in in your neighbourhood right now. To make it worse, he could be in your house with you eating and drinking right now! He is very dedicated, clever, motivated and doesn&amp;#8217;t leave behind any traces!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ismul Jalaalah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Ismul Jalaalah, The Grand Name: Allah الله. This is Allah&amp;#8217;s Personal Name. His Identifying Name. This Name only belongs to Allah, no one else can have besides Allah. Allah is the Title, the Name, of the One True Ilaah. The Name of Allah, you cannot play around with: there is no plural, there is no feminine. The Name Allah appears over 3000 times in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
When we mentioned the Name &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221; linguistically, we don&amp;#8217;t say &amp;#8220;the word Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the Name Allah&amp;#8221; because it is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Receive Allah’s Special Mercy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/how-to-receive-allahs-special-mercy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 01:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/how-to-receive-allahs-special-mercy/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
We know that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala Name&amp;#8217;s Ar-Raheem is specifically for the believers, so how is it that one can receive this special Mercy from ar Raheem?
 Obedience to Allah and His Messenger. &amp;#8220;and obey Allah and His Messenger so that you all may receive Mercy.&amp;#8221; [3:132]   Taqwa of Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala, fear and consciousness of Allah. &amp;#8220;And this is a book, We have sent it down as one blessed, so follow it and fear Allah so that you all may receive Mercy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an is Mubaarak</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-quran-is-mubaarak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 11:17:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-quran-is-mubaarak/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah subhanahu wa ta’ala says in Surah Saad verse 29,كِتَابٌ أَنْزَلْنَاهُ إِلَيْكَ مُبَارَكٌ لِيَدَّبَّرُوا آيَاتِهِ وَلِيَتَذَكَّرَ أُولُو الأَلْبَابِ  “(This is) a Mubaarak Book which We have sent down to you, that they may reflect upon its signs, and that men of understanding may remember.” (Saad: 38:29)  Mubaarak is that which is full of barakah. And barakah is from the root, ba ra kaaf (ب ر ك), and barakah is that which lasts long and has the ability to increase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Delight</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 03:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
What is the greatest gift you could ever receive? That you could ever want? That would bring you the greatest happiness and delight?&amp;#8230;..Think about it.
Got an idea? &amp;#8230;.good.
Most of us will be thinking of Jannah and all of its delights. But the most pleasurable thing in Jannah is not having spouses, or servants that will serve you, or drinking milk and honey. No rather, there is something MUCH GREATER for the Dwellers of Jannah that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala is keeping for them&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubhanAllah: A Pure Negation (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah was-salatu was-salam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam
Continuing in our discussion of the oft-repeated words and phrases in our salat, this week inshallah we will focus on looking at: SubhanAllah
This is another word that is very common in the Muslim&amp;#8217;s vocabulary. We all have heard the word, we all say it in our prayers daily (inshallah), yet how many of us truly understand its meaning?
Commonly this word is translated as, &amp;#8220;Glory be to Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;All Glory is to Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Praise of Perfection (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum,
There are certain words and phrases which we pronounce in our salat repeatedly, yet more than likely we do not know what they mean. This is the state of our salat these days&amp;#8230;nothing more than actions of the limbs. O Muslims! Remember faith (eman) is belief in the heart, statements upon the tongue, and actions of the limbs. All three are required for a completeness of faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Tasbeeh?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 14:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-tasbeeh/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we now know what hamd means, let&amp;#8217;s move on to tasbeeh!
Tasbeeh means to say subhanAllah just as tahmeed means to say alhamdulillah.
  Tasbeeh is comprised of two words: Subhan and Allah: سبحان الله
Subhan which is derived from tasbeeh is from seen-ba-ha (س-ب-ح) and it means to glorify, praise, magnify, extol Allah, by tongue or by heart. It includes:
1-To say He has no flaw in His Perfection Far above any imperfection</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooba!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 01:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah ta’ala says:
الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ طُوبَىٰ لَهُمْ وَحُسْنُ مَآبٍ  Those who have believed and done righteous deeds – ‘Tooba’ is theirs and a good return. (Suratur Ra’ad, ayah 29)
Allah ta’ala promises ‘Tooba’ to the believers in this ayah. We also know this word for the famous hadeeth of the strangers, the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam states: fa Tooba lil ghurabaa’, so Tooba to the strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Hamd?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 22:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
As Muslims, the phrase &amp;#8220;alhamdulillah&amp;#8221; الحمد لله (all praise and thanks is for Allah) is an integral part of our deen; we are taught to say it from both the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah. Linguistically, Hamd is from ha-meem-daal ( حمد or ح م د) and it is to mention the good attribute of a person, such an attribute that is the at the level of perfection. Hamd is based on mahabbah (love) and ta&amp;#8217;dheem (greatness).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Islamic Diet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-islamic-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 21:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-islamic-diet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We are constantly bombarded in this society with diet after diet, new ways to loose weight or supposedly be &amp;#8216;healthy&amp;#8217;. As Muslims, we know that Allah (سبحانه و تعالى) sent the Qur&amp;#8217;an to us as a huda, a guide. Not only is the Qur&amp;#8217;an a guidance for us in our beliefs, our worship and character, but we learn basic lessons on how to live our lives in a way that is pleasing to Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levels of Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 15:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/levels-of-patience/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
Truly, patience is a characteristic of the Muslim that is required on many levels:
 Patience in worshiping Allah Patience in abstaining from wrong actions Patience at times of trials  These are the three levels we should constantly be monitoring, for verily it is these levels of patience that will bring us success. My dear brothers and sisters, Ramadan is only days away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is they who are Guided</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/it-is-they-who-are-guided/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
My dear brothers and sisters in this beautiful religion of Islam, sometimes we have to sit back and ponder about life and ponder about the purpose of it. Sometimes we know the purpose, yet we fall of track due to the play and amusement of this world. Nonetheless, we should never despair of the mercy of our Lord, for verily He is the Most Merciful and Most Forgiving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Peace</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 01:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/find-peace/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Sitting in a halaqah–in a khutbah–in an AlMaghrib class, learning about the deen of Allah– the emanrush, your heart just flutters with tranquility. With satisfaction. With humility. With peace.
Why do we only feel this way in these gatherings?
Allah azza wa jal provides the answer:
He says in Surah Ra’d ayah 28:الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ وَتَطْمَئِنُّ قُلُوبُهُم بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ أَلاَ بِذِكْرِ اللّهِ تَطْمَئِنُّ الْقُلُوب
Those who have believed and whose hearts find satisfaction in the remembrance of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Complain only to Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/i-complain-only-to-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
I start by asking a very simple question: Where does patience stand within our lives today?
SubhanAllah, what a beautiful trait it is yet we rarely see the implementation of it. Such a beautiful tree by which the sweetest of fruits cultivate and bless our lives, yet we just let it slip away as a &amp;#8220;thing of the past&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raging and Roaring</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 23:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:إِذَا رَأَتْهُمْ مِنْ مَكَانٍ بَعِيدٍ سَمِعُوا لَهَا تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِير 
When it sees them from a far place, they will hear its raging and its roaring. Suratul Furqan, verse 12
What is the &amp;#8220;it&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;them&amp;#8221; in this verse referring too? When the hell fire sees the disbelievers. Hell fire will see them from a far place, and they will hear it تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِيرًا , raging with fury and roaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Matter What…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum, Time comes and goes; some people grow, some people remain exactly same throughout time.
وَالْعَصْرِ
By the Time!
إِنَّ الْإِنسَانَ لَفِي خُسْرٍ**_
_** Indeed! Mankind is in loss__
Thus, Allah makes clear that by the passing time man is in complete loss. Why? Because they don&amp;#8217;t take heed, they don&amp;#8217;t learn, they don&amp;#8217;t listen, they go on doing what their hearts desire without thinking twice. They (in general) don&amp;#8217;t ponder about the real purpose of their life; they (in general) cover reality with their false notions and desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reading Light: Importance of Tafseer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 00:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur’an,
كِتَابٌ أَنزَلْنَاهُ إِلَيْكَ مُبَارَكٌ لِّيَدَّبَّرُوا آيَاتِهِ وَلِيَتَذَكَّرَ أُوْلُوا الْأَلْبَابِ  &amp;#8220;(This is) a Book which We have sent down to you, full of blessings, so that they may ponder over its verses, and that men of understanding may remember.” Surah Saad: verse 29.
(linguistic explanation of the word yaddabaroo is in the comments)
It is the science of tafseer which is the fruit of ‘pondering over its verses’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Only …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 14:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/if-only/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Suratul Anbiya:
لَوْ يَعْلَمُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا حِينَ لَا يَكُفُّونَ عَن وُجُوهِهِمُ النَّارَ وَلَا عَن ظُهُورِهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يُنصَرُونَ  Translation: If only those who disbelieved knew when they will not be able to ward off the Fire from their faces, nor from their backs; and they will not be helped. [Surah Suratul Anbiya, verse 39]
The word for ward off is &amp;#8220;yakuffoona&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;يَكُفُّونَ&amp;#8221; and this is from the root word &amp;#8220;ka-fa-fa&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;kaff&amp;#8221; which means palm/hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Do It</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/you-can-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 15:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/you-can-do-it/</guid>
      <description>My brothers and sisters in Islam, know that the Muslim is one who never gives up in anything that he or she does. O People! Know that the one who submits himself to Allah, should never feel like he or she does not have the capabilities to accomplish something.
My brothers and sisters, sometimes we find it difficult to excel in our fields. If you&amp;#8217;re a student &amp;#8212; you may feel that you&amp;#8217;re not able to get that A+ grade, you think to yourself &amp;#8216;I&amp;#8217;m not that smart, I can&amp;#8217;t do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Plans for Friday?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2008 16:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-plans-for-friday/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Check out this hadith:
‏إِنَّ مِنْ أَفْضَلِ أَيَّامِكُمْ يَوْمَ الْجُمُعَةِ فَأَكْثِرُوا عَلَيَّ مِنْ الصَّلاَةِ فِيهِ
فَإِنَّ صَلاَتَكُمْ مَعْرُوضَةٌ عَلَيَّ قَالَ فَقَالُوا يَا رَسُولَ اللَّهِ
وَكَيْفَ تُعْرَضُ صَلاَتُنَا عَلَيْكَ وَقَدْ أَرَمْتَ ‏- ‏قَالَ يَقُولُونَ بَلِيتَ
‏قَالَ إِنَّ اللَّهَ تَبَارَكَ وَتَعَالَى حَرَّمَ عَلَى الأَرْضِ أَجْسَادَ الأَنْبِيَاءِ صَلَّى اللَّهُ عَلَيْهِمْ
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Surely, among the best of your days is Friday; so increase in (invoking Allah&amp;#8217;s) salaat upon me during it, for your (invocations for Allah&amp;#8217;s) Salaat (upon me) will be displayed to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following vs. Obeying</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 15:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/following-vs-obeying/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-e-Imran ayaat 31-32:
قُلْ إِن كُنتُمْ تُحِبُّونَ اللّهَ فَاتَّبِعُونِي يُحْبِبْكُمُ اللّهُ وَيَغْفِرْ لَكُمْ ذُنُوبَكُمْ وَاللّهُ غَفُورٌ رَّحِيمٌ
قُلْ أَطِيعُواْ اللّهَ وَالرَّسُولَ فإِن تَوَلَّوْاْ فَإِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يُحِبُّ الْكَافِرِينَ  Translation: Say: If you should love Allah, then follow me (so) Allah will love you and forgive your sins. And Allah is Al-Ghafuwr (the All-Forgiving), Ar-Raheem (the All-Mericful). Say, Obey Allah and His Messenger. But if you turn away then indeed, Allah does not love the disbelievers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Duaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 20:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-complete-duaa/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
How many times have we heard this duaa in our lives: Rabbana aatina fid-dunya hasanah, wa fil-akhirati hasanah, wa qinaa athaban naar. Have we ever contemplated how complete this duaa is?
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says
فَمِنَ النَّاسِ مَن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا وَمَا لَهُ فِي الآخِرَةِ مِنْ خَلاَقٍ وِمِنْهُم مَّن يَقُولُ رَبَّنَا آتِنَا فِي الدُّنْيَا حَسَنَةً وَفِي الآخِرَةِ حَسَنَةً وَقِنَا عَذَابَ النَّارِ  Translation: And among the people is he who says, &amp;#8220;our Lord, give us in this world,&amp;#8221; and he will have in the Hereafter no share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Parable of Spouses and Garments</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-parable-of-spouses-and-garments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 10:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-parable-of-spouses-and-garments/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) uses amazing parables in the Qur&amp;#8217;an that strike fear, awe and amazement in the hearts of the believers. Throughout the Qur&amp;#8217;an, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) draws parables for us to convey the importance of certain topics, to extract lessons from them and so that we may ponder and reflect over them. We hear many times of the examples of the hypocrites, the mushrikeen (pagans) and the believers. But there is one parable that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) puts forth that increases the love and mercy between a husband and wife, and this parable is one of the most eloquent and striking in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth’s Fill in Gold</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earths-weight-in-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2007 19:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earths-weight-in-gold/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُواْ وَمَاتُواْ وَهُمْ كُفَّارٌ فَلَن يُقْبَلَ مِنْ أَحَدِهِم مِّلْءُ الأرْضِ ذَهَبًا وَلَوِ افْتَدَى بِهِ أُوْلَـئِكَ لَهُمْ عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌ وَمَا لَهُم مِّن نَّاصِرِينَ  Translation: Indeed, those who disbelieve and die while they are disbelievers &amp;#8211; never would the [whole] capacity of the earth in gold be accepted from one of them if he would [seek to] ransom himself with it. For those there will be a painful punishment, and they will have no helpers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Museebah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 12:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/what-is-a-museebah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in Surah Al-Baqarah:
وَلَنَبْلُوَنَّكُمْ بِشَيْءٍ مِّنَ الْخَوْفِ وَالْجُوعِ وَنَقْصٍ مِّنَ الأَمْوَالِ وَالأنفُسِ وَالثَّمَرَاتِ وَبَشِّرِ الصَّابِرِينَ
الَّذِينَ إِذَا أَصَابَتْهُم مُّصِيبَةٌ قَالُواْ إِنَّا لِلّهِ وَإِنَّا إِلَيْهِ رَاجِعونَ  Translation: And We shall surely test you with something of fear and hunger and a loss of wealth and lives and fruits, but give good tidings to the patient. Those who when disaster strikes them, say, &amp;#8220;Indeed we belong to Allah and indeed to Him we will return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizq Without Measure</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2007 20:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-without-measure/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
كُلَّمَا دَخَلَ عَلَيْهَا زَكَرِيَّا الْمِحْرَابَ وَجَدَ عِندَهَا رِزْقاً قَالَ يَا مَرْيَمُ أَنَّى لَكِ هَذَا قَالَتْ هُوَ مِنْ عِندِ اللّهِ إِنَّ اللّهَ يَرْزُقُ مَن يَشَاءُ بِغَيْرِ حِسَابٍ  هُنَالِكَ دَعَا زَكَرِيَّا رَبَّهُ قَالَ رَبِّ هَبْ لِي مِن لَّدُنْكَ ذُرِّيَّةً طَيِّبَةً إِنَّكَ سَمِيعُ الدُّعَاءِ  Translation: Every time he entered Al-Mihrab to her, he found her supplied with sustenance. He said: &amp;#8220;O Maryam (Mary)! From where have you got this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words beginning with Fa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/words-beginning-with-fa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2007 14:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/words-beginning-with-fa/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Learning Arabic as a second language may be difficult for many, so I decided to share some tips that assist with learning the meanings of words and their structures.
Words that begin with ف usually will always mean something that breaks open, separates, or breaks apart. Check out these examples:
الفجر (Al-Fajr) from ف ج ر means the dawn, but it literally means when the daylight breaks/crack through the darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness in Front of your Eyes</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/happiness-in-front-of-your-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2007 11:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/happiness-in-front-of-your-eyes/</guid>
      <description>Time comes and goes, life slips and goes forth, what is to come? No creation knows.
Sometimes, things (سبحانه وتعالى) takes it away, because in His infinite Wisdom it is something which is not good for you. However, what is to say that same thing is not good for you later in life? Time can go by, a jewel can accumulate dust, but with a blow of the mouth and a brush of the hands, it sparkles like new just as it was before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charity – Where to Give</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/charity-where-to-give/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2007 14:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/charity-where-to-give/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I have already donated enough to masajids. I want to help the needy, poor, orphans and widows. Its so hard to find these people here in the west. Back home, it was so easy.&amp;#8221; This is the typical problem that many of us face.
So if you are wondering, how and where should I spend my charity, follow these six steps:
 Niyah Check: Make sure that you are only doing it for Allah, not to please anyone else or get praised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abu Bakr and His Request</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 08:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</guid>
      <description>What do you make of the amazing incident when the best of the sahaba (رضالله عنه) came to the best of the Prophets (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to ask for a du&amp;#8217;a to make in his prayers?
 Narrated Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه) I asked Allah&amp;#8217;s Apostle (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to teach me an invocation so that I may invoke Allah with it in my prayer. He told me to say, [Sahih Bukhari]  (Hover your mouse over each line to see the translation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Guarantees of Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/three-guarantees-of-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2007 22:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/three-guarantees-of-paradise/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;I guarantee a house in Jannah (Paradise) for one who gives up arguing, even if he is in the right; and I guarantee a house in the middle of Jannah for one who abandons lying even when joking / for the sake of fun; and I guarantee a house in the highest part of Jannah for one who has good manners.&amp;#8221; [Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) &amp;#8211; reported by Imam Abu Dawud]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Dignity</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/protect-your-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2007 08:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/protect-your-dignity/</guid>
      <description>With the Facebook craze that has struck us all in the past months, we have forgotten about a very serious matter that our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسل) talked about, and that matter being exposing of ones sins. We post messages on peoples walls, we post up pictures and what not, and its all exposing our sins to the public. We should be very cautious of the environment and inshallah try our best to protect our own dignity but also the dignity and respect of our brothers and sisters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typical</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2007 08:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/typical/</guid>
      <description>Typ‧i‧cal: Conforming to a particular type. For someone to be &amp;#8220;typical&amp;#8221;, he/she would be one who conforms to his society and behaves much like his environment.
Typical in the 21st century: clubbing, flirting, sex, drugs, alcohol, stealing, cheating, swearing, injustice, premarital relations, immodesty, and the list goes on and on.
So who&amp;#8217;s typical? Is it the one who refrains from all the above, or the one indulges in it? Is it the one who&amp;#8217;s perceived weird when he speaks out against someone swearing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speak Good or Stay Silent</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/speak-good-or-stay-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2007 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/speak-good-or-stay-silent/</guid>
      <description>Abu Hurayrah relates that Allah’s Messenger (peace be upon him) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should speak a good word or remain silent. And whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should show hospitality to his neighbor. And whoever believes in Allah and the Last Day should show hospitality to his guest.&amp;#8221; [Sahih al-Bukhari and Sahih Muslim]
_Speak good, or stay silent
Treat your guest, and don’t be violent</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Minute at a Time</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-minute-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 03:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-minute-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>Everybody wants to read the Qur&amp;#8217;an more&amp;#8211;and why not? The Word of Allah, no less&amp;#8211;unfiltered, unmodified, eternal; guidance for the entire planet. Yet many of us&amp;#8211;even Arabs, who understand and have no problems reading and reciting&amp;#8211;procrastinate and put off reading the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
So try this inshaAllah: every day, read and recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an for at least one minute. Try it. I mean, one minute is hardly time enough to do anything&amp;#8211;so you have no excuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance That Benefits</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/inheritance-that-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 06:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/inheritance-that-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Death. It&amp;#8217;s inevitable. It&amp;#8217;s one of the certainties of life. No one denies it and no one can escape it. And once you&amp;#8217;re dead, your good deeds stop. Except in the following ways:
Abu Hurayrah (رضالله عنه) reported that Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;When a human being dies, all of his deeds are TERMINATED, except for three types:
 An ongoing charity (aka sadaqah jariyah)
 A knowledge (of Islam) from which others benefit,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path of Goodness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-path-of-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2007 00:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-path-of-goodness/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعال) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
فَأَمَّا مَن أَعْطَى وَاتَّقَى
وَصَدَّقَ بِالْحُسْنَى
فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْيُسْرَى
وَأَمَّا مَن بَخِلَ وَاسْتَغْنَى
وَكَذَّبَ بِالْحُسْنَى
فَسَنُيَسِّرُهُ لِلْعُسْرَى
وَمَا يُغْنِي عَنْهُ مَالُهُ إِذَا تَرَدَّى
إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا لَلْهُدَى
وَإِنَّ لَنَا لَلْآخِرَةَ وَالْأُولَى  Translation: &amp;#8220;So for him who gives in charity, fears Allah, and testifies to goodness, We shall facilitate for him the Path of good. As for him who is stingy and considers himself independent of Allah and rejects the goodness, We shall facilitate for him the Path to evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Nature is Insatiable</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 02:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/human-nature-is-insatiable/</guid>
      <description>Human Nature is Insatiable  Human nature is insatiable. No matter how much you get, you will never be happy with it. That is the way we have been created. The key to happiness is not to get it all, but rather, to be content with little.
&amp;#8220;O Allah, I seek refuge in Thee from incapacity, from sloth, from cowardice, from miserliness, from decrepitude, and from the torment of the grave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule Around Salaah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/schedule-around-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2007 03:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/schedule-around-salaah/</guid>
      <description>Not enough time to do what you want in life? Are you over-worked, over-stressed, and over-tired? Looking for that one key element that&amp;#8217;ll make everything fall into place time-wise?
Schedule around salaah. Try it&amp;#8211;plan your day around your salaah. &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ll do x, y, z after Fajr.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;I can fit these things in before Dhur &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Sorry bro, I can&amp;#8217;t meet up until after Isha&amp;#8221; etc.
And see the difference it makes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadhaa Kitaabun vs. Haadhal Kitaabu</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/hadhaa-kitaabun-vs-haadhal-kitaabu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 02:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/hadhaa-kitaabun-vs-haadhal-kitaabu/</guid>
      <description>One question that plagues many new students of the Arabic language is the difference between hadhaa kitaabun and hadhaal kitaabu &amp;#8230;
The difference is best demonstrated by example: hadhaa kitaabun kabiyrun means &amp;#8220;this is a big book,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hadhaal kitaabul kabiyru&amp;#8221; means &amp;#8220;this big book &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
Get the difference? The first (hadhaa kitaabun) is talking about any book. &amp;#8220;This is a book.&amp;#8221; Nothing special. The second&amp;#8211;hadhaal kitaabu&amp;#8211;is talking about a specific book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distance of One Mile</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</guid>
      <description>In a very beautiful hadith, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: __
 “There are seven whom Allah will shade in His Shade on the Day when there is no shade except His Shade:
 a just ruler; a youth who grew up in the worship of Allah, the Mighty and Majestic; a man whose heart is attached to the mosques; two men who love each other for Allah’s sake, meeting for that and parting upon that; a man who is called by a woman of beauty and position [for illegal intercourse], but be says: ‘I fear Allah’; a man who gives in charity and hides it, such that his left hand does not know what his right hand gives in charity; and a man who remembered Allah in private and so his eyes shed tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearer of Beautiful Fragrance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/bearer-of-beautiful-fragrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 05:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/bearer-of-beautiful-fragrance/</guid>
      <description>In the fast-paced world we live in, we often lose the righteousness needed to attain the closeness to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) that we desire. We go through constant struggles, fighting with ourselves to do what is good and to stay on The Straight Path. At times we prosper and succeed, but much of the time, we lose the fight, but why? Why do we succumb to the temptations of this world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</guid>
      <description>Innal-Hamdu lillah was-Salaatu was-Salaam `alaa Rasoolillah
&amp;ldquo;Lucky escape &amp;hellip; hmmm &amp;hellip; Nah! It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t my time to go yet; Allah saved me and gave me a little longer &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Driving home from work after having a late staff meeting, it was an ordinary evening not much traffic on the road. I got onto the dual carriage, I was in the right lane doing around 60-70 miles an hour, then all of a sudden *BANG* the bonnet of my car flew open and smashed against my car windscreen, *SMASH* all the glass cracked and from the great impact, my back view mirror had completely broken off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatness of Ayat al-Kursi</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-greatness-of-ayat-al-kursi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 04:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-greatness-of-ayat-al-kursi/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
اللَّهُ لاَ إِلَهَ~َ إِلاَّ هُوَ الْحَيُّ الْقَيُّومُ لاَ تَأْخُذُه ُُ سِنَة ٌ وَلاَ نَوْم ٌ لَه ُُ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الأَرْضِ مَنْ ذَا الَّذِي يَشْفَعُ عِنْدَهُ~ُ إِلاَّ بِإِذْنِه ِِ يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أَيْدِيهِمْ وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ وَلاَ يُحِيطُونَ بِشَيْء ٍ مِنْ عِلْمِهِ~ِ إِلاَّ بِمَا شَاءَ وَسِعَ كُرْسِيُّهُ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالأَرْضَ وَلاَ يَئُودُه ُُ حِفْظُهُمَا وَهُوَ الْعَلِيُّ الْعَظِيمُ  &amp;#8220;Allah! There is no god but He,-the Living, the Self-Subsisting, Eternal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Step Towards Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/take-a-step-towards-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2007 02:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/take-a-step-towards-allah/</guid>
      <description>So, do you want to enter Jannah? Think about it for a second.
OK, that was an easy one. Here&amp;#8217;s a more difficult question, how do you plan on getting there? Take your time and think about that one.
That thinking in and of itself will help you get to Jannah, inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) will make the path easier for those who sincerely desire to come closer to Him and find ways to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a Witness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/you-are-a-witness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2007 02:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/you-are-a-witness/</guid>
      <description>Humankind is witness to the blessings that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) has bestowed upon them, yet they look the other way. Humankind is witness to the world and everything in it, yet they deny the very Creator of it. Subhanallah.
Narrated Abu Hurairah (رضي الله عنه): The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) said: &amp;#8216;The son of Adam tells a lie against Me, though he hasn&amp;#8217;t the right to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control? I Don’t Think So.</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/control-i-dont-think-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2006 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/control-i-dont-think-so/</guid>
      <description>Do you control your eyes? If so, then stop yourself from blinking. Do you control your heart? If so, then stop yourself from feeling. Do you control your brain? If so, then stop yourself from thinking.
Can’t do it, can you? If we’re not in control then who is?
Who else besides Al-Khaliq, The Creator &amp;#8212; Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)
Reality Check … this dunya is not what it percieves to be, so next time we think we got things under control, we should think again, because more than likely we don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Your Intentions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/watch-your-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 19:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/watch-your-intentions/</guid>
      <description>There are many times throughout our daily activities that we do things without clarifying the intention to ourselves. We may buy a new car but end up doing it to raise our status in society or for pride. At the same time though, we may buy a car and do it solely for Allah&amp;#8217;s cause, and in this there is good. Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
&amp;#8220;So whomsoever does good equal to the wieght of an atom (or a small ant), shall see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Severe Consequence</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-severe-consequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 03:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-severe-consequence/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Be not like those who forgot Allah, as a result Allah caused them to forget themselves, it is they who are the transgressors&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8211; Surah Hashr V.19 A very powerful ayah in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, very powerful indeed for those who ponder and reflect upon the words of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). This one ayah speaks to many amongst our ummah in this day and age at the same time shows us the results of their doings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imam Abu Hanifa: A True Tradesman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2006 11:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/imam-abu-hanifa-a-true-tradesman/</guid>
      <description>Once, a women came to Abu Hanifa (رحمالله) to sell a silk garment. Abu Hanifa asked &amp;#8221; How much is it?&amp;#8221; She replied, &amp;#8220;one hundred.&amp;#8221; He said, &amp;#8220;It is worth more than a hundred. How much?&amp;#8221;
So the woman increased the price by hundred, and again, and when it reached four hundred, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;It should be more than that.&amp;#8221; The woman said, &amp;#8221; you are mocking me.&amp;#8221;
So, Abu Hanifa said, &amp;#8220;bring a man to value it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money, Power, Respect</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/money-power-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 16:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/money-power-respect/</guid>
      <description>How do we attain money, power, and respect?
The path is easy, you follow the way of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and the commands of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), then inshallah you will attain the money, the power, and the respect. Now it is up to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) whether He blesses you with such things. However, with sincerity in your actions, the chances are high.
The overlying goal is to keep Islam in your heart; thrive for it, live to please Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), do all your actions in accordance to the sunnah, and follow the commands of The Al-Mighty, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Defined</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/family-defined/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 02:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/family-defined/</guid>
      <description>After years of dawah the people of Nuh (عليه سلام), Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) revealed to Nuh (عليه سلام) (interpretation of the meaning) &amp;#8220;None of thy people will believe except those who have believed already! So grieve no longer over their (evil) deeds.&amp;#8221; (Surah Hud, verse 35)
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) instructed Nuh (عليه سلام) to build an ark, and that the sinners will drown in a flood. As Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) states in Qur&amp;#8217;an (to the interpretation of the meaning): &amp;#8220;But construct an Ark under Our eyes and Our inspiration, and address Me no (further) on behalf of those who are in sin: for they are about to be overwhelmed (in the Flood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe and Beautify Your Writing</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/observe-and-beautify-your-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 16:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/observe-and-beautify-your-writing/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who regularly write Arabic (and, incidentally, you can generalize this to any language inshallah), you might look at your writing and say, &amp;#8220;man, that is ugggggleeeeeee!&amp;#8221;
So how do you go about beautifying it? The key here is that you can recognize nice Arabic writing when you see it&amp;#8211;and I don&amp;#8217;t mean calligraphy.
The solution is surprisingly simple. Grab a mushaf (or, if you have them, one of the three Medinah University Arabic books), Apply your observational skills, and you can easily inshallah detect a few clues on how to improve (or even how to write them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maryam of the Qanitiyn</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/maryam-of-the-qanitiyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/maryam-of-the-qanitiyn/</guid>
      <description>Inshallah what follows is a small gem from the Qur&amp;#8217;an about Maryam (عليها سلام), mother of &amp;#8216;Isa (عليه سلام).
At the end of Surah Tahrim, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَمَرْيَمَ ابْنَتَ عِمْرَانَ الَّتِي أَحْصَنَتْ فَرْجَهَا فَنَفَخْنَا فِيهِ مِن رُّوحِنَا وَصَدَّقَتْ بِكَلِمَاتِ رَبِّهَا وَكُتُبِهِ وَكَانَتْ مِنَ الْقَانِتِينَ  Translation: And Mary the daughter of &amp;#8216;Imran, who guarded her chastity; and We breathed into (her body) of Our spirit; and she testified to the truth of the words of her Lord and of His Revelations, and was one of the Qanitiyn [Surah Tahrim, 66:12]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Mortem Parental Rights</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/post-mortem-parental-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 01:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/post-mortem-parental-rights/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so you parents have rights upon you while they live. Most of us know that. What about after they&amp;#8217;ve left this life? Is it possible they might still have some rights due from you?
The answer is a resounding yes! Their rights, after they die, are:
 Janaazah: That you (or someone in the community) washes their body, buries them, etc., and you pray their janaazah prayer with the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing on Behalf of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 12:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/signing-on-behalf-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Never, ever, EVER say such-and-such is haram/halal/fard/etc. without knowledge. To say so, is to sign on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). And who dares to do that without knowledge? This is the job of the mujtahiduwn &amp;#8212; those who research fiqh issues and then issue fatawa. Notice, the best of them always say, &amp;#8220;this is the final ruling, and Allah knows best.&amp;#8221; Why? Because they are signing on behalf of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can’t Please Everyone</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 08:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/you-cant-please-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Today I have learned a valuable lesson, and I believe its a lesson that all of you readers can benefit from. The lesson itself is very simple, but realizing the importance and understanding the implications it may have in one’s life is what matters the most. The lesson is: you can‘t please everyone. Sounds so simple, right? Many of us are reading this and saying, well duh! So then, if its so obvious why do we keep persisting in our efforts to doing so?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Paradise</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 02:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/keys-to-paradise/</guid>
      <description>Anytime Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) mention Paradise for an action, it means that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) holds that action in high regard. So perform these activities regularly, and with ihsaan! Inshallah in the coming days, we will expound and narrate some instances where Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), or His messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم), promised paradise &amp;#8212; keys that we can use to unlock the doors and, inshallah, enter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Umar and the Eloquent Woman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, in a long hadith: &amp;#8220;A believer should speak good or keep silent!&amp;#8221; We all know this hadith, right?
But how do we implement this hadith? What if someone does something wrong? What if they deprive us of our rights? Should we still keep silent, or give them 80 lashes with our tongues?
Check this out&amp;#8211;this incident ocurred during the life of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), second Khalifa of Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Categories of Everything</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2006 21:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>Those five categories of all actions&amp;#8211;fard (also known as wajib), mustahab (sometimes called &amp;#8220;sunnah&amp;#8221;), mubah, makrooh, and haram&amp;#8211;what do they really mean? While you can understand these from different angles, we explain these from an Usool-ul-Fiqh perspective. Here they are:
    Fard/Wajib (obligatory) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn a punishment from abstaining from. Examples include praying, fasting, etc.
Mustahab/Sunnah (recommended) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn nothing from abstaining from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire Exits in the Qur’an</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fire-exits-in-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2006 13:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fire-exits-in-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>Whenever Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) mentions the Fire, He (سبحانه وتعالى) always mentions a fire exit&amp;#8211;usually immediately afterwards. There&amp;#8217;s always a chance to escape. But once you die, there&amp;#8217;s no fire exit. For example, in Surah Baqarah, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
فَإِن لَّمْ تَفْعَلُواْ وَلَن تَفْعَلُواْ فَاتَّقُواْ النَّارَ الَّتِي وَقُودُهَا النَّاسُ وَالْحِجَارَةُ أُعِدَّتْ لِلْكَافِرِينَ  وَبَشِّرِ الَّذِين آمَنُواْ وَعَمِلُواْ الصَّالِحَاتِ أَنَّ لَهُمْ جَنَّاتٍ تَجْرِي مِن تَحْتِهَا الأَنْهَار  Translation: But if you cannot&amp;#8211;and you can never do it&amp;#8211;then fear the Fire whose fuel is men and the stones, prepared for the Unbelievers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an: It’s All For You!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-its-all-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-its-all-for-you/</guid>
      <description>When you read the Qur&amp;#8217;an, cultivate the mentality that every single surah, verse, ayah, and letter was revealed for you, personally. Verse addressed to Banu Israeel (Jews)? Maybe Ahlil Kitaab (people of the book)? Or maybe An-Naas (humankind)? Or even the obvious, to those who believed? Yes, it addresses them&amp;#8211;but it also addresses you. Learn from their past&amp;#8211;their triumphs and their defeats, their actions and their mistakes, their joys and their pains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan: The Excuse-Killer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan kills all the excuses we make for ourselves throughout the year, and allows us to soar to new heights of eman! If someone said to you, &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s go to the masjid every day,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! If someone said &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s play Qiyam al-Layl all night,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! Subhanallah, in Ramdan, wishes and hopes and dreams can become reality!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase Your Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2006 01:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/increase-your-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Now that you know what barakah is, you might ask, how can one increase the barakah in his or her life? Aside from visiting the places with barakah, and making use of times with barakah, what else can you do?
The answer is very simple. If you want Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to bless you, then do anything for the sake of Allah, upon the sunnah (methodology) of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mu’min Tree</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-mumin-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2006 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-mumin-tree/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Ibrahim, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) gives us the metaphor of the kalimah (la ilaha ilallah) as a beautiful tree. The verse is:
أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ ضَرَبَ اللّهُ مَثَلاً كَلِمَةً طَيِّبَةً كَشَجَرةٍ طَيِّبَةٍ أَصْلُهَا ثَابِتٌ وَفَرْعُهَا فِي السَّمَاء  Translation: Have you not seen how Allah has given the parable of a beautiful kalimah, like a beautiful tree, whose roots are firmly established, and whose branches tower in the sky? (Surah Ibrahim, verse 24)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-Emptive Parental Kindness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pre-emptive-parental-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pre-emptive-parental-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Kindness to parents is pre-emptive&amp;#8211;you fulfill their needs and wants before they can ask, before they even know it themselves. Kindness to parents is pre-emptive&amp;#8211;it means you fulfill their needs before they ask. It&amp;#8217;s not antagonistic, where they ask and ask and ask until you give in and do what they say. It&amp;#8217;s not passive, where they have to tell you every little thing they need. It&amp;#8217;s active, so take the initiative and do what needs to be done, in order to earn the pleasure of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushrikeen Believed in Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mushrikeen-believed-in-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 20:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mushrikeen-believed-in-allah/</guid>
      <description>Belief in Allah  Check this out. The mushrikeen, now and in the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), believed in Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). Remember, these are the people who rejected Islam, and who are among the worst of people.
In Surah Ankabut, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
وَلَئِن سَأَلْتَهُم مَّنْ خَلَقَ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَسَخَّرَ الشَّمْسَ وَالْقَمَرَ لَيَقُولُنَّ اللَّهُ
[&amp;#8230;]
وَلَئِن سَأَلْتَهُم مَّن نَّزَّلَ مِنَ السَّمَاء مَاء فَأَحْيَا بِهِ الْأَرْضَ مِن بَعْدِ مَوْتِهَا لَيَقُولُنَّ اللَّهُ  Translation: If indeed thou ask them who has created the heavens and the earth and subjected the sun and the moon (to his Law), they will certainly reply, &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things that Contain Barakah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/things-that-contain-barakah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2006 20:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/things-that-contain-barakah/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of barakah, you might ask &amp;#8220;so what has barakah in it?&amp;#8221;
 The Qur&amp;#8217;an: In many verses, the Qur&amp;#8217;an itself is called &amp;#8220;mubarak&amp;#8221;. There is nothing but good in it&amp;#8211;every letter, every verse, every surah, every prohibition, every command. The revelation, the recitation, the understanding, and the memorization, as well, are blessed&amp;#8211;because they are the speech of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). The Prophets: All prophets have barakah, especially the last, Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fruits of Eman (4): A Good Life</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 16:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-fruits-of-eman-4/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our study of the fruits of eman, here are some additional fruits that spring from the tree of eman:
13) A Good Life  In Surah Nahl, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
مَنْ عَمِلَ صَالِحًا مِّن ذَكَرٍ أَوْ أُنثَى وَهُوَ مُؤْمِنٌ فَلَنُحْيِيَنَّهُ حَيَاةً طَيِّبَةً وَلَنَجْزِيَنَّهُمْ أَجْرَهُم بِأَحْسَنِ مَا كَانُواْ يَعْمَلُونَ  Translation: Whoever works righteousness, man or woman, and has Faith, verily, to him will We give a new Life, a life that is good and pure and We will bestow on such their reward according to the best of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Da’wah to Atheists: Five Minutes</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/dawah-to-atheists-five-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 02:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/dawah-to-atheists-five-minutes/</guid>
      <description>When you give da&amp;#8217;wah to atheists, give them five minutes of your time, then move on. If you can&amp;#8217;t convince them in five minutes, you won&amp;#8217;t be able to in five centuries. As proof that you should focus your da&amp;#8217;wah on other then atheists, consider the Qur&amp;#8217;an. How many verses did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) reveal to the Jews and Christians (People of the Book)? Countless. To the mushrikeen, the polytheistic Arabs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Ibadah, Natural Actions, Religious Actions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2006 03:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ibadah-natural-actions-religious-actions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Ibadah. We hear the word all the time. But what does it mean?
Linguistically, &amp;#8216;ibadah means to show subserviance, or to be subserviant to.
From a shar&amp;#8217;ee perspective, &amp;#8216;ibadah has two meanings:
 The spiritual conscience of the worshipper&amp;#8211;what constitutes worship spiritually. The actions&amp;#8211;what consitutes worship in action.  And Ibn Tamiyyah says: &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Ibadah includes all hidden and shown actions, statements, and beliefs beloved to Allah.&amp;#8221;
Of actions, there are two types: natural and religious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness for Shirk?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 05:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/forgiveness-for-shirk/</guid>
      <description>Allah blessed me with the opportunity to listen to Shaykh Yasir Qadhi, who specializes in Aqeeda, speak about shirk. Here&amp;#8217;s what he said.
Question: What happens if you&amp;#8217;re Muslim and you&amp;#8217;ve committed shirk?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
In the Qur&amp;#8217;an, in many places, Allah says shirk is unforgivable.
إِنَّ اللّهَ لاَ يَغْفِرُ أَن يُشْرَكَ بِهِ وَيَغْفِرُ مَا دُونَ ذَلِكَ لِمَن يَشَاء وَمَن يُشْرِكْ بِاللّهِ فَقَدِ افْتَرَى إِثْمًا عَظِيمًا  Translation: Surely Allah does not forgive that anything should be associated with Him, and forgives what is besides that to whomsoever He pleases; and whoever associates anything with Allah, he devises indeed a great sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water, Soil, Plants, Fruit, Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 05:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that your time is water. Every day, you get 24 liters to use as you wish. You keep it in one giant metal bucket and carry it around with you. The bucket leaks&amp;#8211;if you don&amp;#8217;t pour your time into buckets and use it effectively, most of it will end up spilled on the ground, lost.
Each day, you pass by some plants, and you have to stop and water them, or they die&amp;#8211;the big, thick bush of family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aim for 110%</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/aim-for-110/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 02:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/aim-for-110/</guid>
      <description>All of us, and especially those of us in educational institutes, run into tests and projects and assignments. And often&amp;#8211;too often&amp;#8211;we aim merely for a pass. A 60% or 50%, and we&amp;#8217;re good to go.
But, imagine if you will, an archer shooting at a target. High above his head is 100%. Somewhere level with him is 50%&amp;#8211;a pass. And below, lesser marks.
He draws back his arrow. He aims. 50%?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: A Springboard of Eman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-springboard-of-eman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2006 22:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-springboard-of-eman/</guid>
      <description>Salaah is the springboard of eman. Everytime you perform salaah, your eman should go up. In Surah Baqarah, Allah says: &amp;#8220;And seek help in patience and prayer. Indeed it is difficult, except for those with kushu&amp;#8220;.
Here are some tips inshaAllah to help you achieve awesome salaah:
 Pray as if it is your last prayer. We hear imams say this a lot. But what does it mean? How would your salaah be if you knew it was your last salaah before you returned to Allah, Lord of the Worlds?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek Knowledge from the Best Sources</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-knowledge-from-the-best-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 20:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-knowledge-from-the-best-sources/</guid>
      <description>When you seek knowledge, seek from the best sources&amp;#8211;the most authentic, and those closest to the source. The companion Abdullah ibn Zubayr (رضي الله عنه) was 10 years old when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) went on his farewell Hajj. Abdullah ibn Zubayr went, too, and witnessed the Prophet (sallalahu alayhi wa sallam)&amp;#8217;s hajj first-hand.
After the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) passed away, Abdullah ibn Zubayr became the definitive source of the fiqh of Hajj&amp;#8211;starting at age 10&amp;#8211;until he passed away at 73.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Uthman’s Caravan: Doing Business with Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uthmans-caravan-doing-business-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uthmans-caravan-doing-business-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>During a year of difficulty&amp;#8211;during the reign of Abu Bakr as-Siddique (radiAllahu &amp;#8216;an), when the Muslims needed food&amp;#8211;this HUGE caravan rolls into town. Everyone clamers around, they want to buy stuff, and it goes straight to the house of &amp;#8216;Uthman (radiAllahu &amp;#8216;an). He owned the caravans.
So they went to &amp;#8216;Uthman and said &amp;#8220;We want to buy it from you, we&amp;#8217;ll give you double the price&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;that is, double the cost, for food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islam Mission Statement – Rib’ee ibn ‘Amir</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/islam-mission-statement-ribee-ibn-amir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2006 16:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/islam-mission-statement-ribee-ibn-amir/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Allah has sent us to deliver whomsoever chooses, from the &amp;#8216;uboodiyyah of men to the &amp;#8216;uboodiyyah of Allah, from the narrowness of this world to the vastness of this world and the Hereafter, and from the tyranny and oppression of (false) religions to the justice of Islam.&amp;#8221;
So said Rib&amp;#8217;ee ibn &amp;#8216;Amir (may Allah be pleased with him) to the Persian general Rustum, before the battle of Qadisiyyah. An explaination of the core of Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Why?”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2006 04:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/why/</guid>
      <description>Often, non-Muslims question us about aspects of our faith. &amp;#8220;Why do you wear hijab&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;why don&amp;#8217;t you eat pork&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;why don&amp;#8217;t you drink or date&amp;#8221;.
And we get defensive and mangle our explainations. &amp;#8220;Well alcohol&amp;#8217;s not good for you&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;pigs are dirty&amp;#8221; and so on. Which is not correct.
The answer to all these questions is very, very simple:
Because Allah or His Messenger (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sea, the Boat, and the Governers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 03:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are a boat, and the dunya is the sea. Far off in the distance, is land &amp;#8212; the akhira.
&amp;#8220;You are a boat. You sail the waters of the dunya towards the lands of Jannah.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;Abdur-Rahman
What happens if the sea floods into the boat? You sink.
So be like the best Muslim leaders: they ditched the dunya for the akhira.
In particular, I refer to the governers in the time of the Khulafa Rashideen (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an on Battle Tactics</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-on-battle-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 03:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-on-battle-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Nisaa, Allah says:
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ خُذُواْ حِذْرَكُمْ فَانفِرُواْ ثُبَاتٍ أَوِ انفِرُواْ جَمِيعًا  Translation: O ye who believe! Take your precautions, and either go forth in parties or go forth all together (Surah Nisaa, 4:71).1
The message: prepare, and fight in groups.
A related incident: after the battle of Uhud, many tribes targeted the Muslims to take them down once and for all. The day the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) returned from battle, he slept, prayed &amp;#8216;Isha (alone), and the next day, after Fajr, said &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;re going after [the fleeing army].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (12): Sincerity of Du’a</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 02:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-12/</guid>
      <description>We often make empty du&amp;#8217;as&amp;#8211;they lack in sincerity, but hey, we don&amp;#8217;t expect them to be answered. But why do it? Are you just testing Allah?
Think with certiny that Allah will answer your du&amp;#8217;a. Make the most sincere, heart-felt du&amp;#8217;a of your existance. And have hope that Allah will answer it. Before Islam, there was a man named Jurayj, a worshipper of Allah. The people around him had intense jealousy of him for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (11): Torture and Flattery</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 02:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-11/</guid>
      <description>The king&amp;#8217;s companion pointed out the boy.
Why didn&amp;#8217;t he remain silent? For that matter, why does the boy point out the monk later?
Resolve. Ibn Tamiyyah, may Allah have mercy on him, said &amp;#8220;much of your resolve disappears when tortured&amp;#8221;. Your determination and strength of will plummets. So the man pointing out the boy, well, his determination couldn&amp;#8217;t withstand the torture.
So the king&amp;#8217;s soldiers brought the boy to the king, who said &amp;#8220;O my boy, your magic heals the blind and cures the lepers &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; Then he used flattery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (10): Kings Suck</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 00:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-10/</guid>
      <description>The king&amp;#8217;s companion returned to the king. They knew he was cured&amp;#8211;previously, people had to help him find his way in, but now, he waltzed right in.
The king said: &amp;#8220;Who gave you back your sight?&amp;#8221;
His companion said: &amp;#8220;My Lord.&amp;#8221;
The king said: &amp;#8220;Do you have a Lord other then me?&amp;#8221;
His companion said: &amp;#8220;My Lord and your Lord is Allah.&amp;#8221;
So the king tortured him until he pointed out the boy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (8): The Power of Words</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 23:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-8/</guid>
      <description>The boy used to heal the blind and the lepers and the people. (He wasn&amp;#8217;t a prophet: see the next post for more details.) The king&amp;#8217;s blind companion (jalees bin malik, or the one who sits next to the king) went to the boy with gifts, and said &amp;#8220;these are all for you if you heal me&amp;#8221;. The boy said &amp;#8220;Truly Allah heals. If you believe in Him, I will pray to Him, and He will heal you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling: A Fundamental Da’wah Technique</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 22:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>Storytelling is a fundamental da&amp;#8217;wah technique. It effortlessly communicates a message in a memorable medium. Storytelling is so powerful that you see it in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (Surah Baqarah and Surah Yusuf, for example), in ahadith (The People of the Ditch).
Among the benefits: storytelling communicates a message without spelling it out. Human beings recall stories more easily then they recall other forms of teaching. With a story, you can continually extract lessons and benefit from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Before Death</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-before-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/lessons-before-death/</guid>
      <description>From the teachings of the khulafa rashideen: when you&amp;#8217;re about to do something, ask yourself: &amp;#8220;Would I be happy and unregretful of how I spent my time today?&amp;#8221;
If the answer is &amp;#8220;no&amp;#8221;, then find something better to do with your time.
And remember: Time is one of the ONLY irreversable resources. Money comes and goes, status builds, but time, once it&amp;#8217;s gone, it never comes back.
The Prophet, peace and blessings upon him, said: Two things about which people are deceived are their health and their time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Measure of Leadership</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-true-measure-of-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2006 04:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-true-measure-of-leadership/</guid>
      <description>The true measure of leadership is influence, nothing more, and nothing less. When you can influence people, you&amp;#8217;re a leader, even if nobody recognizes you. And when you can&amp;#8217;t influence people, you&amp;#8217;re not a leader &amp;#8212; even if the masjid says so, or the organization says so, or your friends say so, or your car says so.
And remember the command of the Prophet, peace be upon him: Do not covet leadership, for it entails blame, regret, and punishment on the Day of Judgement &amp;#8212; except for the just ruler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief Shapes Identity and Action</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-shapes-identity-and-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 23:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/belief-shapes-identity-and-action/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Baqarah, Allah says:
وَإِذَا لَقُواْ الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ قَالُواْ آمَنَّا وَإِذَا خَلَوْاْ إِلَى شَيَاطِينِهِمْ قَالُواْ إِنَّا مَعَكْمْ إِنَّمَا نَحْنُ مُسْتَهْزِؤُونَ  Translation: &amp;#8220;When they meet those who believe, they say &amp;#8216;we believe,&amp;#8217; but when they are alone with their shayateen, they say &amp;#8216;we are with you&amp;#8216; &amp;#8230;&amp;#8221; (Al-Quran, Surah Al-Baqarah, 2:14)1
Although the hypocrites say they believe, they associate their identities with shayateen (devils, or &amp;#8220;evil ones&amp;#8221;).
The lesson: your belief system shapes your identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Leaders, Not Followers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/train-leaders-not-followers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 03:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/train-leaders-not-followers/</guid>
      <description>If you want your Islamic work&amp;#8211;your project, or organization, or masjid, or whatever it is&amp;#8211;to survive you, you need to train leaders, not followers.
When you train followers, they work well, for a time&amp;#8211;a month, or two, or a year, or ten, or 20&amp;#8211;but without a leader, the project collapses. Instead, train leaders, who in turn train followers and other leaders in your absence, and the cycle perpetuates inshaAllah.
This is also part of what you need to transform your project from a mom-and-pop-style business to an independant self-existing entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eman: Belief</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eman-belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 05:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eman-belief/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Eman is to believe, even when an overpowering tide of evil surrounds you.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;Imam Anwar al-Awlaki Remember, Allah controls eman. Even great Muslims sometimes die as disbelievers, wa iyyadubillah. O Allah, protect us from that evil end.
Among the many means to strengthen include constant rememberance of Allah and reminders of the hereafter. Ask Allah to strengthen your eman, and inshaAllah even your low-points become higher and higher over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yaqeen: Certainty</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/yaqeen-certainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 05:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/yaqeen-certainty/</guid>
      <description>Imam Anwar al-Awlaki says: Yaqeen is certainty in your beliefs over your physical reality. Your heart soaks up the belief and becomes unshakable. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) had it. All four khulafa had it.
O Allah, grant us belief in the hereafter and make our hearts firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Key to Attract an Amazing Spouse</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-attract-an-amazing-spouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2006 02:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-key-to-attract-an-amazing-spouse/</guid>
      <description>The key to attract an amazing spouse is to nurture in yourself those qualities that appeal to a person of that standard. Many of us pine for the perfect spouse&amp;#8211;realize he or she does not exist. Pick the best you can find, and learn to live with and cover their warts and weaknesses.
Set your criteria (based on the hadith of the Prophet, peace be upon him)&amp;#8211;have they memorized the Qur&amp;#8217;an?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wear Islam Responsibly</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/wear-islam-responsibly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 04:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/wear-islam-responsibly/</guid>
      <description>When you wear Islam, wear it properly and responsibly. &amp;#8211;A. M. When you grow a beard or put on hijab, be aware of the responsibility. You represent the Muslims, more then ever. Represent properly!
Don&amp;#8217;t mess up and appear at clubs or bars and similar places. With the greater reward comes the greater potential of punishment&amp;#8211;you can misguide many, many people if you represent Islam improperly.
May Allah protect us from anti-da&amp;#8217;wah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek Protection From Shirk</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-protection-from-shirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 03:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-protection-from-shirk/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) asked Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) for His protection from shirk. So why do we act like we know we&amp;#8217;ll die Muslim? Remember, this is the Prophet of Allah. He spoke to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) without any barrier. He received revelation directly from Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). He is the best of creation.
So seek protection in Allah from shirk, the unforgivable sin that destroys good deeds. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) taught us the following du&amp;#8217;a:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Happiness Doesn’t Exist</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/perfect-happiness-doesnt-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 03:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/perfect-happiness-doesnt-exist/</guid>
      <description>All people on Earth seek happiness&amp;#8211;whether it&amp;#8217;s through wealth, or love, or piety. Few realize that perfect happiness does not exist in the dunya. When you think about it, you&amp;#8217;ll find that hardship and pain exist with moments of great happiness. For example, you ate your favourite meal after a long time, but you feel over-full and you become tired and lazy. Or, you enjoy a wonderful hike through the woods, minus the insect bites and that bee that flew into your ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Label</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</guid>
      <description>Never label. Human beings are not two-dimensional that you can slap a label onto them and classify them. One of the best ways to destroy ties between people, groups, and organizations is to label them. Even if they deserve it, don&amp;#8217;t do it.
When you find yourself applying a label to someone, ask yourself: Will this action please Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)?
When you find others who label, back away. You don&amp;#8217;t want to involve yourself with people like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation (Shura): A Fundamental Leadership Technique</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 02:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</guid>
      <description>Consultation, or shura, is a fundamental leadership technique in Islam. You consult with the experts, and you implement it, and you close the issue. Shura means consultation. It also means the consulted group. Shura is a fundamental technique in leadership. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), the best and most knowledable and noble of people, practiced shura with his companions&amp;#8211;and who knew better than he? How can the rest of us believe we don&amp;#8217;t need shura?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Hold Back Your Talents</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</guid>
      <description>If you possess some skill you can utilize to the benefit of the people everywhere, never hold back. Don&amp;#8217;t hold it to yourself. Forget about what other people are thinking. Focus on how they can benefit from it. This applies especially if a) you have relatively rare talents, or b) nobody knows about your skills.
Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you Choose a Leader, Someone ALWAYS Disagrees</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-you-choose-a-leader-someone-always-disagrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 23:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-you-choose-a-leader-someone-always-disagrees/</guid>
      <description>When you choose a leader, someone always disagrees with you. No matter who you are and who your leader is, you cannot please everyone. So get used to it inshaAllah.
During the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) chose &amp;#8216;Usama ibn Zayd (son of Zayid ibn Thabit, may Allah be pleased with them both) as the leader of the army. And they had high-status alumni sahaba in that army, like &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anh), who was in his 40s or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership at the Front and Leadership from the Back</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 23:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</guid>
      <description>Front Leaders: These leaders take charge, set the vision, and lead the way. They take the initiative, and step up to the call when Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) calls them.
Back Leaders: These leaders encourage, gather everyone&amp;#8217;s opinion, call meetings, and encourage mutual agreement and compromise.
In Islaimc work, and in any project, you need both types of leadership. Like when a group hikes through a trail. You need someone at the front to pick the path and set the pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Meetings: Two Cents and Two Sentences</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/productive-meetings-two-cents-and-two-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 03:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/productive-meetings-two-cents-and-two-sentences/</guid>
      <description>To optimize your meetings and keep them clear, concise, and on-topic, follow the following two rules as much as possible:
Two Cents: Keep your two cents out of it. Nobody wants to hear your opinion anyway, and spewing one opinion denies other opinions their right. When you compound personal opinion with rebuttal with re-rebuttal, your main topic quickly derails. (Never tolerate deviations from this rule.)
Two Sentences: _When you speak, l_imit your dialogue to two sentences max.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Beard can be Weird</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 02:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t judge a book by its cover or a man by his beard, because what&amp;#8217;s behind the beard can be weird.&amp;#8221; Apply this to your lives, and you&amp;#8217;ll find that, bi ithnillah (by the permission of Allah), you will never be surprised or dissapointed. When you make great assumptions about people, where can they go except down?
Great assumptions often lead to great letdowns. Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear the Creator, Fear the Creation?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fear-the-creator-fear-the-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 22:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fear-the-creator-fear-the-creation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;If you fear the creator, you will never fear the creation.&amp;#8221; -Imam Anwar al-Awlaki If your heart trembles in fear of Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and awe of His majesty, nothing in the dunya (world) can ever overshadow that fear. The dunya can throw a bigger army at you, better weapons, everything and anything. And if you fear Allah the way He deserves to be feared, none of that can overshadow your fear of the Creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Work: A Lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/islamic-work-a-lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/islamic-work-a-lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Islamic work isn&amp;#8217;t something we do for a hobby&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s our life.&amp;#8221; Work for the cause, don&amp;#8217;t abandon it. Don&amp;#8217;t neglect it to play video games or watch TV or surf the internet. It isn&amp;#8217;t a hobby. It isn&amp;#8217;t part-time. It&amp;#8217;s full-time, all out, no holds-barred work for the cause of Allah.
If you consider the illustrious sahaba, radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhuma ajma&amp;#8217;een, they all gave their all for the cause. Their wealth, their health, their free time, even their very lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Things Are Worth Crying Over</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Very few things in life are worth crying over.&amp;#8221; Ponder it. Very few things in life are worth throwing a fit over or complaining about. In Islamic work, especially, people attach importantance to things that aren&amp;#8217;t issues, tempers rise, fights break out, and brotherhood dies. And in the end, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) controls over all things.
So sit back, chill out, and let it run by you. No harm done, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>