<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sahaba on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/sahaba/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sahaba on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 03:46:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/sahaba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect: A Lesson from Al-Abbas</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 03:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</guid>
      <description>Someone asked Al-Abbas (radiallahu anhu), the uncle of rasulullah, a question: are you akbar than rasulullah?
In Arabic, literally, this means &amp;#8220;are you greater than rasulullah.&amp;#8221; But the obvious connotation is that the questioner asks about age: are you older than him?
Al-Abbas said:
 رسول الله أكبر مني و لكن ولدت قبله
Rasulullah is greater than me, but I was born before him.
 He wanted to set the record set, and give a clear message to all of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Hesitate: Lessons from the Battle of Mu’tah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 02:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</guid>
      <description>One of the unique characteristics of the battle of Mu&amp;#8217;tah is that rasulullah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed not one, but three commanders in the chain of command:
 `Abdullah bin &amp;#8216;Umar said: Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed Zaid bin Haritha as the commander of the army during the Ghazwa of Mu&amp;#8217;tah and said, &amp;#8220;If Zaid is martyred, Ja&amp;#8217;far should take over his position, and if Ja&amp;#8217;far is martyred, Abdullah bin Rawaha should take over his position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Choose the Path</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-choose-the-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 18:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/you-choose-the-path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/forked-path.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;forked-path&#34; title=&#34;forked-path&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1099&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #10 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Layl, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا يَغْشَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَالنَّهَارِ إِذَا تَجَلَّى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَمَا خَلَقَ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنثَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;إِنَّ سَعْيَكُمْ لَشَتَّى&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By the night when it covers, and [by] the day when it appears, and [by] He who created the male and female: &lt;em&gt;Indeed&lt;/em&gt;, your paths are diverse. [Surah Layl, verses 1-4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Arabic (and in English), people talk. And when you want to really draw attention to something, you make an oath. Compare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Child 1:&lt;/strong&gt; I didn&amp;#8217;t break the cookie jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Child 2:&lt;/strong&gt; I swear by my mother&amp;#8217;s grave, that I didn&amp;#8217;t break the cookie jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which would you pay more attention to? Obviously, the second child (by the way, don&amp;#8217;t swear by other than Allah, it&amp;#8217;s shirk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine two people talking&amp;#8211;your brother or sister, who you&amp;#8217;ve known forever, and the President of America. Who would you pay more attention to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillahi mathalu al-&amp;#8216;alaa. This is &lt;strong&gt;Allah&lt;/strong&gt; talking to you. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; He&amp;#8217;s making an oath&amp;#8211;not just one, but three things! We should &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; pay attention here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what does He testify to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verse 4&amp;#8211;that your paths are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Made the Companions Special</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-made-the-companions-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 16:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-made-the-companions-special/</guid>
      <description>In a report by Abdullah bin `Amr bin `Aas (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu), he related that a woman came to the Messenger of Allah with her daughter. On the daughter&amp;#8217;s wrist were two heavy gold bracelets. The Messenger asked her, &amp;#8220;Do you pay Zakaat on this?&amp;#8221; She replied, &amp;#8220;No.&amp;#8221; The Messenger said: &amp;#8220;Would it please you that Allah will encircle you with two bracelets of fire?&amp;#8221; The reporter commented that she took them off and threw them down in front of the Messenger, and said: &amp;#8220;They are for Allah and his Messenger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things” that Loved the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
عن انس قال النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏لا يؤمن ‏ ‏أحدكم حتى أكون أحب إليه من والده وولده والناس أجمعين ‏ 
Anas radi Allahu anhu narrated that the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, &amp;#8220;None of you truly believes (has emaan) until I am more beloved to him than his father, his child and all of mankind.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Loving the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam is a part of emaan, and Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala has made it obligatory for us to love the Messenger alayhi salaam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Hamd?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 22:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/what-is-hamd/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
As Muslims, the phrase &amp;#8220;alhamdulillah&amp;#8221; الحمد لله (all praise and thanks is for Allah) is an integral part of our deen; we are taught to say it from both the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah. Linguistically, Hamd is from ha-meem-daal ( حمد or ح م د) and it is to mention the good attribute of a person, such an attribute that is the at the level of perfection. Hamd is based on mahabbah (love) and ta&amp;#8217;dheem (greatness).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reading Light: Importance of Tafseer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 00:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reading-light-importance-of-tafseer/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur’an,
كِتَابٌ أَنزَلْنَاهُ إِلَيْكَ مُبَارَكٌ لِّيَدَّبَّرُوا آيَاتِهِ وَلِيَتَذَكَّرَ أُوْلُوا الْأَلْبَابِ  &amp;#8220;(This is) a Book which We have sent down to you, full of blessings, so that they may ponder over its verses, and that men of understanding may remember.” Surah Saad: verse 29.
(linguistic explanation of the word yaddabaroo is in the comments)
It is the science of tafseer which is the fruit of ‘pondering over its verses’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Assassination of ‘Umar ibn Al-Khattab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-assassination-of-umar-ibn-al-khattab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 01:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-assassination-of-umar-ibn-al-khattab/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه‏) was the second khalifa, and one of the ten companions promised Jannah in their lifetimes.
&amp;#8216;Umar (رضي الله عنه‏) used to be a soldier&amp;#8211;one of the best. But when he became the khalifah, the other companions refused to let him fight&amp;#8211;he disagreed with them, but in the end, he stayed back in Medinah while the battles waged. Yet he always made one du&amp;#8217;a, publicly and privately, throughout his khilafah: &amp;#8220;Allahumma ruziqniy shahaadah,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;O Allah, provide me with martyrdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Teacher</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 18:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an,
هُوَ الَّذِي بَعَثَ فِي الْأُمِّيِّينَ رَسُولًا مِّنْهُمْ يَتْلُو عَلَيْهِمْ آيَاتِهِ وَيُزَكِّيهِمْ وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الْكِتَابَ وَالْحِكْمَةَ وَإِن كَانُوا مِن قَبْلُ لَفِي ضَلَالٍ مُّبِينٍ  Translation: It is He who has sent among the unlettered a Messenger from themselves reciting to them His verses and purifying them and teaching them the Book and wisdom although they were before in clear error. [Suratul Jumu&amp;#8217;ah, verse 2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Do You Not Love that Allah Should Forgive You?”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 17:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/do-you-not-love-that-allah-should-forgive-you/</guid>
      <description>SubhanAllah, we all know the story about the accusations that were forged against &amp;#8216;Aishah (رضالله عنها), but in addition to that story, the tafsir for Surat An-Nur (Surah 24), ayah 22, reveals another story&amp;#8211;a story of forgiveness, a story of compassion, a story demonstrating the superiority of those who act for the sake of Allah (may Allah make us of them).
  Mistah was the cousin of As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umm Salamah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-salamah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2007 11:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/umm-salamah/</guid>
      <description>Umm Salamah! What an eventful life she had! Her real name was Hind. She was the daughter of one of the notables in the Makhzum clan nicknamed &amp;#8220;Zad ar-Rakib,&amp;#8221; because he was well known for his generosity, particularly to travelers. Umm Salamah&amp;#8217;s husband was Abdullah ibn Abdul-Asad, and they both were among the first people to accept Islam. Only Abu Bakr and a few others, who could be counted on the fingers of one hand, became Muslims before them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abu Bakr and His Request</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 08:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</guid>
      <description>What do you make of the amazing incident when the best of the sahaba (رضالله عنه) came to the best of the Prophets (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to ask for a du&amp;#8217;a to make in his prayers?
 Narrated Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه) I asked Allah&amp;#8217;s Apostle (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to teach me an invocation so that I may invoke Allah with it in my prayer. He told me to say, [Sahih Bukhari]  (Hover your mouse over each line to see the translation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Role Models–Got Any?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 08:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</guid>
      <description>Who are your role models? Movie stars? Sports stars? Celebrities? Do we have any role models for Ramadan&amp;#8211;people we can look on to and learn from? Let us take a glimpse at how our pious predecessors and the early generations spent their Ramadan.
Their reading of Qur&amp;#8217;an in Ramadan:
 Salam ibn Abi Muti&amp;#8217; informs us that Qatadah used to normally complete reading the Qur&amp;#8217;an in 7 days, but in Ramadan, he completed it in three days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conquest: History of the Khulafa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/conquest-history-of-the-khulafa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2007 03:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/conquest-history-of-the-khulafa/</guid>
      <description>Conquest: History of the Khulafa  Conquest: History of the Khulafa is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef.
&amp;#8220;Follow my sunnah and the sunnah of the Khulafa Rashideen.&amp;#8221; Advice from the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to all of humankind&amp;#8211;to stick to the sunnah, and follow the Khulafa Rashideen, the righteous Khalifas.
But do we know who the Khulafa Rashideen are? Abu Bakr, &amp;#8216;Umar, &amp;#8216;Uthmaan, and &amp;#8216;Ali (رضي الله عنهم)&amp;#8211;may Allah be pleased with them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of the Masjid</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-role-of-the-masjid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 23:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-role-of-the-masjid/</guid>
      <description>When the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) arrived in Medina, he built a masjid before doing anything else! The masjids the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) built were more than places to pray! Their functions included:
 A place for children: not a place where they cried and ran around but a place where they were accommodated. There are several narrations of how when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) was praying, the children would come and climb on his back or he (صلي الله عليه وسلم) would hold them while praying salah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Empowering Beliefs from ibn Al-Khattab</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/four-empowering-beliefs-from-ibn-al-khattab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2007 12:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/four-empowering-beliefs-from-ibn-al-khattab/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), the second khalifa, had four beliefs that made it easier for him to bear calamities:
 The situation could have been worse. It didn’t strike him in his religion. Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) will reward him with Jannah in return inshallah. When he remembered the hardship of losing the Prophet(صلي الله عليه وسلم) everything else faded away.  Subhanallah, these are profound beliefs from the second khalifa that we can all benefit from!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules of Engagement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2006 22:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/rules-of-engagement/</guid>
      <description>Rules of Engagement  Rules of Engagement is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad ibn Faqih. The course teaches and emphasizes ethics, morality, rights, character attributes, and manners&amp;#8211;everything from the rights of children before they&amp;#8217;re born to the cause for the decline and destruction of socieities to the literally dozens of virtues one earns from sabr! The course focuses a lot on self-development, self-improvement, and dealing with others, as well as improving oneself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic Four</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 06:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</guid>
      <description>One day, the Prophet (peace be upon him) sat with his companions, early in the morning. He asked, &amp;#8220;who among you is fasting this day?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I am.&amp;#8221; The Prophet (peace be upon him) asked, &amp;#8220;who amongst you followed the funeral bier (i.e. a janaazah) today?&amp;#8221; and Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.&amp;#8221; Then the Prophet (peace be upon him) said, &amp;#8220;who amongst you served food to the needy?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer ibn Abbas</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tafseer-ibn-abbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 08:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tafseer-ibn-abbas/</guid>
      <description>Abdullah ibn Abbas (رضي الله عنه) was a great companion and a great scholar. In fact, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) made du&amp;#8217;a for him, that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) grants him knowledge of the deen.
Even more amazing then this, Ibn Abbas narrated that the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) once made du&amp;#8217;a and said, &amp;#8220;O Allah! teach him wisdom (i.e. the understanding of the knowledge of Qur&amp;#8217;an).&amp;#8221; [Bukhari 5/57/100] This is why his tafseer carries a heavy weight, even today, more then a millenium after his death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Umar and the Eloquent Woman</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/umar-and-the-eloquent-woman/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, in a long hadith: &amp;#8220;A believer should speak good or keep silent!&amp;#8221; We all know this hadith, right?
But how do we implement this hadith? What if someone does something wrong? What if they deprive us of our rights? Should we still keep silent, or give them 80 lashes with our tongues?
Check this out&amp;#8211;this incident ocurred during the life of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه), second Khalifa of Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lessons: Power With Conciseness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 15:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</guid>
      <description>Another important gem we learn from the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and the early generations is that power comes with conciseness.
During the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), he received a letter from a man named Musaylimah, who claimed prophethood as well, and wished to divide up the area. In response, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) wrote:
&amp;#8220;From Muhammad the Messenger of Allah to Musaylimah the liar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stepping Up: Leadership Lessons from Az-Zubayr</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/stepping-up-leadership-lessons-from-az-zubayr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2006 19:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/stepping-up-leadership-lessons-from-az-zubayr/</guid>
      <description>During the battle of Yarmuk, Az-Zubayr (رضي الله عنه) tried to incite the mujahideen to fight against the Romans. (You can read the entire incident here.)
From this incident, we learn some important leadership lessons:
 When nobody steps up to the task, the leader must take the initiative to get the job done. Because, one way or another, the task must be completed. Leaders also work in the trenches, when circumstances require it of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jafar ibn Abu Talib’s Speech to the Negus</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/jafar-ibn-abu-talibs-speech-to-the-negus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2006 21:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/jafar-ibn-abu-talibs-speech-to-the-negus/</guid>
      <description>The Muslims were forced out of their land because of the persecution of the polytheist Arabs, who tortured them because they said, &amp;#8220;our Lord is one&amp;#8221;. The Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) commanded the Muslims to migrate to Abysynnia, to live under the Negus, a just ruler. The Polytheists refused to let them leave peacefully, and confronted the king to demand the return of the Muslims. Jafar was chosen as the spokesperson for the Muslims to the king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek Knowledge from the Best Sources</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-knowledge-from-the-best-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2006 20:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/seek-knowledge-from-the-best-sources/</guid>
      <description>When you seek knowledge, seek from the best sources&amp;#8211;the most authentic, and those closest to the source. The companion Abdullah ibn Zubayr (رضي الله عنه) was 10 years old when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) went on his farewell Hajj. Abdullah ibn Zubayr went, too, and witnessed the Prophet (sallalahu alayhi wa sallam)&amp;#8217;s hajj first-hand.
After the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) passed away, Abdullah ibn Zubayr became the definitive source of the fiqh of Hajj&amp;#8211;starting at age 10&amp;#8211;until he passed away at 73.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Uthman’s Caravan: Doing Business with Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uthmans-caravan-doing-business-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uthmans-caravan-doing-business-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>During a year of difficulty&amp;#8211;during the reign of Abu Bakr as-Siddique (radiAllahu &amp;#8216;an), when the Muslims needed food&amp;#8211;this HUGE caravan rolls into town. Everyone clamers around, they want to buy stuff, and it goes straight to the house of &amp;#8216;Uthman (radiAllahu &amp;#8216;an). He owned the caravans.
So they went to &amp;#8216;Uthman and said &amp;#8220;We want to buy it from you, we&amp;#8217;ll give you double the price&amp;#8221;&amp;#8211;that is, double the cost, for food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Ya Ahlil Ansar” – The Battle of Yamamah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ya-ahlil-ansar-battle-of-yamamah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 23:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ya-ahlil-ansar-battle-of-yamamah/</guid>
      <description>In the battle of Yamamah (against Musaylimah. Muslims: 11k. Enemy: narrations vary, 20k-60k), Abdullah ibn &amp;#8216;Umar (may Allah be pleased with him) ended up wounded and in the nursing docks. He saw this one Ansar (may Allah be pleased with him, whoever he was) critically injured&amp;#8211;he couldn&amp;#8217;t walk&amp;#8211;out of commission, being nursed.
To create motivation, outside on the battlefield, someone shouted &amp;#8220;ya ahlil ansar&amp;#8221; (o people of Ansar), like called them to group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Az-Zubayr and Yarmuk: The Man Worth 1000 Fighters</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/az-zubayr-and-yarmuk-the-man-worth-1000-fighters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 00:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/az-zubayr-and-yarmuk-the-man-worth-1000-fighters/</guid>
      <description>During the time of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (may Allah be pleased with him), Amr ibn al-&amp;#8216;As was in Egypt, and requested fighters. &amp;#8216;Umar (radiallahu &amp;#8216;an) sent a letter saying &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ll send you 8000 fighters.&amp;#8221; He sent 4000 fighters. &amp;#8216;Amr ibn al-&amp;#8216;As (radiallahu &amp;#8216;an) replied and said (to the meaning of) &amp;#8220;you said you sent 8000 and you sent 4000,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8216;Umar (radiallahu &amp;#8216;an) said &amp;#8220;I sent 4000, and at the head of each thousand is a man worth 1000 himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing to Good Deeds: Abu Dujana and the Prophet’s Sword</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 05:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</guid>
      <description>Before the battle of Uhud, when the Muslims were preparing and such, the Prophet, peace be upon him, lifted up his sword and said &amp;#8220;who will fight with my sword?&amp;#8221;
And all the sahaba were like &amp;#8220;me, me&amp;#8221;, like &amp;#8220;pick me&amp;#8221;. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) put down his sword. Their emotions were raised.
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) raised it again and said &amp;#8220;who will take my sword and give it the haq (right) due to the sword?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sea, the Boat, and the Governers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 03:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-sea-the-boat-and-the-governers/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are a boat, and the dunya is the sea. Far off in the distance, is land &amp;#8212; the akhira.
&amp;#8220;You are a boat. You sail the waters of the dunya towards the lands of Jannah.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211;Abdur-Rahman
What happens if the sea floods into the boat? You sink.
So be like the best Muslim leaders: they ditched the dunya for the akhira.
In particular, I refer to the governers in the time of the Khulafa Rashideen (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four Allah Blessed, Reach That Level</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-four-allah-blessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 04:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-four-allah-blessed/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Nisaa, Allah says:
وَمَن يُطِعِ اللّهَ وَالرَّسُولَ فَأُوْلَـئِكَ مَعَ الَّذِينَ أَنْعَمَ اللّهُ عَلَيْهِم مِّنَ النَّبِيِّينَ وَالصِّدِّيقِينَ وَالشُّهَدَاء وَالصَّالِحِينَ وَحَسُنَ أُولَـئِكَ رَفِيقاً  Translation: And who-so-ever obeys Allah and the Messenger, shall be with those whom Allah has blessed-the Prophets, the truthful (siddiyqin) and the martyrs (shuhada) and the righteous (saliheen). What excellent companions these are that one may get! [Surah An-Nisaa, verse 69]
Prophets are those Allah blessed with divine revelation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“It has a Ropey Tail and a Trunk.”  The Miracle of the Qur’an.</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/it-has-a-ropy-tail-and-a-trunk-the-miracle-of-the-quran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2006 03:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/it-has-a-ropy-tail-and-a-trunk-the-miracle-of-the-quran/</guid>
      <description>Musaylimah used to pray three times a day. He used to lie and say Qur&amp;#8217;an was revealed to him, and he&amp;#8217;d make up verses of &amp;#8220;Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8221;. In one instance, the people came to him and asked &amp;#8220;was anything revealed?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Not yet.&amp;#8221; And later, &amp;#8220;anything yet?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Nope.&amp;#8221;. And later &amp;#8220;Anything yet?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Nope.&amp;#8221;
At one point, some people came to him and one said &amp;#8220;was anything revealed to the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware Endorsements: The Fitnah of Ar-Rajal</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/beware-endorsements-the-fitnah-of-ar-rajal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2006 22:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/beware-endorsements-the-fitnah-of-ar-rajal/</guid>
      <description>A man came to the Prophet (salallhu alayhi wa sallam) from Al-Yamamah, learned some Quran, and apostated and joined Musalimah. His kunya (pet-name) was Ar-Rajal (&amp;#8220;the man&amp;#8221;). He endorsed Musaylimah.
His fitna was more intense then Musaylimah. People thought he was learned and scholarly, and he believed in Musaylimah. It caused a huge doubt among the ignorant people. They felt that if Ar-Rajal listened, they should listen, too.
Today, everyone has endorsements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities of Musaylimah al-Kadhab, False Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/qualities-of-musaylimah-al-kathab-false-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 12:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/qualities-of-musaylimah-al-kathab-false-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Musaylimah al-Kadhab (Musaylimah the Liar) claimed prophethood during the time of the Prophet, sallalahu alayhi wa sallam. He sent a letter to the prophet saying &amp;#8220;Good news, I&amp;#8217;m a prophet too! So you be the prophet of the Hijaz area (very hilly area near the sea where the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) resided) and I&amp;#8217;ll be the prophet of the Najd area.&amp;#8221;
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) replied with &amp;#8220;From Muhammad the Messenger of Allah to Musaylimah the liar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mujahideen Culture: Khalid bin Walid and Malik ibn An-Nuwayrah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mujahideen-culture-khalid-bin-walid-and-malik-ibn-an-nuwayrah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2006 03:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/mujahideen-culture-khalid-bin-walid-and-malik-ibn-an-nuwayrah/</guid>
      <description>Among the culture of the mujahideen is that they honoured each others&amp;#8217; families. If someone died in battle, their wives were married to people of equal stature after the &amp;#8216;iddah (mourning period).
Malik ibn An-Nuwayrah, during the time of Abu Bakr as-Siddique, radiallahu &amp;#8216;an, did not want to pay zakaah. There&amp;#8217;s a difference of opinion, and Allahu &amp;#8216;alim, he (Malik ibn An-Nuwayrah) was not Muslim.
Kahlid bin Walid killed him one night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Interaction: Professionalism</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 04:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</guid>
      <description>The key to gender interaction (aka gender relations) is professionalism. During the lifetime of the Prophet, peace be upon him, &amp;#8216;Umar said to one woman sahaba in Abysinnia: &amp;#8220;We have more right to the Prophet then you&amp;#8221;. She said (to the effect of) &amp;#8220;nope&amp;#8221;. She approached the Prophet and narrated the incident to him, and he said &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Umar was incorrect. You (Abyssinians) made hijrah (migration) twice, you get double the reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khalid bin Walid: From General to Foot-Soldier</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</guid>
      <description>During the reign of Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم), and later, the reign of Abu Bakr, the first Khalifa, may Allah be pleased with him, Khalid bin Walid, commander of the Muslim army, rocked the non-Muslim armies again and again and again and lead the Muslims to many victories. In this way, he became a fitnah&amp;#8211;people ascribed victory to him, and not to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).
After the battle of Yarmuk, the newly-instated Khalifa, &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (may Allah be pleased with him) removed Khalid bin Walid from leadership of the army and instated Abu Ubaydah (RA) as the commander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Label</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</guid>
      <description>Never label. Human beings are not two-dimensional that you can slap a label onto them and classify them. One of the best ways to destroy ties between people, groups, and organizations is to label them. Even if they deserve it, don&amp;#8217;t do it.
When you find yourself applying a label to someone, ask yourself: Will this action please Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)?
When you find others who label, back away. You don&amp;#8217;t want to involve yourself with people like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Tactic: The Trench Rush</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/business-tactic-the-trench-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/business-tactic-the-trench-rush/</guid>
      <description>In one of the battles in the time of the Khulafa Rashideen, the Muslim armies attacked a fort behind a trench.
With a trench, defenses spread thin: 500 people need to guard all points of the trench. So in any given area, you have only a few guards.
How did the Muslims succeed? They find the one lazy guy&amp;#8211;if the trench is eight feet deep and six feet across, they find the location two feet deep and one foot across&amp;#8211;and focus the entire army towards that one location, all the hundreds or thousands of mujahideen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dedication of the Sahaba</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-dedication-of-the-sahaba/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 04:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-dedication-of-the-sahaba/</guid>
      <description>The dedication of sahaba is no joke. They strove beyond the physical limtations of their bodies. When they couldn&amp;#8217;t stand, or open their eyes, they continued. Their dedication to Allah transcended their bodies.
In the battle of Yamamah, when Abdullah ibn &amp;#8216;Umar (RA) lay in the nursing docks after one battle, he heard a shout from outside&amp;#8211;ya ahlil ansar, &amp;#8220;o people of the Ansar&amp;#8221;. He spotted an ansari nearby&amp;#8211;a man critically injured, couldn&amp;#8217;t walk, incapacitated, being nursed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amir Competition, Tribe Competition</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amir-competition-tribe-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amir-competition-tribe-competition/</guid>
      <description>The illustrious sahaba (companions of the Prophet), may Allah be pleased with all of them, competed in righteousness. They did not compete for the largest house or the biggest family. They competed, among other things, for the honour of guard ingthe Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) in battle.
They divided into tribes and competed with other tribes. The amirs, too, competed with each other. For example, in the campaign in Ash-Sham, the two armies competed&amp;#8211;who could be the fastest to fight their way to the key city?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khalid Bin Walid’s Fundamental Strategy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walids-fundamental-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walids-fundamental-strategy/</guid>
      <description>One of the fundamental war techniques of Khalid bin Walid (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anh) is that he never wasted time. He might make mistakes from it, but he moved the entire army at the speed of a single rider. Most armies crawl at a slow pace, but his army moved quickly. The Muslims were all very well disciplined. If you were in his army, you moved fast.
He moved so quickly that after one battle took place at one village, before the defenders regrouped, he arrived at the next village and attacked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>