<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seerah on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/seerah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seerah on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 16:01:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/seerah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Legacy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-lost-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 16:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/the-lost-legacy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
We live in an era where knowledge is abundant and is available at our finger tips in variety of formats (audio, video, ebooks&amp;#8230;) and on variety of devices and platforms (tablets, smartphones, laptops&amp;#8230;.). However, we lack the enthusiasm, passion, dedication and commitment to seeking knowledge. Here are few of the inspiring stories of past to rekindle that spark.
 Imam Zafar said &amp;#8220;We used to sit down and take our spots for the circle of Imam Ali Madini after the Asar prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect: A Lesson from Al-Abbas</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 03:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</guid>
      <description>Someone asked Al-Abbas (radiallahu anhu), the uncle of rasulullah, a question: are you akbar than rasulullah?
In Arabic, literally, this means &amp;#8220;are you greater than rasulullah.&amp;#8221; But the obvious connotation is that the questioner asks about age: are you older than him?
Al-Abbas said:
 رسول الله أكبر مني و لكن ولدت قبله
Rasulullah is greater than me, but I was born before him.
 He wanted to set the record set, and give a clear message to all of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Uncle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</guid>
      <description>And We have not sent you, [O Muhammad], except as a mercy to the worlds. [21:107]
In the last post, we looked at how our beloved prophet (SAW) set for us an excellent example as a father. Inshallah, continuing with the theme, in this post, we will explore two more roles: **uncle and the master.
**
Treatment with niece
 After the Taif Campaign, one of the captives As-Shaima, the daughter of Al-Harith As-Sadiya, the Messenger’s foster sister was brought to the Messenger of Allah (peace be upon him) , she introduced herself to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Father</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 03:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.&amp;#8221; [33:21]
Inshallah in this post and in future posts, we will be looking at seerah. We will look at how the prophet (SAW) set an excellent example for us in different roles; be it be as a husband, father, friend, leader and other such roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things” that Loved the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
عن انس قال النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏لا يؤمن ‏ ‏أحدكم حتى أكون أحب إليه من والده وولده والناس أجمعين ‏ 
Anas radi Allahu anhu narrated that the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, &amp;#8220;None of you truly believes (has emaan) until I am more beloved to him than his father, his child and all of mankind.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Loving the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam is a part of emaan, and Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala has made it obligatory for us to love the Messenger alayhi salaam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>