<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Series the Victorious One on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/series-the-victorious-one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Series the Victorious One on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 21:49:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/series-the-victorious-one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Culture vs. Religion</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/understanding-culture-vs-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 21:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/understanding-culture-vs-religion/</guid>
      <description>As we continue our foray into Medini seerah, we notice that Medinah, at the time of hijrah, was divided culturally. It contained three distinct groups: Al-Aws, Al-Khazraj, and the Jews. All three held roughly equal power, with no one being significantly stronger than the other; Medinah had no clear leader who all the groups answered to.
Medinah was not only multi-cultural, but multi-religious! Which brings us to an important discussion: what is the difference between culture and religion, and how do we find a balance bewteen the two?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect: A Lesson from Al-Abbas</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 03:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/respect-a-lesson-from-al-abbas/</guid>
      <description>Someone asked Al-Abbas (radiallahu anhu), the uncle of rasulullah, a question: are you akbar than rasulullah?
In Arabic, literally, this means &amp;#8220;are you greater than rasulullah.&amp;#8221; But the obvious connotation is that the questioner asks about age: are you older than him?
Al-Abbas said:
 رسول الله أكبر مني و لكن ولدت قبله
Rasulullah is greater than me, but I was born before him.
 He wanted to set the record set, and give a clear message to all of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Hesitate: Lessons from the Battle of Mu’tah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 02:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</guid>
      <description>One of the unique characteristics of the battle of Mu&amp;#8217;tah is that rasulullah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed not one, but three commanders in the chain of command:
 `Abdullah bin &amp;#8216;Umar said: Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed Zaid bin Haritha as the commander of the army during the Ghazwa of Mu&amp;#8217;tah and said, &amp;#8220;If Zaid is martyred, Ja&amp;#8217;far should take over his position, and if Ja&amp;#8217;far is martyred, Abdullah bin Rawaha should take over his position.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>