<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sawm on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/sawm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sawm on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/sawm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Do List After Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Wikipedia
Ramadan ended. (May Allah accept all our prayer, fasting, du&amp;#8217;a, and good deeds during this blessed month &amp;#8212; ameen!) How should we, as Muslims, act now?
We graduated from the school of Ramadan; can life simply return to normal?
Our scholars mention a few points about this:
 Allah says, in surah Baqarah, that Ramadan was prescribed on us in the hope that we gain taqwa. Did we achieve that goal of the school of Ramadan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerful Tips for the Last 10 Nights</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/powerful-tips-for-the-last-10-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 20:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/powerful-tips-for-the-last-10-nights/</guid>
      <description>By Sheikh Tawfique Chowdhury
[https://www.youtube.com/embed/6a2Jpkp6cNM?feature=oembed]
  Do not let your &amp;#8216;performance&amp;#8217; until now affect your last 10 days. The moment of forgiveness could be today or anytime in the coming days! It is not all lost! If you sincerely wish it could have been better &amp;#8211; Chin up and get ready to make it your best yet! Start with a positive, sincere intention!
 Today, take a little time to read the Tafseer of Surah al-Qadr to understand what actually happens this night!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 03:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Eid Mubarak! As the sahaba would tell each other: May Allah accept our good deeds and your good deeds (from Ramadan). Ameen!
Ramadan is still fresh in your mind; the long days of fasting, the pain in your legs and back from taraweeh, and most of all, that biting regret that you didn&amp;#8217;t do enough.
Would you like to make the next Ramadan even better? With only five minutes worth of effort?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Resource Bonanza!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ramadan-resource-bonanza/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#8217;s better than a chest of gold and jewels? A post full of Qur&amp;#8217;an and sunnah!  Bismillah.
This is a guest post by an author who compiled a wide number of resources related to fasting, reciting Qur&amp;#8217;an, and sincerity of intention. This is a great resource of ahadith and ayaat related to fasting. May Allah grant them a great reward (ameen!) and forgive any mistakes I have made in re-formatting it and linking all the sources to their citations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Ramadan Opinion Do I Pick?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 21:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</guid>
      <description>Sight the moon, and if you cannot, then count the days &amp;#8230;  Ramadan is coming, alhamdulillah. Ramadan, a time when all the shayateen are chained up, as the Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said:
 Narrated Abu Huraira (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu): Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said, &amp;#8220;When the month of Ramadan starts, the gates of the heaven are opened and the gates of Hell are closed and the devils are chained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reasons Behind Seasons</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Why did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) create seasons? All of this&amp;#8211;snow, leaves changing, hot summer days and freezing winter nights. In some countries&amp;#8211;like Canada, and the US&amp;#8211;you have places where Isha time starts around 11pm, or 12am (midnight), and Fajr starts arond 2-3am! You also have days where Isha starts at 6pm, and Fajr starts around 7am.
What can we learn from this?
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) gives this away when he narrates: &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) made the night short so you can pray, and the day short so you can fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praying Isha While The Imam Prays Taraweeh</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 17:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s well-known in our communities, alhamdulillah, that you can pray &amp;#8216;Isha behind an imam praying Taraweeh. (Which happens if you run late, very late, indeed!) But we&amp;#8217;re just going to dive a bit into the details of how and why this is.
Note: We do not issue fatwa! For that, please consult Islam Question and Answer!
First of all, there is a difference of opinion among the scholars about whether this is permissible or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local or International Sighting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 16:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</guid>
      <description>As yet another Ramadan comes, the question arises? should we follow the opinion of the local moonsighting, or the international moonsighting? Great arguments erupt, people insulting each other left and right, breaking ties, breaking families &amp;#8230;
Brothers and sisters, ya Muslims, WAKE UP!! Realize that all the opinions which are backed by the scholars are correct!
What? All of them?
Yes. all of them.
How does that work? In Islam, we have scholars (&amp;#8216;ulama), and we have people who have the knowledge and tools and responsibility to give fatwa (mujtahidoon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Islamic Diet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-islamic-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2008 21:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-islamic-diet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We are constantly bombarded in this society with diet after diet, new ways to loose weight or supposedly be &amp;#8216;healthy&amp;#8217;. As Muslims, we know that Allah (سبحانه و تعالى) sent the Qur&amp;#8217;an to us as a huda, a guide. Not only is the Qur&amp;#8217;an a guidance for us in our beliefs, our worship and character, but we learn basic lessons on how to live our lives in a way that is pleasing to Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fasting in Muharram</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/fasting-in-muharram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 07:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/fasting-in-muharram/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
The sacred month of Muharram is now upon us, and a new year has begun alhamdulillah. InshaAllah I wanted to remind you all and myself of the great sunnan this month has for us:
Rasulllah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The best of fasting after Ramadaan is the month of Allah, Muharram, and the best of prayer after the obligatory prayers is prayer at night (qiyaam al-layl).&amp;#8221; [Saheeh Muslim, #1163]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</guid>
      <description>So, another Ramadan has come and gone! 30 days of reading Qur&amp;#8217;an and feeding the poor, 30 nights of Qiyaam-ul-Layl and Taraweeh and Tahajjud. And so, &amp;#8216;Eid comes again.
Congratulations! You have been one of those lucky few who lived to receive this great blessing from Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), this chance to get all your sins forgiven! Because the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever fasts during Ramadan out of sincere faith and hoping to attain Allah&amp;#8217;s rewards, then all his past sins will be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Why Are You Fasting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/so-why-are-you-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 15:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/so-why-are-you-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Why are you fasting? The answer to this questions determines your reward on Judgment Day. Monks fast. Some poeple fast to lose weight. Is it a cultural thing?
Or is it because Allah is worthy of worship, and only He deserves your fast? That you are seeking His reward? This is what the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said&amp;#8211;&amp;#8220;Whoever fasted Ramadan with belief, hoping for the reward from Allah, all his previous sins will be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Amazing Ramadan: Planning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/your-amazing-ramadan-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 14:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/your-amazing-ramadan-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is here, you&amp;#8217;re all excited, praying in the masjid &amp;#8230; but how can you make the MOST of Ramadan? Do you have what it takes to keep your heart in touch, regardless of the distractions around you? To be one of those who look back and realize they&amp;#8217;ve had an AMAZING Ramadan?
Listen to the podcast below to figure out how to plan your Ramadan! Props out to Living Halal for this amazing ilm-tastic podcast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Role Models–Got Any?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2007 08:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-role-models-got-any/</guid>
      <description>Who are your role models? Movie stars? Sports stars? Celebrities? Do we have any role models for Ramadan&amp;#8211;people we can look on to and learn from? Let us take a glimpse at how our pious predecessors and the early generations spent their Ramadan.
Their reading of Qur&amp;#8217;an in Ramadan:
 Salam ibn Abi Muti&amp;#8217; informs us that Qatadah used to normally complete reading the Qur&amp;#8217;an in 7 days, but in Ramadan, he completed it in three days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earn MAXIMUM Profit This Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earn-maximum-profit-this-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 08:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/earn-maximum-profit-this-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah,
Ramadan is of a countable number of days, so we have to be smart, and think about how can we MAXIMIZE the rewards we earn! Inshallah following is a list of ibada that take less time and have big reward. We need to be smart and think like a businessman (small investment -&amp;gt; big profit)
Remember reward of every deed is multiplied in Ramadan.
 Get the reward of hajj and umrah every single day Be smart in your dhikar Get the reward of fasting many Ramadans Get the reward of performing salaah the whole night Earn the reward of reciting one third of Qur&amp;#8217;an in few minutes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prophet’s Sermon on the Reception of Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prophets-sermon-on-the-reception-of-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 11:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prophets-sermon-on-the-reception-of-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Below is a well-published Sermon of the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) on Ramadan; if anyone knows the source, please post it in a comment&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s well-known as far as the internet goes!
  &amp;#8220;Indeed ahead of you is the blessed month of Allah. A month of blessing, mercy and forgiveness. A month which, with Allah, is the best of months. Its days, the best of days, its nights, the best of nights, and its hours, the best of hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Tips</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 10:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-tips/</guid>
      <description>If you’re like me&amp;#8230; and, well, probably a lot of other people, you won’t fully realize that Ramadan is here until you’re dragging yourself out of bed a few hours early to eat while it’s still dark.
Ramadan offers us a very unique opportunity. Ramadan offers us the opportunity to start fresh. It may not necessarily have the &amp;#8220;wash-away-all-your-sins&amp;#8221; publicity that Hajj does, but Ramadan gives us a chance to put ourselves through a mind, body and soul detoxification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-mubarak-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/ramadan-mubarak-2007/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan Mubarak! May Allah allow us all to take the most benefit out of this month, when the good deeds (but also the bad deeds) are multiplied!
The companions&amp;#8211;may Allah be pleased with all of them&amp;#8211;used to ask Allah for 6 months to accept their last Ramadan, and ask Allah for 6 months to allow them to live to see the next Ramadan.
THAT&amp;#8217;S Ramadan for you!
And remember, if you&amp;#8217;re fasting, but not praying the fards&amp;#8211;or you&amp;#8217;re praying taraweeh, but skipping Fajr, Dhur, Asr, Maghrib, or Isha&amp;#8211;you have a big problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitless: Ramadan Planning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</guid>
      <description>My brothers and sisters a blessed month is fast approaching us, a month in which the opportunities are limitless and the reward is ready for taking in abundance. This blessed month, known as Ramadan is approaching us and we will soon say good-bye to it as well.
Inshallah, join me on this journey as we go through some self-planning for this blessed month, and inshallah learn about the one action which is most noble in the sight of Allah&amp;#8230;that action being du&amp;#8217;a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizq Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 01:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/rizq-management/</guid>
      <description>Rizq Management  Rizq Management is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef. The course focuses on three pillars of Islam: Zakaah, Siyaam, and Hajj. Which moon opinion is correct&amp;#8211;one of them? _All_of them? Does chewing gum break your fast? (Why or why not?) Does a woman pay zakaah on her gold jewelry?
Learn about these three fundamental pillars of Islam, and how to not only perform, but how to benefit from them at the highest level!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Days of the Year</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2006 00:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-days-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>Are you a student, or working? Are you depressed or frustrated that you could not take the advantage of the last ten nights of Ramadan? There were midterms, assignments, and projects for all the working folk, all those cliched reasons, or maybe you did take advantage. Here is another chance. Its on our doorsteps, the most beloved days to Allah, the first ten days of Dhul Hijjah.
It was reported by Ibn ‘Abbas (رضي الله عنه) that the Rasoolullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;There are no days in which righteous deeds are more beloved to Allah than these ten days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Days of Shawwal</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-days-of-shawwal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2006 12:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-days-of-shawwal/</guid>
      <description>Now that Ramadan&amp;#8217;s over, many of us feel sad&amp;#8211;we miss the spirituality, the eman rush, the amazing strength that we all demonstrate in Ramadan. So what can you do to bring those feelings back?
One thing is to keep performing the deeds you performed in Ramadan&amp;#8211;and this is one of the signs that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) accepted your deeds.
Another act you can perform is to fast six days of Shawwal, the month right after Ramadan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006/</guid>
      <description>Just like we have different starting dates for Ramadan, we have different Eid dates.
And you know what? That&amp;#8217;s ok. Why? Because it&amp;#8217;s all based on legitimate difference of opinion. Not some beardy guy making stuff up because he feels like it.
So when &amp;#8216;Eid rolls around, enjoy it, and don&amp;#8217;t hate on other people for when they celebrate. That&amp;#8217;s messed up.
By the way&amp;#8211;when &amp;#8216;Eid rolls around, remember this: you just fasted for 30 days straight, give or take a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purpose of Fasting</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-purpose-of-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2006 19:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-purpose-of-fasting/</guid>
      <description>One of the verses of the Qur&amp;#8217;an we hear all the time in the context of fasting is this one:
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ كُتِبَ عَلَيْكُمُ الصِّيَامُ كَمَا كُتِبَ عَلَى الَّذِينَ مِن قَبْلِكُمْ لَعَلَّكُمْ تَتَّقُونَ  Translation: O you who believe! Allah prescribed fasting upon you, as it He prescribed for those before you, that you may attain taqwa (piety, God-consciousness). [Al-Baqarah, 2:183]
Those last two words summarize the entire purpose of fasting: to attain taqwa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Burn-Out</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-burn-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-burn-out/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan is the month of Qur&amp;#8217;an. A month where many of us fast, pray Taraweeh, pray Qiyam al-Layl, and read the entire Qur&amp;#8217;an&amp;#8211;maybe more then once!
But subhanallah, in our love for Ramadan and our zeal for good deeds, we sometimes aim to accomplish more then our human capacity. We&amp;#8217;re humans, we all have limits.
But people say &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to read the WHOLE QUR&amp;#8217;AN this time!&amp;#8221; when they can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8211;sometimes, even reading only one juz, maybe even the last juz, is an accomplishment for them, one within their ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Sunnahs of Fasting</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-sunnahs-of-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 20:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-sunnahs-of-fasting/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) taught us five favourable (mustahab or &amp;#8220;sunnah&amp;#8221;) actions for us to follow while fasting. These are:
 Hasten Iftaar: When Maghrib time arrives, hasten to break your fast&amp;#8211;do not delay. It&amp;#8217;s said that he, (صلي الله عليه وسلم), sent Bilal (رضي الله عنه) to stand on top of a high-up hill to see when the sun set, then broke his fast immediately. Eat Suhoor: A lot of cultures teach us to skip suhoor and start fasting when we sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-mubarak-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2006 17:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-mubarak-2006/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan Mubarak to you and your families! May Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) make this a most blessed and beneficial month for you all, and a source of taqwa and eman for the whole year, ameen!
Subhanallah, one of the companions of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) even said, &amp;#8220;We spend half the year making du&amp;#8217;a for Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to allow us to see another Ramdaaan, and we spend half the year making du&amp;#8217;a for Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) to accept the Ramdaan that passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramadan: The Excuse-Killer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2006 16:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/ramadan-the-excuse-killer/</guid>
      <description>Ramadan kills all the excuses we make for ourselves throughout the year, and allows us to soar to new heights of eman! If someone said to you, &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s go to the masjid every day,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! If someone said &amp;#8220;let&amp;#8217;s play Qiyam al-Layl all night,&amp;#8221; you&amp;#8217;d say &amp;#8220;we can&amp;#8217;t do it!&amp;#8221; but, in Ramdan, you do it! Subhanallah, in Ramdan, wishes and hopes and dreams can become reality!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moonsighting or Moonfighting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/moonsighting-or-moonfighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 17:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/moonsighting-or-moonfighting/</guid>
      <description>In many countries (mostly Western countries&amp;#8211;America, Canada, Europe, etc.) our communities fight over the actual start date of Ramadan. This, itself, is not so bad&amp;#8211;because, alhamdulillah, everyone backs up their opinion with a legitimate fiqh source (more on that in a second). However, the problem is that people in the same region fast on different days&amp;#8211;sometimes, even two people in the same house fast on different days!
So how do we go about picking an appropriate date to start fasting?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>