<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Usool Ul Fiqh on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/usool-ul-fiqh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Usool Ul Fiqh on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 21:49:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/usool-ul-fiqh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Culture vs. Religion</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/understanding-culture-vs-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 21:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/understanding-culture-vs-religion/</guid>
      <description>As we continue our foray into Medini seerah, we notice that Medinah, at the time of hijrah, was divided culturally. It contained three distinct groups: Al-Aws, Al-Khazraj, and the Jews. All three held roughly equal power, with no one being significantly stronger than the other; Medinah had no clear leader who all the groups answered to.
Medinah was not only multi-cultural, but multi-religious! Which brings us to an important discussion: what is the difference between culture and religion, and how do we find a balance bewteen the two?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikhtilaf – I</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/ikhtilaf-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/ikhtilaf-i/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we introduced the topic of Differences of Opinions. We listed the four ways of categorizing these differences. In this post, we will look at the first category: Differences due to interpretation of word meanings and grammatical constructions.
Within this category, we have several sub categories:
Shared literal meanings/Equivocality/Homonym (Ishtirak):
An example of this would be the word &amp;#8220;qur&amp;#8221; which means menses as well as the time of purity between menses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcdonald, KFC, Moon Sighting…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 23:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</guid>
      <description>Muslims, living in the Muslim Countries, generally tend to have limited exposure to Fiqh and its rulings. There is usually one dominant madhab and that&amp;#8217;s all people know about. Rarely, if ever, people are exposed to other madahibs. However, the situation for many of us living in west, like Canada, is quite different.
Because of the diversity of muslims, from various countries, cultures and backgrounds, we are exposed to many madhabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Ramadan Opinion Do I Pick?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 21:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</guid>
      <description>Sight the moon, and if you cannot, then count the days &amp;#8230;  Ramadan is coming, alhamdulillah. Ramadan, a time when all the shayateen are chained up, as the Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said:
 Narrated Abu Huraira (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu): Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said, &amp;#8220;When the month of Ramadan starts, the gates of the heaven are opened and the gates of Hell are closed and the devils are chained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local or International Sighting?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 16:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/local-or-international-sighting/</guid>
      <description>As yet another Ramadan comes, the question arises? should we follow the opinion of the local moonsighting, or the international moonsighting? Great arguments erupt, people insulting each other left and right, breaking ties, breaking families &amp;#8230;
Brothers and sisters, ya Muslims, WAKE UP!! Realize that all the opinions which are backed by the scholars are correct!
What? All of them?
Yes. all of them.
How does that work? In Islam, we have scholars (&amp;#8216;ulama), and we have people who have the knowledge and tools and responsibility to give fatwa (mujtahidoon).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Sources of Islamic Law (Pt.7)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-sources-of-islamic-law-pt7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 15:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-sources-of-islamic-law-pt7/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
To continue, last post we discussed the details of the sunnah. We explained how the sunnah is comprised of the saying and actions of the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam along with his tacit approvals and that which he left given the need. We also summarized how the sunnah came to explain the Qur&amp;#8217;an by detailing rulings which were very general in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, by limited what seemed absolute, by affirming what Allah said in the Qur&amp;#8217;an, and by bringing rulings which are not directly found in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Sources of Islamic Law (Pt. 6)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-sources-of-islamic-law-pt-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 19:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-sources-of-islamic-law-pt-6/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
Continuing in our talks about the science of fiqh, today we will look at the sources of Islamic Law.
As we know the sources of Islamic Law depend on two core sources: al-Qur&amp;#8217;an and as-Sunnah. These two sources are the basis of which our religion is based upon. One without the under is not Islam, for verily they both go hand in hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Foundation Stage (Pt.5)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 15:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt5/</guid>
      <description>So far, we have come to realize that Allah azza wa jal revealed the Qur&amp;#8217;an to reform human conditions; to take people out of ignorance and darkness and into light. To carry out this purpose laws had to be enacted to make sure the system of Islaam was established perfectly and correctly. Last article we talked about two of the four basic principles relating to Qur&amp;#8217;anic revelation. We will continue with the last two now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Foundation Stage (Pt.4)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 15:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt4/</guid>
      <description>As we discussed in the last post, the method of legislation was primarily through the questioning of the Companions radhiAllah anhum to which Allah revealed verses to answer their inquiries or the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam answered them.
Its important to make clear here that the Prophet sallalalahu alayhi wasalam did not speak from his own desires; meaning, that which he answered was a type of revelation and not just from his whims and desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Foundation Stage (Pt.3)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-foundation-stage-pt3/</guid>
      <description>As per the last discussion, the Foundational stages of Fiqh are characterized by the Prophethood of our beloved Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam. It is in the life time of the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam that rules, which would govern fiqh for generations to come, were established. These rules were established via the statements of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala found in the Qur&amp;#8217;an and also the Sunnah of the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: The Stages (Pt. 2)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-the-stages-pt-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2008 05:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-the-stages-pt-2/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
It is imperative to realize that fiqh has gone through many developments/stages, which traditionally fall into six categories:
 Foundational Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the Prophethood of Muhammad sallalahu alayhi wasalam which lasted for 23 years (610 &amp;#8211; 632 CE) Establishment Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the Righteous Caliphs radhiAllah anhum which lasted for 29 years from the death of the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam (632 CE) to the midle of the 7th century (661 CE) Building Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the founding of the Umayyad dynasty until its decline to the middle of the 8th century Flowering Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the rise of the &amp;#8216;Abbaasid dynasty in the middle of the 8th century to the beginning of its decline around the middle of the 10th century Consolidation Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the decline of the &amp;#8216;Abbaasid dynasty to the murder of the last &amp;#8216;Abbaasid Caliph in the middle of the 13th century Stagnation and Decline Stage &amp;#8211; This period is characterized by the sacking of Baghdad in 1258 CE to our present times  This gives us a brief overview of the developments of fiqh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Fiqh: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 01:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/understanding-fiqh-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
When we begin to talk about a field of study in the religion of Islam it is very imperative we begin by defining the terms; making clear the terminology which is used throughout that field of study. With that said, I want to focus on Fiqh.
Linguistically, fiqh is defined as the true understanding of what is intended. For example: The true understanding of Anatomy, the true understanding of Plants, or the true understanding of Religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fard vs. Wajib</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/fard-vs-wajib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 09:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/fard-vs-wajib/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people&amp;#8211;especially new Muslims&amp;#8211;break their heads on this conundrum. What is the difference between fard and wajib? Are they the same? Are they different? What&amp;#8217;s the scoop? Why do some people say fard, while others say wajib for the same things?
The answer is simple. According to the majority of scholars, fard and wajib mean the EXACT same thing. There is no difference. They are interchangable. (Recall that fard means: an action that, if performed, entails reward, and if neglected, entails punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sofa Fard, Bucket-Seat Fard</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sofa-fard-bucket-seat-fard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2007 14:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sofa-fard-bucket-seat-fard/</guid>
      <description>Fard: technically, it means any action which, if done, deserves reward from Allah; and if neglected, deserves punishment from Allah. (Yes, that&amp;#8217;s right&amp;#8211;you actually earn reward for doing all those fard actions!)
Here, we discuss two classifications of faraaid&amp;#8211;Sofa Fard, and Bucket-Seat Fard.
Sofa Fard   
Sofa Fard (also known as Fard Muwassa&amp;#8217;) is a fard which you have a choice of when you can do it. It&amp;#8217;s like a sofa&amp;#8211;you can sit on the left, on the right, in the middle, anywhere you want!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pen is Lifted From Three</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pen-is-lifted-from-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2007 11:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pen-is-lifted-from-three/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The Pen is lifted from three (i.e., their deeds are not recorded):
 a child until he reaches puberty; an insane man until he comes to his senses; one who is asleep until he wakes up.&amp;#8221;  [Recorded in Abu Dawud #4403, and Ibn Majah #2041]
This is an important hadith, fundamental to usool-ul-fiqh. This hadith applies in practically every situation and with every issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Scholars</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/code-of-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 12:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/code-of-scholars/</guid>
      <description>Code of Scholars  Code of Scholars is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef. The course teaches the basics of the science of Usool ul-Fiqh, derived from the Qur&amp;#8217;an and Sunnah. What does haram mean? Who makes laws? What are the different types of fard actions? What Arabic keywords indicate something is haram? Students who succeed gain the ability to analyze contradicting fatawa and determine which are more correct islamically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Categories of Everything</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2006 21:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-categories-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>Those five categories of all actions&amp;#8211;fard (also known as wajib), mustahab (sometimes called &amp;#8220;sunnah&amp;#8221;), mubah, makrooh, and haram&amp;#8211;what do they really mean? While you can understand these from different angles, we explain these from an Usool-ul-Fiqh perspective. Here they are:
    Fard/Wajib (obligatory) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn a punishment from abstaining from. Examples include praying, fasting, etc.
Mustahab/Sunnah (recommended) means any action that you earn a reward for performing, and earn nothing from abstaining from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is the Law Maker?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/who-is-the-law-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 01:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/who-is-the-law-maker/</guid>
      <description>Every specific Islamic rule originates from a law maker. Here, we investigate who can say, in Islam, that something is the law.
Allah is the Law Maker!  Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), Lord of the Worlds, is the law maker. None can dispute His laws. What&amp;#8217;s the proof? In Surah Yusuf Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:
إِنِ الْحُكْمُ إِلاَّ لِلّهِ أَمَرَ أَلاَّ تَعْبُدُواْ إِلاَّ إِيَّاهُ ذَلِكَ الدِّينُ الْقَيِّمُ وَلَـكِنَّ أَكْثَرَ النَّاسِ لاَ يَعْلَمُونَ  Translation: the command is for none but Allah: He hath commanded that ye worship none but Him: that is the right deen, but most men understand not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>