<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Islamic Work on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/islamic-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Islamic Work on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 15:47:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/islamic-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reality of Time</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-reality-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 15:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-reality-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is our 14th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/clock.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;85741170&#34; title=&#34;85741170&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1147&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah says, in Surah &amp;#8216;Asr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالْعَصْرِ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;إِنَّ الْإِنسَانَ لَفِي خُسْرٍ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;إِلَّا الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ وَتَوَاصَوْا بِالْحَقِّ وَتَوَاصَوْا بِالصَّبْرِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;By Time. Indeed, mankind is at loss. Except for those who have believed, done righteous deeds and advised each other to truth and advised each other to patience.&amp;#8221; [Asr: 1-3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah swears by time&amp;#8211;which shows how enormous and noble this creation is. Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imam Shafi said about this revelation that had it been the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; revelation sent to mankind, it would have been enough.  What motivated him to say this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Inshrah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-inshrah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 14:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-inshrah/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is our 13th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
Stand up and do more. Muslims don&amp;#8217;t retire or quit from working for the deen. Persist. Be like the flower that springs through concrete.
Allah says, in verse 3:
 وَرَفَعْنَا لَكَ ذِكْرَكَ
 Translation: And raised high for you your repute.
If you see those polls on CNN and BBC and all those places, &amp;#8220;Who is the most famous person in the world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer of Surah Duhaa</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 18:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-of-surah-duhaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this is our 12th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/breakfast-on-bed.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1118&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;
  Islam is about social service and shukr (thankfulness).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insha&amp;#8217;Allah in this post, we&amp;#8217;re going to discuss three points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The close relationship between Allah and His prophet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A glimpse of Paradise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A core theme of social services in Islam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) received revelation prior to Surah Duhaa. Then for a while, nothing. Umm Jameelah, the wife of Abu Lahab, came to him and said: &amp;#8220;I hope your shaytaan has finally left you.&amp;#8221; Because the Arabs used to say, if someone was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good at something, that they had a shaytaan helping them. (No doubt like some of the musicians today.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still nothing came. The people began to talk &amp;#8230; and they said, maybe his Lord has left him. Maybe He has abandoned him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so Allah revealed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Duhaa, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالضُّحَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَاللَّيْلِ إِذَا سَجَى&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;مَا وَدَّعَكَ رَبُّكَ وَمَا قَلَى&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By duhaa (the morning brightness after Fajr), and [by] the night when it covers with darkness, your Lord has not taken leave of you, [O Muúammad], nor has He detested [you].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[This hadith is found in Bukhari and Muslim, and is quoted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://tafsir.com/default.asp?sid=93&amp;amp;tid=58628&#34;&gt;Tafseer ibn Katheer&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows us two things: first, that the people &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; when revelation came; that it was a big deal, and everybody knew about it. And second, &lt;span class=&#34;gem&#34;&gt;the immense love of Allah for His prophet.&lt;/span&gt; How close their relationship&amp;#8211;that even something as small as this stress, Allah revealed verses on behalf of the prophet, to reassure him. Subhanallah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, Allah &lt;em&gt;swears&lt;/em&gt; by duhaa&amp;#8211;by the brightness of the day right after the sun has come up&amp;#8211;and by the night, as it covers up the day with darkness. (This shows the greatness of these creations&amp;#8211;that Allah swears by them. Who would deny these things? Nobody!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex in Western Culture</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sex-in-western-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 09:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/sex-in-western-culture/</guid>
      <description>The hypocrisy of Western Modern culture is amazing! We need to realize that Islam began as something strange, and will end as something strange, so we need not worry what people think of us; rather, we need to be people that respect and fear Allah (سبحانه وتعال), and the creation of Allah (the people) come second.
Legal marriage age is 16? 18? but:
It&amp;#8217;s okay for 14-year-old teens to have sex , and their parents having no idea about it, and it&amp;#8217;s with someone they may not approve of, and the person may not have their son or daughter&amp;#8217;s best interest at heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victory Comes With Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 12:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/victory-comes-with-patience/</guid>
      <description>The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said to his cousin: &amp;#8220;And know that victory comes with patience, relief with affliction, and ease with hardship. 1
Even in the battle of Qadisiyyah, after fighting through the whole day, the Muslim leader said &amp;#8220;just be patient, and keep fighting.&amp;#8221; Even into the night, when most armies stop fighting at night! But subhanallah, what happened? By the next morning, the Muslims had won.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Distance of One Mile</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/a-distance-of-one-mile/</guid>
      <description>In a very beautiful hadith, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: __
 “There are seven whom Allah will shade in His Shade on the Day when there is no shade except His Shade:
 a just ruler; a youth who grew up in the worship of Allah, the Mighty and Majestic; a man whose heart is attached to the mosques; two men who love each other for Allah’s sake, meeting for that and parting upon that; a man who is called by a woman of beauty and position [for illegal intercourse], but be says: ‘I fear Allah’; a man who gives in charity and hides it, such that his left hand does not know what his right hand gives in charity; and a man who remembered Allah in private and so his eyes shed tears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 16:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/thank-you-allah/</guid>
      <description>Innal-Hamdu lillah was-Salaatu was-Salaam `alaa Rasoolillah
&amp;ldquo;Lucky escape &amp;hellip; hmmm &amp;hellip; Nah! It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t my time to go yet; Allah saved me and gave me a little longer &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Driving home from work after having a late staff meeting, it was an ordinary evening not much traffic on the road. I got onto the dual carriage, I was in the right lane doing around 60-70 miles an hour, then all of a sudden *BANG* the bonnet of my car flew open and smashed against my car windscreen, *SMASH* all the glass cracked and from the great impact, my back view mirror had completely broken off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water, Soil, Plants, Fruit, Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 05:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that your time is water. Every day, you get 24 liters to use as you wish. You keep it in one giant metal bucket and carry it around with you. The bucket leaks&amp;#8211;if you don&amp;#8217;t pour your time into buckets and use it effectively, most of it will end up spilled on the ground, lost.
Each day, you pass by some plants, and you have to stop and water them, or they die&amp;#8211;the big, thick bush of family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Responsibility, Spread the Message</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-responsibility-spread-the-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 03:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-responsibility-spread-the-message/</guid>
      <description>In the Qur&amp;#8217;an, surah Nisaa, Allah says:
فَقَاتِلْ فِي سَبِيلِ اللّهِ لاَ تُكَلَّفُ إِلاَّ نَفْسَكَ وَحَرِّضِ الْمُؤْمِنِينَ عَسَى اللّهُ أَن يَكُفَّ بَأْسَ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُواْ وَاللّهُ أَشَدُّ بَأْسًا وَأَشَدُّ تَنكِيلاً  Translation: Then fight in Allah’s cause &amp;#8211; you are responsible only for yourself &amp;#8211; and rouse the believers. It may be that Allah will restrain the fury of the Unbelievers; for Allah is the strongest in might and in punishment (Surah Nisaa, 4:84)1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Brings Change</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pain-brings-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 20:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pain-brings-change/</guid>
      <description>Pain is often an instigator of change. Pain works as one method to break people out of their cycles or mindsets.
Look at the story of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab, may Allah be pleased with him. In Mecca, before he became Muslim, he was one of the toughest on the Muslims.
One of his relatives, Umm Abdullah, prepared to leave for Habasha. He asked &amp;#8220;where are you going?&amp;#8221; and she said &amp;#8220;To Habasha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing to Good Deeds: Abu Dujana and the Prophet’s Sword</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 05:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</guid>
      <description>Before the battle of Uhud, when the Muslims were preparing and such, the Prophet, peace be upon him, lifted up his sword and said &amp;#8220;who will fight with my sword?&amp;#8221;
And all the sahaba were like &amp;#8220;me, me&amp;#8221;, like &amp;#8220;pick me&amp;#8221;. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) put down his sword. Their emotions were raised.
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) raised it again and said &amp;#8220;who will take my sword and give it the haq (right) due to the sword?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (13): Your Purpose on Earth</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2006 03:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-13/</guid>
      <description>The king asked the boy to renounce his religion, to which the boy refused. The king said &amp;#8220;take him to the highest mountain and if he doesn&amp;#8217;t renounce by the time you reach the top, throw him off.&amp;#8221;
Why not saw him in half? Because the boy&amp;#8217;s useful. He has influence among the poeple. People love him, and if he joins the king, many will follow his example.
So they took him up, and the boy said &amp;#8220;O Allah, suffice me against them in whatever way You please&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of the Ditch (9): Honouring vs. Prophetic Miracles</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 23:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-people-of-the-ditch-9/</guid>
      <description>The boy healed the blind and the lepers&amp;#8211;the same miracles given to the prophet &amp;#8216;Isa (Jesus), on whom be peace.
Was he a prophet?
No, he was not.
The difference is: Allah gave the boy karamah, a less intense form of mu&amp;#8217;jizah. In a way, karamah mimics mu&amp;#8217;jizah, but to a less intense level.
The boy&amp;#8217;s powers mimiced the miracles of &amp;#8216;Isa (alayhi salaam), to a lesser level. And while &amp;#8216;Isa (alayhi salaam) could resurrect the dead, the boy could not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Use of Your Skills for Da’wah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-use-of-your-skills-for-dawah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 20:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-best-use-of-your-skills-for-dawah/</guid>
      <description>If you have multiple skills and multiple interests, how can you determine the best use of your skills for da&amp;#8217;wah? Try this method inshaAllah.
 Skills: List all your skills. Ummah: Prioirtize the needs of the ummah (i.e. your community). Map and Prioritize: Tie each skill to an action, and prioritize according to need.  For example, if your skills are writing, graphic design, and drama, and your ummah needs youth involvement and education, you may decide to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Time For Yourself: Avoid Burnout</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/make-time-for-yourself-avoid-burnout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2006 04:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/make-time-for-yourself-avoid-burnout/</guid>
      <description>When you get involved in da&amp;#8217;wah, don&amp;#8217;t forget yourself. We see many examples of this&amp;#8211;people join the local MSA, and spend 40 hours a week to keep it alive. And the next year, you see them in the bar, with their girlfriend or boyfriend. Or others spend months putting together The Biggest Conference Ever, and while it goes on, they miss all the lectures and mill around outside with their friends, or out in the parking lot arguing about lunches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Sacrifice</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/benefits-of-sacrifice-tafseer-surah-nisaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 20:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/benefits-of-sacrifice-tafseer-surah-nisaa/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Nisaa, Allah says:
وَلَوْ أَنَّا كَتَبْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ أَنِ اقْتُلُواْ أَنفُسَكُمْ أَوِ اخْرُجُواْ مِن دِيَارِكُم مَّا فَعَلُوهُ إِلاَّ قَلِيلٌ مِّنْهُمْ وَلَوْ أَنَّهُمْ فَعَلُواْ مَا يُوعَظُونَ بِهِ لَكَانَ خَيْرًا لَّهُمْ وَأَشَدَّ تَثْبِيتًا
وَإِذاً لَّآتَيْنَاهُم مِّن لَّدُنَّـا أَجْراً عَظِيمًا
وَلَهَدَيْنَاهُمْ صِرَاطًا مُّسْتَقِيمًا  Translation: If We had ordered them to sacrifice their lives or to leave their homes, very few of them would have done it. But if they had done what they were (actually) told, it would have been best for them, and would have gone farthest to strengthen their (faith).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling: A Fundamental Da’wah Technique</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 22:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>Storytelling is a fundamental da&amp;#8217;wah technique. It effortlessly communicates a message in a memorable medium. Storytelling is so powerful that you see it in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (Surah Baqarah and Surah Yusuf, for example), in ahadith (The People of the Ditch).
Among the benefits: storytelling communicates a message without spelling it out. Human beings recall stories more easily then they recall other forms of teaching. With a story, you can continually extract lessons and benefit from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Interaction: Professionalism</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 04:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/gender-interaction-professionalism/</guid>
      <description>The key to gender interaction (aka gender relations) is professionalism. During the lifetime of the Prophet, peace be upon him, &amp;#8216;Umar said to one woman sahaba in Abysinnia: &amp;#8220;We have more right to the Prophet then you&amp;#8221;. She said (to the effect of) &amp;#8220;nope&amp;#8221;. She approached the Prophet and narrated the incident to him, and he said &amp;#8220;&amp;#8216;Umar was incorrect. You (Abyssinians) made hijrah (migration) twice, you get double the reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Measure of Leadership</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-true-measure-of-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2006 04:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-true-measure-of-leadership/</guid>
      <description>The true measure of leadership is influence, nothing more, and nothing less. When you can influence people, you&amp;#8217;re a leader, even if nobody recognizes you. And when you can&amp;#8217;t influence people, you&amp;#8217;re not a leader &amp;#8212; even if the masjid says so, or the organization says so, or your friends say so, or your car says so.
And remember the command of the Prophet, peace be upon him: Do not covet leadership, for it entails blame, regret, and punishment on the Day of Judgement &amp;#8212; except for the just ruler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Leaders, Not Followers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/train-leaders-not-followers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2006 03:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/train-leaders-not-followers/</guid>
      <description>If you want your Islamic work&amp;#8211;your project, or organization, or masjid, or whatever it is&amp;#8211;to survive you, you need to train leaders, not followers.
When you train followers, they work well, for a time&amp;#8211;a month, or two, or a year, or ten, or 20&amp;#8211;but without a leader, the project collapses. Instead, train leaders, who in turn train followers and other leaders in your absence, and the cycle perpetuates inshaAllah.
This is also part of what you need to transform your project from a mom-and-pop-style business to an independant self-existing entity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khalid bin Walid: From General to Foot-Soldier</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 05:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/khalid-bin-walid-from-general-to-foot-soldier/</guid>
      <description>During the reign of Prophet Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم), and later, the reign of Abu Bakr, the first Khalifa, may Allah be pleased with him, Khalid bin Walid, commander of the Muslim army, rocked the non-Muslim armies again and again and again and lead the Muslims to many victories. In this way, he became a fitnah&amp;#8211;people ascribed victory to him, and not to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى).
After the battle of Yarmuk, the newly-instated Khalifa, &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab (may Allah be pleased with him) removed Khalid bin Walid from leadership of the army and instated Abu Ubaydah (RA) as the commander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Label</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-label/</guid>
      <description>Never label. Human beings are not two-dimensional that you can slap a label onto them and classify them. One of the best ways to destroy ties between people, groups, and organizations is to label them. Even if they deserve it, don&amp;#8217;t do it.
When you find yourself applying a label to someone, ask yourself: Will this action please Allah (سبحانه وتعالى)?
When you find others who label, back away. You don&amp;#8217;t want to involve yourself with people like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Tactic: The Trench Rush</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/business-tactic-the-trench-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/business-tactic-the-trench-rush/</guid>
      <description>In one of the battles in the time of the Khulafa Rashideen, the Muslim armies attacked a fort behind a trench.
With a trench, defenses spread thin: 500 people need to guard all points of the trench. So in any given area, you have only a few guards.
How did the Muslims succeed? They find the one lazy guy&amp;#8211;if the trench is eight feet deep and six feet across, they find the location two feet deep and one foot across&amp;#8211;and focus the entire army towards that one location, all the hundreds or thousands of mujahideen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute Ideas Without Perfection</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/execute-ideas-without-perfection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 00:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/execute-ideas-without-perfection/</guid>
      <description>If you have an idea, execute it, even if it won&amp;#8217;t turn out perfect. Ihsaan is not perfection, it&amp;#8217;s excellence. Strive your best, but tolerate mistakes as well. Only Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) is perfect.
Don&amp;#8217;t be like the shopkeeper who keeps the door to his shop closed all the time in order to keep it clean. No customers enter. If you&amp;#8217;re always closed and looking for perfection, you&amp;#8217;ll shut down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultation (Shura): A Fundamental Leadership Technique</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 02:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/consultation-shura-a-fundamental-leadership-technique/</guid>
      <description>Consultation, or shura, is a fundamental leadership technique in Islam. You consult with the experts, and you implement it, and you close the issue. Shura means consultation. It also means the consulted group. Shura is a fundamental technique in leadership. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), the best and most knowledable and noble of people, practiced shura with his companions&amp;#8211;and who knew better than he? How can the rest of us believe we don&amp;#8217;t need shura?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dedication of the Sahaba</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-dedication-of-the-sahaba/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 04:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-dedication-of-the-sahaba/</guid>
      <description>The dedication of sahaba is no joke. They strove beyond the physical limtations of their bodies. When they couldn&amp;#8217;t stand, or open their eyes, they continued. Their dedication to Allah transcended their bodies.
In the battle of Yamamah, when Abdullah ibn &amp;#8216;Umar (RA) lay in the nursing docks after one battle, he heard a shout from outside&amp;#8211;ya ahlil ansar, &amp;#8220;o people of the Ansar&amp;#8221;. He spotted an ansari nearby&amp;#8211;a man critically injured, couldn&amp;#8217;t walk, incapacitated, being nursed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amir Competition, Tribe Competition</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amir-competition-tribe-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/amir-competition-tribe-competition/</guid>
      <description>The illustrious sahaba (companions of the Prophet), may Allah be pleased with all of them, competed in righteousness. They did not compete for the largest house or the biggest family. They competed, among other things, for the honour of guard ingthe Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) in battle.
They divided into tribes and competed with other tribes. The amirs, too, competed with each other. For example, in the campaign in Ash-Sham, the two armies competed&amp;#8211;who could be the fastest to fight their way to the key city?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotions Misguide</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emotions-misguide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/emotions-misguide/</guid>
      <description>After the death of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), many tribes apostated from Islam. Some stopped paying zakaah (poor-due), and some tribe leaders claimed prophethood. Many of the common people at that time lacked education. The emotional charge of the situation swept up many of the Muslims.
Protect yourself. If you allow the river of emotion to sweep you up, in a lot of cases, it will misguide you towards the wrong direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Hold Back Your Talents</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/never-hold-back-your-talents/</guid>
      <description>If you possess some skill you can utilize to the benefit of the people everywhere, never hold back. Don&amp;#8217;t hold it to yourself. Forget about what other people are thinking. Focus on how they can benefit from it. This applies especially if a) you have relatively rare talents, or b) nobody knows about your skills.
Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with Ihsaan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</guid>
      <description>As Islamic workers, we never lower our standers. Not as volunteers, not as professionals, and not as Muslims. Always strive to the best of your abilities. And inshaAllah this way, your skills and talent grow faster than if you barely use them.
Never fall into the trap of so many people who produce second-rate material &amp;#8220;just because&amp;#8221; it&amp;#8217;s for Islamic work, and not for their own (percieved/worldly) benefit.
And remember: ihsaan means excellence, not perfection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Teachers Need Good Students (and Vice-Versa)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/good-teachers-need-good-students-and-vice-versa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/good-teachers-need-good-students-and-vice-versa/</guid>
      <description>Good teachers need good students, and good students need good teachers. When either teachers or students are not up to par, knowledge wastes. Either the teacher fails to teach at their best capability, or the students learn nothing. The same concept can apply to leadership&amp;#8211;good leaders require good followers, and good followers require good leaders.
Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim. Are YOU a good teacher and a good student?
Something to think about inshaAllah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence Leaders, Don’t Import!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/influence-leaders-dont-import/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 00:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/influence-leaders-dont-import/</guid>
      <description>Influence leaders, don&amp;#8217;t import your own. When you need to influence masses of people towards your ideology (da&amp;#8217;wah) or project or cause, don&amp;#8217;t bring your speaker in to preach to them. It doesn&amp;#8217;t consistantly work&amp;#8211;if the people don&amp;#8217;t know your leader, they can&amp;#8217;t trust him, and most will refuse to follow him.
Instead, influence the leader of the people you wish to lead. Once he agrees to your cause, he automatically spreads it to those who follow him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest and Build Excellent Workers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/invest-and-build-excellent-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 00:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/invest-and-build-excellent-workers/</guid>
      <description>Good workers are rare. Great workers are more rare. Outstanding workers are still more rare. Instead of investing hundreds of hours in the search for excellent workers, take what you can get&amp;#8211;given that they hold some of the attributes you need, and the potential to grow&amp;#8211;and increase them in their excellence.
This way, not only do you benefit from the work they produce, but they benefit from the training. Think of it as an investment that pays off long-term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When you Choose a Leader, Someone ALWAYS Disagrees</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-you-choose-a-leader-someone-always-disagrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 23:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/when-you-choose-a-leader-someone-always-disagrees/</guid>
      <description>When you choose a leader, someone always disagrees with you. No matter who you are and who your leader is, you cannot please everyone. So get used to it inshaAllah.
During the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) chose &amp;#8216;Usama ibn Zayd (son of Zayid ibn Thabit, may Allah be pleased with them both) as the leader of the army. And they had high-status alumni sahaba in that army, like &amp;#8216;Umar ibn Al-Khattab (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anh), who was in his 40s or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership at the Front and Leadership from the Back</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 23:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-at-the-front-and-leadership-from-the-back/</guid>
      <description>Front Leaders: These leaders take charge, set the vision, and lead the way. They take the initiative, and step up to the call when Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) calls them.
Back Leaders: These leaders encourage, gather everyone&amp;#8217;s opinion, call meetings, and encourage mutual agreement and compromise.
In Islaimc work, and in any project, you need both types of leadership. Like when a group hikes through a trail. You need someone at the front to pick the path and set the pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Management: Abstraction</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/effective-management-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 22:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/effective-management-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Abstraction: Selective ignorance of certain elements in order to focus on other elements.
In software development, abstraction means you zoom out and see the big picture. You ignore minor implementation details&amp;#8211;what are the little pieces? How do they work?&amp;#8211;and focus on the whole. These are the systems and how they fit together, and this is the overall goal.
When you employ abstraction, efficiency increases. No longer bogged down with function pointers, memory management, or 16-bit register values, you focus on how to make your software work better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Meetings: Two Cents and Two Sentences</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/productive-meetings-two-cents-and-two-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 03:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/productive-meetings-two-cents-and-two-sentences/</guid>
      <description>To optimize your meetings and keep them clear, concise, and on-topic, follow the following two rules as much as possible:
Two Cents: Keep your two cents out of it. Nobody wants to hear your opinion anyway, and spewing one opinion denies other opinions their right. When you compound personal opinion with rebuttal with re-rebuttal, your main topic quickly derails. (Never tolerate deviations from this rule.)
Two Sentences: _When you speak, l_imit your dialogue to two sentences max.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Beard can be Weird</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2006 02:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/behind-the-beard-can-be-weird/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t judge a book by its cover or a man by his beard, because what&amp;#8217;s behind the beard can be weird.&amp;#8221; Apply this to your lives, and you&amp;#8217;ll find that, bi ithnillah (by the permission of Allah), you will never be surprised or dissapointed. When you make great assumptions about people, where can they go except down?
Great assumptions often lead to great letdowns. Wallahu &amp;#8216;alim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiTimer: Multiple Labeled Item Timers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</guid>
      <description>MultiTimer, a lightweight application, allows you to track your time commitments to multiple items simultaneously. You type in the timer label, set the inital time and count method (countup or countdown), and the application handles the rest.
In particular, if you need to track (and, optionally, aggregate) time usage for multiple projects, you can assign one timer per project and track your time use per day. Or per week. Or per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</guid>
      <description>This article by Steve Pavlina explains how to effectively manage your life by focusing on tasks based on their long-term effects.
The article defines three categories of tasks, and allocates your daily time to each of them proportionally based on their expected benefit.
 &amp;#8220;A&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in five or more years, such as learning a new language. &amp;#8220;B&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in two or more years, such as training for a marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Work: A Lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/islamic-work-a-lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 01:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/islamic-work-a-lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Islamic work isn&amp;#8217;t something we do for a hobby&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s our life.&amp;#8221; Work for the cause, don&amp;#8217;t abandon it. Don&amp;#8217;t neglect it to play video games or watch TV or surf the internet. It isn&amp;#8217;t a hobby. It isn&amp;#8217;t part-time. It&amp;#8217;s full-time, all out, no holds-barred work for the cause of Allah.
If you consider the illustrious sahaba, radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhuma ajma&amp;#8217;een, they all gave their all for the cause. Their wealth, their health, their free time, even their very lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Things Are Worth Crying Over</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/few-things-are-worth-crying-over/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;Very few things in life are worth crying over.&amp;#8221; Ponder it. Very few things in life are worth throwing a fit over or complaining about. In Islamic work, especially, people attach importantance to things that aren&amp;#8217;t issues, tempers rise, fights break out, and brotherhood dies. And in the end, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) controls over all things.
So sit back, chill out, and let it run by you. No harm done, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>