<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paradise on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/paradise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paradise on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 03:27:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/paradise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Delight</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 03:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
What is the greatest gift you could ever receive? That you could ever want? That would bring you the greatest happiness and delight?&amp;#8230;..Think about it.
Got an idea? &amp;#8230;.good.
Most of us will be thinking of Jannah and all of its delights. But the most pleasurable thing in Jannah is not having spouses, or servants that will serve you, or drinking milk and honey. No rather, there is something MUCH GREATER for the Dwellers of Jannah that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala is keeping for them&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooba!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2008 01:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tooba/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah ta’ala says:
الَّذِينَ آمَنُوا وَعَمِلُوا الصَّالِحَاتِ طُوبَىٰ لَهُمْ وَحُسْنُ مَآبٍ  Those who have believed and done righteous deeds – ‘Tooba’ is theirs and a good return. (Suratur Ra’ad, ayah 29)
Allah ta’ala promises ‘Tooba’ to the believers in this ayah. We also know this word for the famous hadeeth of the strangers, the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam states: fa Tooba lil ghurabaa’, so Tooba to the strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raging and Roaring</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 23:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/raging-and-roaring/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says:إِذَا رَأَتْهُمْ مِنْ مَكَانٍ بَعِيدٍ سَمِعُوا لَهَا تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِير 
When it sees them from a far place, they will hear its raging and its roaring. Suratul Furqan, verse 12
What is the &amp;#8220;it&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;them&amp;#8221; in this verse referring too? When the hell fire sees the disbelievers. Hell fire will see them from a far place, and they will hear it تَغَيُّظًا وَزَفِيرًا , raging with fury and roaring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>