<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dua on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/dua/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dua on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/dua/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we focus on the sunnah of making ablution and coming out of the washroom. Here is the sunnah for this week:
After the fard salahs:
 After slautation, say Allahu Akbar in loud voice Say &amp;#8220;Astagfirullah&amp;#8221; thrice in low voice Recite &amp;#8220;Ayat Kursi&amp;#8221; Read the morning and evening supplications after farjar and asar prayers (Another Link) Recite other Adhkars and Supplications Pray the two rakahs of ishraq after the fajar prayer (The Messenger of Allah [SAWS] said, “Whoever prays the dawn prayer (fajr) in a group and then sits and does dhikr until the sun rises, then prays two rakas, shall have the like of the reward of a hajj and an umra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Wealth and Poverty</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 10:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is the 5th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
In our last post, we talked about how the human race does taghaa if they see themselves as self-sufficient. Living in western societies, we see this all around us&amp;#8211;people racing, fighting, stealing, overworking, to make a few more dollars so that they can &amp;#8220;make it.&amp;#8221; They buy lottery tickets so they can &amp;#8220;make it&amp;#8221; and be rich, rich rich!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Laziness and Incapability</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) used to make a du&amp;#8217;a:
 اللّهُمَّ إنِّي أعُوذُبِكَ مِن العَجزِ وَ الكَسلٍTransliteration: Allahumma inniy a&amp;#8217;oothubika min al-ajzi wal-kasli
Translation: O Allah, I seek refuge in you from incapability and laziness.  Why is this du&amp;#8217;a important? For two reasons:   Laziness is an attribute of munafiqeen. If this wasn&amp;#8217;t bad enough, being lazy leads to procrastination, which leads to its own set of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgiveness After Forgiveness After Forgiveness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 17:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/forgiveness-after-forgiveness-after-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s a beautiful du&amp;#8217;a that Allah mentions near the end of Surah Baqarah:
وَاعْفُ عَنَّا وَاغْفِرْ لَنَا وَارْحَمْنَا  Translation: So do &amp;#8216;affuw on us. And forgive us. And have mercy on us. [Surah Baqarah, verse 286]
Allah mentions three things, in order:
 &amp;#8216;Affuw &amp;#8216;annaa: Affuw linguistically means to erase something; to obliterate something; to completely destroy something and leave no traces of it whatsoever. This du&amp;#8217;a is saying: make affuw of our sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Du’a for Guidance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-concise-dua-for-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 21:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-concise-dua-for-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
One of the things I decided to blog about is my own personal du&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s not lifted straight from the pages of the Qur&amp;#8217;an or Sunnah, but it draws from them. My goal was to have a du&amp;#8217;a that:
 Is short, so I can recite it in sujood every rakah or every salah Is encompassing&amp;#8211;covers every aspect (in this case, of the akhirah) Is easy to remember, so I can remember it as needed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Greatest Delight</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 03:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-greatest-delight/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
What is the greatest gift you could ever receive? That you could ever want? That would bring you the greatest happiness and delight?&amp;#8230;..Think about it.
Got an idea? &amp;#8230;.good.
Most of us will be thinking of Jannah and all of its delights. But the most pleasurable thing in Jannah is not having spouses, or servants that will serve you, or drinking milk and honey. No rather, there is something MUCH GREATER for the Dwellers of Jannah that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala is keeping for them&amp;#8230;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comfortable?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/comfortable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 22:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/comfortable/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
‏حدثنا ‏ ‏سويد ‏ ‏أخبرنا ‏ ‏عبد الله ‏ ‏أخبرنا ‏ ‏أبو العلاء ‏ ‏عن ‏ ‏عطية ‏ ‏عن ‏ ‏أبي سعيد ‏ ‏قال ‏
‏قال رسول الله ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏كيف أنعم وصاحب القرن قد ‏ ‏التقم ‏ ‏القرن واستمع الإذن متى يؤمر بالنفخ فينفخ فكأن ذلك ثقل على ‏ ‏أصحاب النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏فقال لهم قولوا حسبنا الله ونعم الوكيل على الله توكلنا  The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said, &amp;#8220;How can I feel comfort while the angel responsible for The Trumpet has placed The Trumpet to his mouth and lowered his forehead, awaiting when he will be commanded (by Allah to blow in it)?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>