<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salaah on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/salaah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salaah on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/salaah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Do List After Ramadan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 20:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2015/to-do-list-after-ramadan/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Wikipedia
Ramadan ended. (May Allah accept all our prayer, fasting, du&amp;#8217;a, and good deeds during this blessed month &amp;#8212; ameen!) How should we, as Muslims, act now?
We graduated from the school of Ramadan; can life simply return to normal?
Our scholars mention a few points about this:
 Allah says, in surah Baqarah, that Ramadan was prescribed on us in the hope that we gain taqwa. Did we achieve that goal of the school of Ramadan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pray as if This is your Last Prayer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/pray-as-if-this-is-your-last-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2014/pray-as-if-this-is-your-last-prayer/</guid>
      <description>You often hear the khatheeb or imam, right before the salah starts, saying &amp;#8220;pray as if this is your last prayer.&amp;#8221; Sure, but what does it mean, and how do we do it?
As one of the righteous people of the past said:
 Pray as if Jannah is on your right side, Hellfire is on your left side, the siraat (bridge over Hellfire) is under you, the angel of death is behind you (waiting to take your soul any minute), your sins are above you (waiting to crush and destroy you), and this is the last deed, the one that decides if you go to Jannah or Jahannam forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Project Unveiled: Salah Support</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 16:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we&amp;#8217;ve been working in the background for a while to launch a new project. Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who helped out, may Allah keep giving you reward for it insha&amp;#8217;Allah long after your bones are dust&amp;#8211;allahumma ameen!
First, check yourself, and fill out the poll below:
[poll id=&amp;#8221;3&amp;#8243;]
If you haven&amp;#8217;t guessed, our new project is: Salah Support, a forum where you can find resources on salah&amp;#8211;everything from videos on how to pray, to ebooks on khushoo&amp;#8217;, to creative alarms for Qiaaym-ul-Layl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Shields of Protection From Supernatural Forces</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/3-shields-of-protection-from-supernatural-forces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/3-shields-of-protection-from-supernatural-forces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is post #22 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/forest-night-light.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;a blinding light emitting from a forest at night&#34; title=&#34;a blinding light emitting from a forest at night&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1233&#34; /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;imageCaption&#34;&gt;The protection of Allah is easily earned and very, very powerful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muslims love talking about Jinns and black magic. Yet, when it comes to inoculating themselves from supernatural forces, Muslims are often either ignorantly doing &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; of what they need to do, or proverbially standing on the interstate highway, woefully oblivious of thousands of cars speeding by at near-miss distances. And many of us, or people we know, personally &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet even the newest Muslim is often quickly equipped with powerful shields of protection against these forces. What are they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say: O You Kafiroon …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 20:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/say-o-you-kafiroon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This is post #20 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Surah Kafiroon, Allah says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;قُلْ يَا أَيُّهَا الْكَافِرُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَا أَعْبُدُ مَا تَعْبُدُونَ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنَا عَابِدٌ مَّا عَبَدتُّمْ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;وَلَا أَنتُمْ عَابِدُونَ مَا أَعْبُدُ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;لَكُمْ دِينُكُمْ وَلِيَ دِينِ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; Say, &amp;#8220;O disbelievers, I do not worship what you worship. Nor are you worshippers of what I worship. Nor will I be a worshipper of what you worship. Nor will you be worshippers of what I worship. For you is your religion, and for me is my religion.&amp;#8221; [Surah Kafiroon]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mushrikeen (polytheists) of Mecca tried many, many different techniques to get the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) to stop spreading Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this ayah was revealed, they decided to make a pact with him. They said, &amp;#8220;Look, how about this&amp;#8211;you worship our gods for one year, and we&amp;#8217;ll worship your God for one year.&amp;#8221; And to sweeten the deal: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ll go first.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they applied the Broken Record technique. Whenever the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) would try to speak to them about Islam, they would only repeat this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he, salallahu alayhi wa sallam, refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who are wondering why&amp;#8211;although it seems on the surface like a fair trade, it&amp;#8217;s not. Allah &lt;strong&gt;does not forgive shirk&lt;/strong&gt;, worshipping other than him; not even a single sujood, or a single du&amp;#8217;a, none of it is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So clearly, this is not a contract the Messenger of Allah could engage with. So he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he &lt;em&gt;refused&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the Mushrikeen said, &amp;#8220;ok, how about this&amp;#8211;just &lt;em&gt;speak highly&lt;/em&gt; of our gods, and we&amp;#8217;ll do the same for you.&amp;#8221; A smaller compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whenever people approached them, they would say, &amp;#8220;Well, we&amp;#8217;re trying to compromise (like &lt;em&gt;we&amp;#8217;re&lt;/em&gt; the good ones in this deal&amp;#8211;even though we kill our daughters and murder on whims and &amp;#8230;), but he&amp;#8217;s not agreeing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) went to the ka&amp;#8217;bah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/kabah-full.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; title=&#34;The Ka&amp;#039;bah, the House of Allah&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1206&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mushrikeen were there. And in front of &lt;strong&gt;everybody&lt;/strong&gt; he said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Who Show Off in Their Salah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/those-who-show-off-in-their-salah/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is post #19 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).
In Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, Allah says:
 فَوَيْلٌ لِّلْمُصَلِّينَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ عَن صَلَاتِهِمْ سَاهُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ يُرَاءُونَ
وَيَمْنَعُونَ الْمَاعُونَ
 Translation: So woe to those who pray; those who are heedless of their prayer, those who make show [of their deeds]; And withhold [simple] assistance (al-ma&amp;#8217;oon). [Surah Ma&amp;#8217;oon, verses 4-7]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask the Readers: Questions about Salah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ask-the-readers-questions-about-salah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 15:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ask-the-readers-questions-about-salah/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who provided feedback. It seems like there&amp;#8217;s a lot of demand for this kind of thing. Insha&amp;#8217;Allah we&amp;#8217;ll see more posts like this in the future.
Bismillah.
Salah. We cannot emphasize the importance of salah&amp;#8211;the dividing line of Islam and Kufr. The first thing asked about on the Day of Judgment. The last thing the Messenger of Allah mentioned before he passed away.
Maybe you&amp;#8217;ve been Muslim a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Mursal Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 18:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</guid>
      <description>In the sciences of hadith, there&amp;#8217;s something called a &amp;#8220;mursal&amp;#8221; hadith. What exactly is a mursal hadith? What is it&amp;#8217;s status? What are the fiqh rulings on mursal ahadith? And why does it matter?
(Ok, for the answer to the last question, read and learn about the science of hadith. In a sentence: Scholars have devised an extremely rigorous process to determine which hadith are authentic, and which are not. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to spend your whole life following a &amp;#8220;hadith,&amp;#8221; only to find out it really wasn&amp;#8217;t legit, do you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Qiyaam-ul-Layl Alarms</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 16:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/creative-qiyaam-ul-layl-alarms/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We all know that we should pray tahajjud, aka qiyaam-ul-layl. It&amp;#8217;s well established in the deen that this is a very, very rewarding thing to do (but it&amp;#8217;s not fard, so don&amp;#8217;t sweat it if you&amp;#8217;re not doing it). Some motivational factors for this include:
 The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) used to pray Qiyaam-ul-Layl until his legs swelled. When asked why&amp;#8211;since Allah has forgiven all his past and future sins, he said: Should I not be a grateful slave?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reasons Behind Seasons</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-reasons-behind-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Why did Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) create seasons? All of this&amp;#8211;snow, leaves changing, hot summer days and freezing winter nights. In some countries&amp;#8211;like Canada, and the US&amp;#8211;you have places where Isha time starts around 11pm, or 12am (midnight), and Fajr starts arond 2-3am! You also have days where Isha starts at 6pm, and Fajr starts around 7am.
What can we learn from this?
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) gives this away when he narrates: &amp;#8220;Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) made the night short so you can pray, and the day short so you can fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praying Isha While The Imam Prays Taraweeh</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2008 17:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praying-isha-while-the-imam-prays-taraweeh/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s well-known in our communities, alhamdulillah, that you can pray &amp;#8216;Isha behind an imam praying Taraweeh. (Which happens if you run late, very late, indeed!) But we&amp;#8217;re just going to dive a bit into the details of how and why this is.
Note: We do not issue fatwa! For that, please consult Islam Question and Answer!
First of all, there is a difference of opinion among the scholars about whether this is permissible or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Due Reward: Surah Ikhlas – Pt.5 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-due-reward-surah-ikhlas-pt5-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 15:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-due-reward-surah-ikhlas-pt5-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
SubhanAllah! How fast Ramadan came and how fast it went. It truly saddens my heart to see this blessed month go away, to see it slipping away, to have to say good-bye. In a few days, the shayateen will be let loose and the difficulties will emerge. Ya Rabbi! Give this ummah the strength to fight the shayateen and keep us steadfast in the deen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unborn: Surah Ikhlas – Pt. 3 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 15:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-unborn-surah-ikhlas-pt-3-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
First and foremost, Ramadan Kareem! May Allah azza wa jal give us all the opportunity to take advantage of this blessed month and to make it a means of us attaining His Paradise. Ameen.
Due to Ramadan, I&amp;#8217;ve found myself to be quite busy. Nonetheless, I do apologize for not having written anything for the past few makes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones in Need: Surah Ikhlas – Pt. 2 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-ones-in-need-surah-ikhlas-pt-2-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-ones-in-need-surah-ikhlas-pt-2-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum!
Continuing in our journey of understanding the 112th chapter of the Qur&amp;#8217;an, Allah says: اللَّهُ الصَّمَدُ Allah, the Self-Sufficient [Surah Ikhlas V.2]
 Recall, the greatest name of the Lord of the heavens and the earth is Allah. This is the name that He has chosen to name Himself with, and it is the grand name to which all His other Names and Attributes are attributed to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Command Like No Other: Surah Ikhlas – Pt.1 (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-command-like-no-other-surah-ikhlas-pt1-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2008 15:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-command-like-no-other-surah-ikhlas-pt1-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Alhamdolilah. We started this initiative to bring people closer to their salat and by the grace of Allah azza wa jal the numbers are increasing and so are the results. May Allah continue to shower His Mercy into this project and make our hearts humble towards Him.
This week and inshallah for the coming weeks we will concentrate our efforts in attempting to understand the surahs we often recite in the salat (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praise of Beauty (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praise-of-beauty-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 15:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/praise-of-beauty-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum, Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah.
Rifa&amp;#8217;ah ibn Rafi&amp;#8217; said: We were praying behind the Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam and when he raised his head at the end of the rak&amp;#8217;ah he said:
 &amp;#8220;Allah listens to him who praises Him&amp;#8221;

A man behind him said:  &amp;#8220;O our Lord! To You belongs all praise, abundant good praise, inherently blessed&amp;#8221;   
When he finished he asked, &amp;#8220;Who was the speaker just now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varying the Supplications (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/varying-the-supplications-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 15:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/varying-the-supplications-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah wa&amp;#8217;lhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
For the most part, or at least from my personal experience, from childhood salat was always made to seem very rigid; one way of doing it, no variation, very systematic. And since we were never taught these variations, salat just ended up becoming a thoughtless set of actions, repeating the same things over and over again. However, as I grew older I realized that there is a lot of variation in salat, a lot that we can do to really build that relationship Allah throughout our salat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubhanAllah: A Pure Negation (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 15:50:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/subhanallah-a-pure-negation/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah was-salatu was-salam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam
Continuing in our discussion of the oft-repeated words and phrases in our salat, this week inshallah we will focus on looking at: SubhanAllah
This is another word that is very common in the Muslim&amp;#8217;s vocabulary. We all have heard the word, we all say it in our prayers daily (inshallah), yet how many of us truly understand its meaning?
Commonly this word is translated as, &amp;#8220;Glory be to Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;All Glory is to Allah&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Praise of Perfection (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 15:47:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-praise-of-perfection-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum,
There are certain words and phrases which we pronounce in our salat repeatedly, yet more than likely we do not know what they mean. This is the state of our salat these days&amp;#8230;nothing more than actions of the limbs. O Muslims! Remember faith (eman) is belief in the heart, statements upon the tongue, and actions of the limbs. All three are required for a completeness of faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Home away from Home (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-home-away-from-home-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2008 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-home-away-from-home-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>By dear brother and sisters in Islam, Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullah
In this blessed month of Ramadan, it is only beneficial to us to increase our worship of Allah azza wa jal. Surely, this month is full of blessings like no other. O Muslims! Take advantage of this month, because the reality is we don&amp;#8217;t know if we will see another one.
Our beloved Prophet sallalahu alayhi wasalam has said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Forgiveness (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/pure-forgiveness-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2008 15:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/pure-forgiveness-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>My dear brothers and sisters in Islam our beloved Prophet alayhi salatu wasalam has told us:
  &amp;#8220;The angels keep on asking Allah&amp;#8217;s forgiveness for anyone of you, as long as he is at his mu&amp;#8217;sallah (praying place) and does he does not pass wind. They say, &amp;#8216;O Allah! Forgive him, O Allah! be Merciful to him.&amp;#8221; [Bukhari]   Gems
   Angels are a great sign of Mercy from Allah and how beautiful it is that Allah has given every single Muslim the ability to feel the mercy just by staying in his place of prayer   How great is it that the angels ask Allah for forgiveness for you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A River of Purity (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-river-of-purity-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 15:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-river-of-purity-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet of Allah sallalahu alayhi wasalam has coined an amazing analogy in regards to salat. The analogy is depicted in a conversation between the Prophet and the Companions radhiAllah anhum, in which the Prophet alayhi salatu wasalam said:
 &amp;#8220;Do you think that if there was a river by the door of one of you and he bathed in it five times a day that there would remain any dirt on him?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tajweed: Different Stops</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tajweed-different-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 14:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/tajweed-different-stops/</guid>
      <description>In this great month of Ramadan, people will be reciting the Qur&amp;#8217;an more, insha&amp;#8217;Allah. While we recommend everybody to get a colour-coded Arabic-text mushaaf&amp;#8211;because it makes it easy to recite with 100% perfect tajweed once you learn the rules&amp;#8211;sometimes, deciphering some of the symbols can be a bit tricky.
In this first post, we&amp;#8217;re going to insha&amp;#8217;Allah discuss different stops in the mushaf. You may have seen these stop symbols: tiny little letters (meem, qaaf+lam, jeem, saad+lam, lam+alif) written above the text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek out the Benefit (Salat 101)</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/seek-out-the-benefit-salat-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/seek-out-the-benefit-salat-101/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum!
What a beautiful month in which we can come together and build our salat. Ramadan Mubarak! We ask Allah to accept all our deeds from this blessed month and to give us the tawfeeq to push ourselves in pleasing Him, Subhana. To begin our journey, we remind ourselves of the saying our our beloved Prophet alayhi salatu wa salam; may not be directly related to prayers, nonetheless it is important:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salat101 now on Ilmfruits!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/salat101-now-on-ilmfruits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 15:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/salat101-now-on-ilmfruits/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wasalatu wasalam &amp;#8216;ala Rasool Allah
Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatahu,
In efforts to bring people closer to their salat a service was created entitled, &amp;#8220;Salat101&amp;#8243;. Alhamdolilah, by the grace of Allah azza wa jal this has been a great success and inshallah it will be now available on Ilmfruits!
Periodically, we will send out tips and tricks which inshallah ta&amp;#8217;ala will aid us all in attaining ihsan in our salat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Two More?!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/just-two-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 16:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/just-two-more/</guid>
      <description>In Suratul-Furqaan (Surah 25), ayah 63, Allah begins a description of what is translated as &amp;#8220;the slaves of Ar-Rahmaan (Allah)&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8230;عِبَادُ الرَّحْمَنِ  In ayah 64, He describes these &amp;#8220;slaves&amp;#8221; by saying:
َالَّذِينَ يَبِيتُونَ لِرَبِّهِمْ سُجَّداً وَقِيَاماً …  This is translated as: those who spend the night before their Lord, prostrating (in sujood) and standing.
Tafsir ibn Kathir explains this ayah, and compares it to ayahs 17-18 from Suratuth-Thaariyaat (Surah 51):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Success is For the Believers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 18:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/success-is-for-the-believers/</guid>
      <description>Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the first few verses of Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon:
قَدْ أَفْلَحَ الْمُؤْمِنُونَ
الَّذِينَ هُمْ فِي صَلَاتِهِمْ خَاشِعُونَ  Translation: Successful are the Believers! Those who establish their salaah with khushoo. [Surah Mu&amp;#8217;minoon, verses 1-2]
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) carries on to mention many other characteristics of the believer in this surah&amp;#8211;however, the thing to focus on, the thing to ponder about, is that the FIRST characteristic that Allah chooses to describe a believer by&amp;#8211;a person who establishes the salaah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worship</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/worship/</guid>
      <description>We go through life praying, giving to the poor, fasting, and other forms of worship which are prescribed by Allah. However, when was the last time we sat back and really tried to understand what it means to worship Allah? Why do we worship Him? Listen to the podcast for more details on this crucial aspect of Islam&amp;#8211;worship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500 Years of Worship</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/500-years-of-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 18:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/500-years-of-worship/</guid>
      <description>500 Years of Worship  By Shaikh Abul Laith Samarkandi
Angel Jibreel (عليه السلام) told Rasulullah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) the following incident:
 A man in the past worshipped Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) continuously for 500 years. He was granted a shelter on top of a mountain that was surrounded by salty water. However, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) caused a stream of sweet water to flow through the mountain for that individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abu Bakr and His Request</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2007 08:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/abu-bakr-and-his-request/</guid>
      <description>What do you make of the amazing incident when the best of the sahaba (رضالله عنه) came to the best of the Prophets (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to ask for a du&amp;#8217;a to make in his prayers?
 Narrated Abu Bakr As-Siddiq (رضالله عنه) I asked Allah&amp;#8217;s Apostle (صلي الله عليه وسلم) to teach me an invocation so that I may invoke Allah with it in my prayer. He told me to say, [Sahih Bukhari]  (Hover your mouse over each line to see the translation)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“As-Salaah! As-Salaah!”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/as-salaah-as-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2007 08:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/as-salaah-as-salaah/</guid>
      <description>The importance of salaah can be seen in the seerah of our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم). Allah raised our beloved Prophet to His heights to give him the command of salaah directly, rather than sending it through Angel Jibreel. Also, the importance of salaah is seen in the seerah, when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) was on his death bed, when he had the chance to give one last message that he could give his ummah until the Day of Judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you Established the Salaah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-established-the-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 06:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/have-you-established-the-salaah/</guid>
      <description>The greatest command after that of tawheed is of salaah. Allah lays out a list for whom this Qur&amp;#8217;an is a guidance, and amongst the first things He says are about those who establish the salaah; those who guard them strictly and stand in front of Allah with obedience. The example of Prophet Ibrahim (عليه السلام) is amongst the best, and as he builds the ka&amp;#8217;ba, he makes du&amp;#8217;a to Allah to make him amongst those who establish salaah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relax! Who are you Racing?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/relax-who-are-you-racing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 06:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/relax-who-are-you-racing/</guid>
      <description>We at times find ourself in a race with salaah. One of the primary ways to gain khushoo in our salaah is to take our time in it, so much so that our Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) told us to be slow and articulate with each movement&amp;#8211;we should let all our bones rest and then continue on, not before that. No need to race, because this will come back on the Day of Judgment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“If it is sound then the rest of his deeds will be sound…”</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/if-it-is-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 07:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/if-it-is-sound/</guid>
      <description>Going on about the importance of salaah, salaah is the first matter that a slave/abd/person will be brought account for on the Day of Judgment. So important is salaah, that Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said that if this one matter is good then everything else will also be good.
Listen to the podcast to gain more understanding on how to make your salaah sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitless: Ramadan Planning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/limitless-ramadan-planning/</guid>
      <description>My brothers and sisters a blessed month is fast approaching us, a month in which the opportunities are limitless and the reward is ready for taking in abundance. This blessed month, known as Ramadan is approaching us and we will soon say good-bye to it as well.
Inshallah, join me on this journey as we go through some self-planning for this blessed month, and inshallah learn about the one action which is most noble in the sight of Allah&amp;#8230;that action being du&amp;#8217;a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You a Believer?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/are-you-a-believer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 08:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/are-you-a-believer/</guid>
      <description>We sometimes forget the vast importance of salaah in our lives. Successful are the believers. Who are these believers? They are those who offer their salaah with full khushoo, with full submissiveness to Allah, those who establish the salaah.
Listen to the podcast for more details on how you can be among the believers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pinnacle of Salaah: Khusoo’</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pinnacle-of-salaah-khusoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2007 20:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-pinnacle-of-salaah-khusoo/</guid>
      <description>Khushoo is to be conscious of God, to have taqwa, to have fear of Allah. And so khushoo is something that comes from the heart, and if the heart is clean, then the salaah&amp;#8211;and everything else&amp;#8211;will be clean. There are many ways that one can go about gaining khusoo; a few of them a few are:
 prepare ahead of time by performing wudoo properly use miswak repeat the words of the adhaan make du&amp;#8217;a between the adhaan and the iqaamah  For more information, listen to the podcast below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Womanly Awrah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/womanly-awrah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2007 17:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/womanly-awrah/</guid>
      <description>Womanly &amp;#8216;Awrah  The topic of the &amp;#8216;awrah of a woman is one of great discussion, both amongst the scholars and the laymen. In sha Allah, here is an attempt to specify what exactly is the &amp;#8216;awrah of a woman in light of the evidences from the Quran and sunnah, as explained by the scholars.
A few definitions:
&amp;#8216;Awrah &amp;#8211; the parts of the body that are not supposed to be exposed to anyone, except your spouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prayer, The Prayer …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prayer-the-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 07:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-prayer-the-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Some points to ponder about Salah, Namaz, Prayer&amp;#8230;
Our purpose in life is to worship Allah. Prayer (Salah) is the manifestation of that. Without it, we have nothing.
Prayer:
 Is the only commandment in Islam that came from Allah (سبحانه وتعال) to Muhammad (صلي الله عليه وسلم) directly, without any angel in-between, in the journey of Isra Wal Miraj[1] Was originally legislated at 50 times per day (That just shows how important it is)[1] One of the last concerns of the dying Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم)[2] Time after time, mentioned in the Quran as the first requirement right after Faith in Allah (سبحانه وتعال) [3] Quran described as guidance for the ones who pray (right at the beginning of the book in Surah Baqarah) [4] Agreement between us and the Prophet, without prayer, is kufr[5] A person&amp;#8217;s feet will not move on the Day of Judgement until he is questioned about the prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Purification Act</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2007 10:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/purification-act/</guid>
      <description>The Purification Act  The Purification Act is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Abdul-Bary Yahya. If you think you know wudoo, think again! This course teaches you the ins and outs of tahara (purity and purification) and salaah (prayer)&amp;#8211;everything from whether one adhaan or two is more correct, to the proper way to purify dog-slobber from your best china, to whether a pigskin football (or for that matter, a leather jacket) is najas or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manly Awrah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/manly-awrah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2007 15:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/manly-awrah/</guid>
      <description>Awrah: islamically, this refers to the area of a human being that is considered private, and, for lack of a better description, &amp;#8220;not for public consumption.&amp;#8221;
We know of many reports that the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said, &amp;#8220;once a woman achieves puberty, it is not befitting that she show anything except this (indicating his face) and this (indicating his hands up to the wrists).&amp;#8221; So we know about a woman&amp;#8217;s awrah &amp;#8230; but how about a man&amp;#8217;s awrah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eh! You Wanna Enter Jannah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eh-you-wanna-enter-jannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 04:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eh-you-wanna-enter-jannah/</guid>
      <description>Attaining Jannah can be easy if we want it to be. The choice is ours to make. Just take a step towards Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) and watch!
To make things easy, it is reported that Abu Umamah said: The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: “Whoever recites Ayatul-Kursi immediately after each prescribed prayer, there will be nothing standing between him and his entering Paradise except death.” (Reported by An-Nasa’i and Ibn Hibban)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2006 17:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/think/</guid>
      <description>To continue our series of ways to purify our salaah, a very important aspect is to take some time and to actually reflect and think about the ayaat being recited.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an:
(This is) a Book (the Qur&amp;#8217;an) which We have sent down to you, full of blessings that they may ponder over its Verses, and that men of understanding may remember.”
&amp;#8211; Surah Saad 38:29 Now the word ponder has strong implications in this translation of the verse quoted above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tahajjud Made Easy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tahajjud-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 15:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/tahajjud-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>Many of us desire to be among those who pray Qiyam al-Layl (or Tahajjud), but find it difficult to wake up in the middle of the night for it. What can we do to make this easier?
Option 1: Late Sleepers. If you happen to be one of those late-night people&amp;#8211;whether you&amp;#8217;re up late studying for exams, chilling, or working on a project&amp;#8211;why not make wudoo and pray two rakahs before you sleep?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice and Slow</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/nice-and-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2006 14:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/nice-and-slow/</guid>
      <description>Continuing in our series of ways to attain purification in salaah: Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur’an:
وَرَتِّلِ الْقُرْآنَ تَرْتِيلاً  “&amp;#8230; and recite the Qur’an in slow, measured rhythmic tones” (Surah al-Muzammil 73:4)
From this alone, we see the importance of reciting the Qur’an in a proper manner–slowly and with a rythmic tone–and not just whizzing through it as if we were reading a magazine of some sort. Also, our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) had a recitation which was clear, with each letter proncounced distinctly (Ahmad, 6&amp;frasl;294, saheeh).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: A Conversation with Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-conversation-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2006 10:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-a-conversation-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth part of our discussion on ways to achieving purification of our salaah.
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: “Allah, the Blessed and Exalted, has said: ‘I have divided the prayer between Myself and My slave, into two halves, and My slave shall have what he has asked for.&amp;#8217;
&amp;#8220;When the slave says &amp;#8220;Ar-Rehman-nir-Raheem&amp;#8220;, Allaah (سبحانه وتعالى) says, &amp;#8220;My slave has extolled me.&amp;#8221;
&amp;#8220;When the slave says, &amp;#8220;Malikee Yawma Ddin&amp;#8220;, Allaah (سبحانه وتعالى) says, &amp;#8220;My slave has glorified me&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;My servant has related all matters to Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Levels of Prayer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-levels-of-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2006 12:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/five-levels-of-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Ibn al-Qayyim (رحمالله) said:
And mankind, with regard to their performance of prayer are in five levels:
The First: The level of the one who is negligent and wrongs his soul: He is the one who falls short in performing wudoo properly, performing the prayer upon its time and within its specified limits, and in fulfilling its essential pillars.
The Second: The one who guards his prayers upon their proper times and within their specified limits, fulfills their essential pillars and performs his wudoo with care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: Relax!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-relax/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2006 12:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-relax/</guid>
      <description>Continuing in our series of purification of salaah, we all need to realize that it&amp;#8217;s not a race to see who can finish first! Inshallah ta&amp;#8217;alla take your time, relax, and comfort your soul with the tranquility of being in communication with Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), your Lord and Creator!
Our beloved Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) used to move at a measured pace throughout his salaah; so much so that he would allow every bone to return to its place after each movement (classified saheeh by Ibn Kuzaymah and al-Hafiz).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Last Prayer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-last-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 23:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/your-last-prayer/</guid>
      <description>Getting further in our discussion on the means to attain the utmost purification in our salaah; one of the best ways is to realize that it may be our last salaah we offer to Allah (سبحانه وتعالى). So the question is, how do you wanna go out?
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Remember death in your prayer, for the man who remembers death during his prayer is bound to pray properly, and pray the prayer of a man who does not think that he will pray any other prayer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salaah: Preperation is KEY!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-preperation-is-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2006 12:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/salaah-preperation-is-key/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our discussion of the purification of salaah, one of the primary ways to gain khushoo’ is to prepare ahead of time! Try these authentic actions from the sunnah:
 Perform wudoo properly; start with bismillah and end with ash-hadu an laa ilaaha illallah wahdahu laa sharee ka lahu wa ash-hadu anna Muhammadan abdahu wa rasoolahu.
Umar bin Al-Khattab (رضي الله عنه) narrated that the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever of you performs wudoo thoroughly then says: &amp;#8216;I testify that there is no god but Allah, with Whom there is no associate, and that Muhammad is His servant and Messenger,&amp;#8217; the eight gates of Paradise will be opened to him to enter from whichever he wants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purification of Salaah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/purification-of-salaah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 04:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/purification-of-salaah/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all been there…You’re just chillin’, chatting on MSN with your buddies, and then you take a look at the time. Its 12:13am and you still haven’t prayed Isha. O mannn! You get off MSN, go make wudoo, and then perform your prayer. However, as we all know, our laziness and tired state takes over us, and this reflects in our prayer.
You finish praying at 12:17am and you find yourself in the same position you were no more than five mins ago, on MSN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>