<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surah Aadiyaat on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-aadiyaat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surah Aadiyaat on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 16:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-aadiyaat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When the War-Horses Pant …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/when-the-war-horses-pant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 16:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/when-the-war-horses-pant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is post #15 in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ilmfruits.com/wp-content/uploads/horse-saddle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-1159&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allah begins Surah Aadiyaat by saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;وَالْعَادِيَاتِ ضَبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُورِيَاتِ قَدْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَالْمُغِيرَاتِ صُبْحًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَأَثَرْنَ بِهِ نَقْعًا&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;فَوَسَطْنَ بِهِ جَمْعًا&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translation:&lt;/strong&gt; By the &amp;#8216;aadiyaat, when they pant, and the muwriyraat striking (when their hoves strike the ground and make sparks), and the mughiyraat, at dawn (when they raid), stirring up thereby [clouds of] dust, arriving thereby in the center collectively, &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a qasam (oath), a big oath that spans five ayaat. I&amp;#8217;m going to dive into word-for-word translation, because no translation can do justice (without paragraphs of brackets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;Aadiyaat (عَادِيَات) are horses (plural: sound feminine plural, in fact). Not those horses you see Canadian Mounties riding; but real, true, WAR horses. If you&amp;#8217;ve ever seen war-horses (send us a picture!), they have a special, particular intensity to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dabhaa (ضَبْحًا) means to pant. Pant meaning, if you&amp;#8217;ve ever run in a 100-meter race, or tried to run until you&amp;#8217;re tired, and you start breathing heavily through your mouth&amp;#8211;that&amp;#8217;s panting. Why are the &amp;#8216;aadiyaat panting? Because they are &lt;em&gt;charging&lt;/em&gt; into battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll see lots of war concepts here. The Arabs at the time of the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) knew these things very, very well; and when Allah testifies, these things he testifies by&amp;#8211;nobody would deny them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muwriyaat (مُورِيَات) are also war-horses&amp;#8211;the ones that strike. Strike meaning, when they run, their hooves strike up sparks on the ground. I definitely don&amp;#8217;t encourage watching movies, so if you&amp;#8217;ve ever read seerah stories, or perhaps Lord of the Rings, or similar books, you might find these kinds of concepts in their battles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mughiyraat (مُغِيرَات) are the raiding horses. In the time of the Prophet, they would have raids; you would see a whole army of horses and riders sweeping into a city, and they&amp;#8217;d kill everybody and destroy it. Mughiyraat are those raiding horses that they rode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>