<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sunnahs on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/sunnahs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sunnahs on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 22:19:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/sunnahs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>And of His signs is your sleep by night….</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/and-of-his-signs-is-your-sleep-by-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 22:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/and-of-his-signs-is-your-sleep-by-night/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. In the last post, we talked about the etiquette of eating. In this post, we will look at the Sunnahs of going to sleep
Click here to show evidences/reference links

What to recite before going to sleep:
 Recite Surah Al-Ikhlas, Surah Al-Falaq and Surah An-Nas and wipe the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we focus on the sunnah of making ablution and coming out of the washroom. Here is the sunnah for this week:
After the fard salahs:
 After slautation, say Allahu Akbar in loud voice Say &amp;#8220;Astagfirullah&amp;#8221; thrice in low voice Recite &amp;#8220;Ayat Kursi&amp;#8221; Read the morning and evening supplications after farjar and asar prayers (Another Link) Recite other Adhkars and Supplications Pray the two rakahs of ishraq after the fajar prayer (The Messenger of Allah [SAWS] said, “Whoever prays the dawn prayer (fajr) in a group and then sits and does dhikr until the sun rises, then prays two rakas, shall have the like of the reward of a hajj and an umra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid 101</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 01:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/eid-101/</guid>
      <description>Below is a fantastic presentation on Eid, based on the sunnah. It outlines the dos and don&amp;#8217;ts of Eid. Learn it, share it, and enjoy!
Eid mubarak to you and your families, on behalf of Ilm Fruits!
SWF from: http://www.outstandingmuslim.com/Eid101/engage.html </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>