<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 14:41:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Children, Our Test – Advice to Parents</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2017/advice-to-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 14:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2017/advice-to-parents/</guid>
      <description>There he stood. A grown man, towering to the sky. Broad shoulders, and so much pain in his eyes. I know it&amp;#8217;s impossible, yet I could hear his heart sobbing. In reality though it was just the sound of my own pumping away. I stopped, asked, and what I was about to hear would break my heart in pieces. It&amp;#8217;s a painful encounter I&amp;#8217;ve heard over and over again of parents who&amp;#8217;ve &amp;#8216;lost&amp;#8217; their children for one reason or another to drugs, alcohol, fame, money, friends, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Children, Our Test – Naseeha to Parents</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/our-children-our-test-naseeha-to-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 19:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/our-children-our-test-naseeha-to-parents/</guid>
      <description>There he stood. A grown man, towering to the sky. Broad shoulders, and so much pain in his eyes. I know it&amp;#8217;s impossible, yet I could hear his heart sobbing. In reality though it was just the sound of my own pumping away. I stopped, asked, and what I was about to hear would break my heart in pieces. It&amp;#8217;s a painful encounter I&amp;#8217;ve heard over and over again of parents who&amp;#8217;ve &amp;#8216;lost&amp;#8217; their children for one reason or another to drugs, alcohol, fame, money, friends, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we focus on the sunnah of making ablution and coming out of the washroom. Here is the sunnah for this week:
After the fard salahs:
 After slautation, say Allahu Akbar in loud voice Say &amp;#8220;Astagfirullah&amp;#8221; thrice in low voice Recite &amp;#8220;Ayat Kursi&amp;#8221; Read the morning and evening supplications after farjar and asar prayers (Another Link) Recite other Adhkars and Supplications Pray the two rakahs of ishraq after the fajar prayer (The Messenger of Allah [SAWS] said, “Whoever prays the dawn prayer (fajr) in a group and then sits and does dhikr until the sun rises, then prays two rakas, shall have the like of the reward of a hajj and an umra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Seeking His Love 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 15:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-seeking-his-love-2/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah walhamdolilah wassalatu wassalam &amp;#8216;ala rasool Allah
Here are ten ways to attain the love of Allah subhanahu wa ta&amp;#8217;ala, as per Ibn al-Qayyim rahimuhallah:
 First, reciting the Qur’an while pondering over its meanings and what is meant by it.
 Allah says, the meaning of which is: &amp;#8220;Then do they not reflect upon the Qur&amp;#8217;an? If it had been from [any] other than Allah , they would have found within it much contradiction&amp;#8221; [4:82]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Four Priorities of the Muslim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</guid>
      <description>Abu Barzah al-Aslami radi Allahu anhu reported that Allah’s Messenger sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, “The two feet of the servant will not cease (from standing before Allah) on the Day of Judgment until he is asked about four things: on his life and how he spent it; on his knowledge and what he did with it; on his wealth and where he earned it and how he spent it; and on his body and in what way he utilized it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Not Despair? Reflections on Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/why-not-despair-reflections-on-patience/</guid>
      <description>Why not despair? The Islamic meaning of sabr is to stop ourselves from despairing and panicking, to stop our tongues from complaining, and to stop our hands from striking our faces and tearing our clothes at times of grief and stress.
To have _sabr_ is to first realize within your own heart that a) there is a god that exists b) that this god is worthy of all my worship c) that this god is indeed characterized by attributes of perfectness and majesty, which can only be ascribed to god and no other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Matter What…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 15:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/no-matter-what/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum, Time comes and goes; some people grow, some people remain exactly same throughout time.
وَالْعَصْرِ
By the Time!
إِنَّ الْإِنسَانَ لَفِي خُسْرٍ**_
_** Indeed! Mankind is in loss__
Thus, Allah makes clear that by the passing time man is in complete loss. Why? Because they don&amp;#8217;t take heed, they don&amp;#8217;t learn, they don&amp;#8217;t listen, they go on doing what their hearts desire without thinking twice. They (in general) don&amp;#8217;t ponder about the real purpose of their life; they (in general) cover reality with their false notions and desires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Patience</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/on-patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/on-patience/</guid>
      <description>Patience is active, not passive. What does this mean? It mains patience doesn&amp;#8217;t just &amp;#8220;happen&amp;#8221;. You must strive for it. You have to actively remind yourself and make yourself patient.
Also, remember that Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) tests you with what you are not patient with. If He (سبحانه وتعالى) tested you with things you already succeed at, how could you ever learn and grow?
For a classic example of patience, consult Surah Yusuf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fight For Sincere Intentions</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fight-for-sincere-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 23:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fight-for-sincere-intentions/</guid>
      <description>In the first hadith in Sahih Bukhari, the messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;The reward of deeds depends upon the intentions and every person will get the reward according to what he intended. So whoever emigrated for worldly benefits or for a woman to marry, his emigration was for what he emigrated for.&amp;#8221;1 The majority scholarly opinion is that this hadith applies to all actions, natural or religious (read more about the distinction here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water, Soil, Plants, Fruit, Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 05:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/water-soil-plants-fruit-life-management/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that your time is water. Every day, you get 24 liters to use as you wish. You keep it in one giant metal bucket and carry it around with you. The bucket leaks&amp;#8211;if you don&amp;#8217;t pour your time into buckets and use it effectively, most of it will end up spilled on the ground, lost.
Each day, you pass by some plants, and you have to stop and water them, or they die&amp;#8211;the big, thick bush of family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Stages of Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-stages-of-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 19:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/six-stages-of-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>There are six stages of knowledge.
 Knowledge of Facts: know the information (eg. what year did &amp;#8216;Umar (radiallahu &amp;#8216;an) become the Khalifa?) Comprehension: think about the information and understand it (eg. the khalifa is in charge of the entire Muslim ummah) Application: learn and apply the knowledge&amp;#8211;it helps you remember. Apply it to your context. What does it mean for you and me, here, today? Analysis: Analyze the information critically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with Ihsaan</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/work-with-ihsaan/</guid>
      <description>As Islamic workers, we never lower our standers. Not as volunteers, not as professionals, and not as Muslims. Always strive to the best of your abilities. And inshaAllah this way, your skills and talent grow faster than if you barely use them.
Never fall into the trap of so many people who produce second-rate material &amp;#8220;just because&amp;#8221; it&amp;#8217;s for Islamic work, and not for their own (percieved/worldly) benefit.
And remember: ihsaan means excellence, not perfection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Saudi Guy Walks Into a Bar …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-saudi-guy-walks-into-a-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 01:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/a-saudi-guy-walks-into-a-bar/</guid>
      <description>A Saudi guy walks into a bar, decked out in his thobe and kufi. (He doesn&amp;#8217;t believe in the meat of the People of the Book arguement.) He walks up to the bar and says &amp;#8220;Bartender, I want a chicken sandwich.&amp;#8221;
The bartender looks at him, nods, and turns to fill the order.
A desi guy who sits nearby stares. The Saudi guy turns to the desi guy. Black spiked hair, leather jacket, one hand clamps around the handle of a half-filled mug of beer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiTimer: Multiple Labeled Item Timers</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2006 16:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/multitimer-multiple-labeled-item-timers/</guid>
      <description>MultiTimer, a lightweight application, allows you to track your time commitments to multiple items simultaneously. You type in the timer label, set the inital time and count method (countup or countdown), and the application handles the rest.
In particular, if you need to track (and, optionally, aggregate) time usage for multiple projects, you can assign one timer per project and track your time use per day. Or per week. Or per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCD Life Management</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/abcd-life-management/</guid>
      <description>This article by Steve Pavlina explains how to effectively manage your life by focusing on tasks based on their long-term effects.
The article defines three categories of tasks, and allocates your daily time to each of them proportionally based on their expected benefit.
 &amp;#8220;A&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in five or more years, such as learning a new language. &amp;#8220;B&amp;#8221; tasks yield benefit in two or more years, such as training for a marathon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>