<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difference of Opinion on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/difference-of-opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difference of Opinion on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 14:21:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/difference-of-opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikhtilaf – I</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/ikhtilaf-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 14:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/ikhtilaf-i/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we introduced the topic of Differences of Opinions. We listed the four ways of categorizing these differences. In this post, we will look at the first category: Differences due to interpretation of word meanings and grammatical constructions.
Within this category, we have several sub categories:
Shared literal meanings/Equivocality/Homonym (Ishtirak):
An example of this would be the word &amp;#8220;qur&amp;#8221; which means menses as well as the time of purity between menses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcdonald, KFC, Moon Sighting…</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 23:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/mcdonald-kfc-moon-sighting/</guid>
      <description>Muslims, living in the Muslim Countries, generally tend to have limited exposure to Fiqh and its rulings. There is usually one dominant madhab and that&amp;#8217;s all people know about. Rarely, if ever, people are exposed to other madahibs. However, the situation for many of us living in west, like Canada, is quite different.
Because of the diversity of muslims, from various countries, cultures and backgrounds, we are exposed to many madhabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Ramadan Opinion Do I Pick?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 21:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/which-ramadan-opinion-do-i-pick/</guid>
      <description>Sight the moon, and if you cannot, then count the days &amp;#8230;  Ramadan is coming, alhamdulillah. Ramadan, a time when all the shayateen are chained up, as the Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said:
 Narrated Abu Huraira (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhu): Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) said, &amp;#8220;When the month of Ramadan starts, the gates of the heaven are opened and the gates of Hell are closed and the devils are chained.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>