<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hadith on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/hadith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hadith on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 16:29:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/hadith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Caller Footsteps</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

 “There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.” [33:21].
 No matter what stage of life we are going through, or whatever roles we are trying to fill: be it be as father, husband, son, friend, leader and others, we will always find guidance in the life of our beloved Prophet(peace be upon him).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imam Bukhari’s Teachers: Four Legends</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/imam-bukharis-teachers-four-legends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/imam-bukharis-teachers-four-legends/</guid>
      <description>Imam Bukhari, rahimahullah, studied from over 1000 teachers. The best of them were also the greatest scholars of his time. This is an important point: in the previous generation, four scholars lived who were stars of hadith sciences. Imam Bukhari not only studied under all four of these masters of hadith sciences, but he became the main student or protege of all four scholars.
As teachers, in that time, each teacher would teach many students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imam Bukhari’s Memory in the Test of Baghdad</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/imam-bukharis-memory-in-the-test-of-baghdad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 17:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/imam-bukharis-memory-in-the-test-of-baghdad/</guid>
      <description>Imam Bukhari, rahimahullah, was tested a few times in his life. One of the early tests, which really showcases the powerful memory that Allah blessed him with, occurred as follows.
While in his twenties, imam Bukhari&amp;#8217;s fame spread over much of the Muslim world &amp;#8212; something rare in the time before internet, before email, before YouTube, our modern era where news travels almost instantenously.
As he arrived in Baghdad, word of his arrival spread, and the scholars of Baghdad devised a test for imam Bukhari &amp;#8212; to prove to the world that he&amp;#8217;s not that good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books Anyone Can Read in Saheeh Al-Bukhari</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/books-anyone-can-read-in-saheeh-al-bukhari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 17:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/books-anyone-can-read-in-saheeh-al-bukhari/</guid>
      <description>We all know Imam Bukhari&amp;#8217;s status as a scholar of hadith. Unquestionably, he is among the best scholars of hadith. This contributed heavily to his ability to produce a book like Saheeh Al-Bukhari.
What is less well known about Imam Bukhari, though, are his other two specialities: aqeedah (which we will inshaAllah discuss another time), and fiqh. Imam Bukhari, rahimahullah, was a master of fiqh, and a mujtahid.
Additionally, Imam Bukhari assumes that any reader of his book will be at least a hafidh of Qur&amp;#8217;an.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 – Manners of Sneezing and Yawning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 16:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
 This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. In the last post, we talked about the manners of sleeping. In this post, we will look at the Sunnahs of sneezing and yawning:
 Narrated Abu Huraira: The Prophet said, &amp;ldquo;Allah loves sneezing but dislikes yawning; so if anyone of you sneezes and then praises Allah, every Muslim who hears him (praising Allah) has to say Tashmit to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 5</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 20:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Making Dua:
 Raise your hands Glorify and praise Allah, in the beginning and at the end Send salutations on Prophet (May Allah Peace and Blessing be on him) in the beginning and at the end Cry while making dua  Adhaan:
 Respond to it (see the first dua here) Make salutation on the prophet (May Allah Peace and Blessing be on him) Make dua (last one on this page)  Breakfast:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 4</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we focus on the sunnah of making ablution and coming out of the washroom. Here is the sunnah for this week:
After the fard salahs:
 After slautation, say Allahu Akbar in loud voice Say &amp;#8220;Astagfirullah&amp;#8221; thrice in low voice Recite &amp;#8220;Ayat Kursi&amp;#8221; Read the morning and evening supplications after farjar and asar prayers (Another Link) Recite other Adhkars and Supplications Pray the two rakahs of ishraq after the fajar prayer (The Messenger of Allah [SAWS] said, “Whoever prays the dawn prayer (fajr) in a group and then sits and does dhikr until the sun rises, then prays two rakas, shall have the like of the reward of a hajj and an umra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 22:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</guid>
      <description>I hope that you had an awesome productive last week, applying and implementing the Sunnah Items, we discussed in the last post. Here is the sunnah for this week:
On Coming Out of Washroom:
 Exit with Right Foot first Say the dua  Making Ablution:
 Say Bismillah Do the Mishwaak Run water through the fingers Put water in the nose Say the Sahada after finishing Say the dua Pray 2 rakahs of tayatul whudoo  Tip of the Week:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 15:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we started a new series. The goal of the series is to learn and implement the sunnah in our lives. We started with the sunnah of our beloved Prophet (May Allah&amp;#8217;s peace and blessings be upon him) on waking up. I hope all of you have been practicing that sunnah. Here is the sunnah for this week:
Entering the Washroom:
 Enter with slippers/shoes Make the dua Enter with Left foot  After Entering the Washroom:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 22:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Allah Subhannallah, tells us in the Quran:
 لَّقَدْ كَانَ لَكُمْ فِي رَسُولِ اللَّـهِ أُسْوَةٌ
حَسَنَةٌ لِّمَن كَانَ يَرْجُو اللَّـهَ وَ
وَذَكَرَ اللَّـهَ كَثِيرًا
 Translation:
There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.[Surah Al-Ahzab, verses 21]
The oxford dictionary defines the word &amp;#8216;role model&amp;#8216; as &amp;#8220;A person looked to by others as an example to be imitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Uncle</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2010/oswatun-hasana-the-best-uncle/</guid>
      <description>And We have not sent you, [O Muhammad], except as a mercy to the worlds. [21:107]
In the last post, we looked at how our beloved prophet (SAW) set for us an excellent example as a father. Inshallah, continuing with the theme, in this post, we will explore two more roles: **uncle and the master.
**
Treatment with niece
 After the Taif Campaign, one of the captives As-Shaima, the daughter of Al-Harith As-Sadiya, the Messenger’s foster sister was brought to the Messenger of Allah (peace be upon him) , she introduced herself to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminder Series: Four Priorities of the Muslim</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2009 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reminder-series-four-priorities-of-the-muslim/</guid>
      <description>Abu Barzah al-Aslami radi Allahu anhu reported that Allah’s Messenger sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, “The two feet of the servant will not cease (from standing before Allah) on the Day of Judgment until he is asked about four things: on his life and how he spent it; on his knowledge and what he did with it; on his wealth and where he earned it and how he spent it; and on his body and in what way he utilized it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to Reject Narrators of Ahadith</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reasons-to-reject-narrators-of-ahadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 20:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/reasons-to-reject-narrators-of-ahadith/</guid>
      <description>As you know, we cannot just accept a hadith from anyone&amp;#8211;this is our deen! If anyone could just say what they wanted, we would have nothing left of the true, pure message of Allah.
The scholars have analyzed the biographies of every narrator of hadith. They compile information on when he was born, and where, his kunya, his tribe, who he met, what his character was, what other people narrated about him &amp;#8230; piles and piles of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Mursal Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 18:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/what-is-a-mursal-hadith/</guid>
      <description>In the sciences of hadith, there&amp;#8217;s something called a &amp;#8220;mursal&amp;#8221; hadith. What exactly is a mursal hadith? What is it&amp;#8217;s status? What are the fiqh rulings on mursal ahadith? And why does it matter?
(Ok, for the answer to the last question, read and learn about the science of hadith. In a sentence: Scholars have devised an extremely rigorous process to determine which hadith are authentic, and which are not. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t want to spend your whole life following a &amp;#8220;hadith,&amp;#8221; only to find out it really wasn&amp;#8217;t legit, do you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things” that Loved the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
عن انس قال النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏لا يؤمن ‏ ‏أحدكم حتى أكون أحب إليه من والده وولده والناس أجمعين ‏ 
Anas radi Allahu anhu narrated that the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, &amp;#8220;None of you truly believes (has emaan) until I am more beloved to him than his father, his child and all of mankind.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Loving the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam is a part of emaan, and Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala has made it obligatory for us to love the Messenger alayhi salaam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of using Weak Hadeeth</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-dangers-of-using-weak-hadeeth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 18:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-dangers-of-using-weak-hadeeth/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
Many scholars like Imam Bukharee rahmatulillah alay and Imam Muslim rahmatulillah alay have clarified the dangers of using da&amp;#8217;eef (weak) ahadeeth. Of the scholars that have used weak ahadeeth, they have done so with very strict conditions.
Ibn Hajar al-Askalani rahmatullilah alay, the father of the scholars of hadeeth, has said da&amp;#8217;eef ahadeeth are only to be used when the following conditions are met:
 It is well accepted amongst the scholars of hadeeth that the weakness is only minor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do you Stand with Allah?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:49:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/where-do-you-stand-with-allah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
حدثنا زهير بن حرب وعثمان بن أبي شيبة وإسحاق بن إبراهيم قال إسحاق أخبرنا وقال الآخران حدثنا جرير عن منصور عن أبي وائل عن عبد الله قال قال رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم إن الصدق يهدى إلى البر وإن البر يهدى إلى الجنة وإن الرجل ليصدق حتى يكتب صديقا وإن الكذب يهدى إلى الفجور وإن الفجور يهدى إلى النار وإن الرجل ليكذب حتى يكتب كذابا  Translation: Narrated &amp;#8216;Abdullah: The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: Truthfulness (sidq) leads to righteousness (birr), and righteousness leads to Paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditions for Saheeh Hadeeth</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/conditions-for-saheeh-hadeeth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 13:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/conditions-for-saheeh-hadeeth/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
The study of hadeeth is one of the most noble sciences in Islam. The precision of this science, and the scholars who perfected it, is amazing and is not found in any other science&amp;#8211;secular or Islamic. The sciences of hadeeth may be the most disputed science in Islam, simply because people do not understand the succinct process and scrutinization for only one narration to be accepted as authentic (saheeh). The Sunnah is the second source of legislation after the Qur&amp;#8217;an, and Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) promised to protect the Sunnah:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chain of Command</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/chain-of-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 15:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/chain-of-command/</guid>
      <description>Chain of Command  The sciences of hadith, and its importance. What is &amp;#8220;sunnah,&amp;#8221; its importance, its authority in Islam, who were the scholars of hadith, their books, and what is the terminology of hadith.
Chain of Command is an AlMaghrib course taught by Abdul-Bary Yahya. This course is divided into two parts: first, the Muhadithoon, the Scholars of Hadith; and second, what is known as &amp;#8220;Mustalah al-Hadith,&amp;#8221; the terminology and categorization of hadith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be An Orange</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-an-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 12:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/be-an-orange/</guid>
      <description>This Ramadan…be an orange!
Say what?
 &amp;#8220;The example of a believer, who recites the Qur&amp;#8217;an and acts on it, is like an orange (utrujjah) which tastes nice and smells nice.
And the example of the believer who does not recite the Qur&amp;#8217;an but acts on it is like a date that tastes sweet but has no smell.
And the example of the hypocrite who recites the Quran is like a sweet basil which smells good but tastes bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantastic Four</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 06:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/fantastic-four/</guid>
      <description>One day, the Prophet (peace be upon him) sat with his companions, early in the morning. He asked, &amp;#8220;who among you is fasting this day?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I am.&amp;#8221; The Prophet (peace be upon him) asked, &amp;#8220;who amongst you followed the funeral bier (i.e. a janaazah) today?&amp;#8221; and Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.&amp;#8221; Then the Prophet (peace be upon him) said, &amp;#8220;who amongst you served food to the needy?&amp;#8221; Abu Bakr said &amp;#8220;I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muhaddith Al-Albani</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muhaddith-al-albani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2006 01:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/muhaddith-al-albani/</guid>
      <description>A Muhaddith is one who studies and memorizes ahadith, and internalizes the science of hadith&amp;#8211;the science that allows us to dissect and analyze ahadith and sort the authentic from the un-authentic. (You can read more about ahadith and their statuses here.) This includes memorizing the biographies of people involved in the narration, including their strengths and weaknesses (in terms of memory and piety).
Shaykh Muhammad Nasir-ud-Deen al-Albani, one of the greatest scholars of recent times, also studied ahadith and became a muhaddith&amp;#8211;one the likes of we have not seen in centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Hadith?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-a-hadith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 02:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/what-is-a-hadith/</guid>
      <description>What exactly is a hadith? It&amp;#8217;s a saying of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم). The Science of Hadith defines a hadeeth as &amp;#8220;whatever is attributed to the Prophet, in terms of sayings, actions, approvals, and physical and character descriptions.&amp;#8221; 1
Ahadith are an important part of Islam. They complement and the Qur&amp;#8217;an, and provide us with numerous benefits and different types of information, including:
 Laws not directly stated in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>