<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surah Iqraa on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-iqraa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surah Iqraa on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 14:41:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-iqraa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ripped Limb From Limb</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ripped-limb-from-limb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 14:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ripped-limb-from-limb/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is post #6 in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma, and insha&amp;#8217;Allah our last post from Surah Iqraa.
In verses 9 and 10 of Surah Iqraa, Allah says:
 أَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي يَنْهَى
عَبْداً إِذَا صَلَّى
 Translation: Have you seen the one who forbids a servant when he prays?
The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) used to make sujood to Allah in the courtyard of the ka&amp;#8217;bah in early times in Mecca, and nobody would stop him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Wealth and Poverty</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 10:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is the 5th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
In our last post, we talked about how the human race does taghaa if they see themselves as self-sufficient. Living in western societies, we see this all around us&amp;#8211;people racing, fighting, stealing, overworking, to make a few more dollars so that they can &amp;#8220;make it.&amp;#8221; They buy lottery tickets so they can &amp;#8220;make it&amp;#8221; and be rich, rich rich!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Sufficient?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/self-sufficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 22:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/self-sufficient/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is our 4th post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
Allah says, in ayahs 6-7 of Surah Iqraa:
 كَلَّا إِنَّ الْإِنسَانَ لَيَطْغَى
أَن رَّآهُ اسْتَغْنَى
 Translation: No! [But] indeed, man transgresses. Because he sees himself self-sufficient. [Surah Iqraa, verses 6-7]
Kalla is a very stern, emphatic warning. If your kid is being bad, you say &amp;#8220;laa, laa;&amp;#8221; and then they grab something hot off the stove and you say &amp;#8220;KALLA!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Statement</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/making-a-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 22:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/making-a-statement/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is the third post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
From the opening ceremonies, to the first move of world leaders, people like to send a message. The intense revelation of the Qur’an is no different. The timing, style and content, sends a message to the final Prophet (saw) and to all of humanity.
Allah (swt) starts the revelation commanding the Prophet to read &amp;#8220;Recite in the name of your Lord who created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Analysis for First Revelation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-for-first-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/arabic-analysis-for-first-revelation/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
The first five ayaat of Surah Iqraa are:
 اقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ
خَلَقَ الْإِنسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ
اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ
الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ
عَلَّمَ الْإِنسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ
 Word-for-word translations are pretty common these days (like this one, which has Surah Iqraa), so I&amp;#8217;m going to touch lightly on that, and do a bit more grammar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Revelation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-beginning-of-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 14:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-beginning-of-revelation/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
Although the story is well-known amongst the Muslims, we will recap the story of the first revelation: Surah Iqraa (also known as Surah &amp;#8216;Alaq), revealed in Mecca.
Imam Ahmed ibn Hanbal (rahimahullah) relates from &amp;#8216;Aisha (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhaa) that the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam), for six months before revelation, would see true dreams that would happen the next day&amp;#8211;day after day after day, for six months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>