<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 16:59:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Project Unveiled: Salah Support</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2009 16:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/new-project-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Alhamdulillah, we&amp;#8217;ve been working in the background for a while to launch a new project. Jazakumullahu khayran to everybody who helped out, may Allah keep giving you reward for it insha&amp;#8217;Allah long after your bones are dust&amp;#8211;allahumma ameen!
First, check yourself, and fill out the poll below:
[poll id=&amp;#8221;3&amp;#8243;]
If you haven&amp;#8217;t guessed, our new project is: Salah Support, a forum where you can find resources on salah&amp;#8211;everything from videos on how to pray, to ebooks on khushoo&amp;#8217;, to creative alarms for Qiaaym-ul-Layl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilm Fruits on Twitter and Facebook!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ilm-fruits-on-twitter-and-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 16:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ilm-fruits-on-twitter-and-facebook/</guid>
      <description>As-salaamu &amp;#8216;alikum wa rahmatullah,
We are very pleased to announce that Ilm Fruits has now extended to Facebook and to Twitter.
Rather than, like other Islamic organizations and groups, following hype, we hope that this will allow us to solve the following problems:
 Facebook Updates: Would you like to see new posts on Ilm Fruits immediately in Facebook? We&amp;#8217;ve added a Facebook user to facilitate this; just add it as your friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Juz ‘Amma Series</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/update-on-juz-amma-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2009 10:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/update-on-juz-amma-series/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
We&amp;#8217;ve been posting about tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma for over a month now; and we&amp;#8217;ve gone through about 10 surahs, walhamdulillah, and it seems like people are benefitting.
But &amp;#8230; there are still 27 (!) surahs remaining. And as much as I would like to finish the series &amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s too long, by far, to have 37 posts on one series. Not to mention that it would take around 2 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series: Tafseer of Juz ‘Amma</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/series-tafseer-of-juz-amma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 21:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/series-tafseer-of-juz-amma/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
As mentioned in the last post, we&amp;#8217;re going to start a series insha&amp;#8217;Allah Monday, April 13th on the tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma, the 30th juz of the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
Here&amp;#8217;s what you can expect in the next while:
 The whole juz. As much as possible, I will post gems, points, tafseer, etc. from every single surah in this juz&amp;#8211;even if it&amp;#8217;s not necessarily the most actionable thing. Every single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Winner is …</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/and-the-winner-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 20:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/and-the-winner-is/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
The results of the poll are in! And it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8230;
It&amp;#8217;s a four-way tie.
The winners are:
 Arabic Language Islamic Finance Uloom-ul-Qur&amp;#8217;an Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma  I was really hoping for a clear-cut winner &amp;#8230; but insha&amp;#8217;Allah khayr. I spent a while thinking about it, taking shura from different people, looking at different factors (such as what information I can easily access and benefit from), and here&amp;#8217;s what I decided:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poll: What Series do YOU Want?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/poll-what-series-do-you-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/poll-what-series-do-you-want/</guid>
      <description>Alhamdulillah, all praise and thanks is due to Allah, who has made Ilm Fruits alhamdulillah a very successful blog. Our recent post on salah questions (and their answers) got a lot of questions (masha&amp;#8217;Allah alhamdulillah), so we&amp;#8217;re going to take it a step further and roll out &amp;#8230; a series.
Insha&amp;#8217;Allah, starting April 6th (Monday), for the month of April, we&amp;#8217;re going to have a series on a single topic. What does this mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ilm Fruits: 3 Years in Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ilm-fruits-3-years-in-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 12:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/ilm-fruits-3-years-in-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Alhamdulillah, it&amp;#8217;s been three years since Ilm Fruits started as a fledgling blog&amp;#8211;one of very few at that time&amp;#8211;with a few posts here and there. A lot has changed over that time; the blog has evolved.
Now it&amp;#8217;s your chance to give back. I want to hear from you, personally, what you liked and didn&amp;#8217;t like, what kinds of things you want to see from the blog in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Israel Bombs Gaza Again</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/israel-bombs-gaza-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 13:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/israel-bombs-gaza-again/</guid>
      <description>Israel is bombing Gaza. Again. In two days, there are 400 dead and 1400 injured. Hospitals overflowing, boycotts, blood, and dead bodies&amp;#8230;
The Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said the Muslim ummah is like one body&amp;#8211;if one part hurts, the whole body feels it and responds.
Do you feel the pain?
There are countless websites, emails, etc. that speak about this. We&amp;#8217;re not going to reiterate all the points. Read about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QMajd Issue 2: Route 114</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qmajd-issue-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 12:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qmajd-issue-2/</guid>
      <description>QMajd has alhamdulillah published their second (or third, depending on how you count) newsletter! This one is all about Route 114, the sciences of the Qur&amp;#8217;an. Insha&amp;#8217;Allah check it out&amp;#8211;it covers everything from notes on the Ameer (and how Majd managed to be the largest student body&amp;#8211;800+ students) to crosswords to articles from our very own Ilm Fruits! So check it out insha&amp;#8217;Allah, there&amp;#8217;s lots of &amp;#8216;ilm to benefit from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IlmSieve – Islamic Search Engine</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ilmsieve-islamic-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 15:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ilmsieve-islamic-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>One of the amazing things about the internet, is that alhamdulillah, it&amp;#8217;s possible to find dozens of different projects that benefit the Muslims.
One such project is Ilm Sieve, an Islamic search engine. Built on top of Google technology, it filters out non-Islamic and un-Islamic sites to give you only the best of Islam on the web. Some of the benefits of Ilm Sieve are:
 Signal-to-Noise: compared to searching on Google, almost all (if not all) the search-results you find in Ilm Sieve are from Islamic sites&amp;#8211;so no more digging to find the Islamic sites in page five and six of the results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2007 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/eid-mubarak-2007/</guid>
      <description>So, another Ramadan has come and gone! 30 days of reading Qur&amp;#8217;an and feeding the poor, 30 nights of Qiyaam-ul-Layl and Taraweeh and Tahajjud. And so, &amp;#8216;Eid comes again.
Congratulations! You have been one of those lucky few who lived to receive this great blessing from Allah (سبحانه وتعالى), this chance to get all your sins forgiven! Because the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;Whoever fasts during Ramadan out of sincere faith and hoping to attain Allah&amp;#8217;s rewards, then all his past sins will be forgiven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid Mubarak!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2006 16:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/eid-mubarak-2006-2/</guid>
      <description>Asalamu &amp;#8216;alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu,
Allahu akber! Allahu akber! Allahu akber! Laa Ilaaha Illallah!
Allahu akber! Allahu akber! Wa Lillahil Hamd!
Alhamdolilah, Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) blessed us to see yet again another Eid.
We here at Ilm Fruits just wanted to send out the warmest Eid greetings to you and your families, whichever day you celebrated on! May Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) accept our good deeds and continue to shower us all with His Mercy, ameen!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Construction Zone</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/heavy-construction-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 02:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/heavy-construction-zone/</guid>
      <description>Ilm Fruits is under heavy construction. (Hence the lack of posts.) Inshallah when it&amp;#8217;s finished, it&amp;#8217;ll be better then ever!In the mean-time, if you notice anything out of order&amp;#8211;any broken links, broken images, anything like that, please drop a comment and let me know. Similarly, if you have any suggestions for improvement, drop a comment and let me know inshallah. That includes suggestions for upcoming content or awesome articles!
May Allah reward all your efforts and make the transition smooth and easy for us all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIA Arabic Course: Tentative Second Offering Staring May</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uia-arabic-course-second-offering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2006 00:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/uia-arabic-course-second-offering/</guid>
      <description>For those who missed the train for UIA&amp;#8217;s two-year Arabic course, email info@uia.ca and ask them to put you on the waiting list. They&amp;#8217;re planning on holding another session (same content, different teacher) starting in May inshaAllah.
Register today. There are only approximately ten seats left!
Related Links: Classes: Understanding Islam Academy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genesis</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2005 23:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2005/genesis/</guid>
      <description>Today, I created my new blog. I hope, by the permission of Allah, you will all learn and grow and benefit from it. For more information on what it is and why it exists, check the About page.
Feedback can only make you stronger.
I borrow from the inaugaration speech of Abu Bakr as-Siddique, radiallahu &amp;#8216;ahn. He said: &amp;#8220;Support me, if I am in the right, and correct me if I am in the wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>