<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surah Qadar on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-qadar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surah Qadar on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 17:30:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/surah-qadar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tafseer Surah Qadar: What’s Better Than 1000 Months?</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qadar-whats-better-than-1000-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 17:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/tafseer-surah-qadar-whats-better-than-1000-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is post #25 in our series on Tafseer of Juz ‘Amma (click the link to see all posts in this series).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-of-revelation&#34;&gt;Reason of Revelation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Messenger of Allah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) told the companions about a man of the previous nations; a man who lived and fought jihad for over 1000 months (roughly 83 years, 4 months). (In case you didn&amp;#8217;t know, the previous nations lived longer than us&amp;#8211;like Prophet Nuh (alayhi salaam), who did da&amp;#8217;wah for nearly 1000 years.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The companions were amazed, and they said: how can we compete with him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And subhanallah, this is a gem. &lt;em&gt;Look at the companions.&lt;/em&gt; They &lt;strong&gt;prioritized and competed for the akhirah.&lt;/strong&gt; Subhanallah to the point that, they don&amp;#8217;t just try to do &amp;#8220;some good deeds before I die;&amp;#8221; not enough. They competed with each other&amp;#8211;but even that was not enough. Rather, &lt;span class=&#34;gem&#34;&gt;they competed with all of the Muslims, ever, starting from the time of Prophet Adam, until the Day of Judgment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to really look at ourselves and see, how much are we like them? Or are we just vying for bigger houses, better cars&amp;#8211;more dunya?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>