<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Duas on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/duas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Duas on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 10:39:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/duas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Wealth and Poverty</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 10:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-wealth-and-poverty/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is the 5th post in our series on Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
In our last post, we talked about how the human race does taghaa if they see themselves as self-sufficient. Living in western societies, we see this all around us&amp;#8211;people racing, fighting, stealing, overworking, to make a few more dollars so that they can &amp;#8220;make it.&amp;#8221; They buy lottery tickets so they can &amp;#8220;make it&amp;#8221; and be rich, rich rich!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Du’a for Laziness and Incapability</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/dua-for-laziness-and-incapability/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) used to make a du&amp;#8217;a:
 اللّهُمَّ إنِّي أعُوذُبِكَ مِن العَجزِ وَ الكَسلٍTransliteration: Allahumma inniy a&amp;#8217;oothubika min al-ajzi wal-kasli
Translation: O Allah, I seek refuge in you from incapability and laziness.  Why is this du&amp;#8217;a important? For two reasons:   Laziness is an attribute of munafiqeen. If this wasn&amp;#8217;t bad enough, being lazy leads to procrastination, which leads to its own set of problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Du’a for Guidance</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-concise-dua-for-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 21:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/a-concise-dua-for-guidance/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
One of the things I decided to blog about is my own personal du&amp;#8217;a&amp;#8211;it&amp;#8217;s not lifted straight from the pages of the Qur&amp;#8217;an or Sunnah, but it draws from them. My goal was to have a du&amp;#8217;a that:
 Is short, so I can recite it in sujood every rakah or every salah Is encompassing&amp;#8211;covers every aspect (in this case, of the akhirah) Is easy to remember, so I can remember it as needed!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>