<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seerah on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/seerah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seerah on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 02:56:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/seerah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Hesitate: Lessons from the Battle of Mu’tah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 02:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/dont-hesitate-lessons-from-the-battle-of-mutah/</guid>
      <description>One of the unique characteristics of the battle of Mu&amp;#8217;tah is that rasulullah (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed not one, but three commanders in the chain of command:
 `Abdullah bin &amp;#8216;Umar said: Allah&amp;#8217;s Messenger (salallahu alayhi wa sallam) appointed Zaid bin Haritha as the commander of the army during the Ghazwa of Mu&amp;#8217;tah and said, &amp;#8220;If Zaid is martyred, Ja&amp;#8217;far should take over his position, and if Ja&amp;#8217;far is martyred, Abdullah bin Rawaha should take over his position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Caller Footsteps</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2013/the-caller-footsteps/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

 “There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.” [33:21].
 No matter what stage of life we are going through, or whatever roles we are trying to fill: be it be as father, husband, son, friend, leader and others, we will always find guidance in the life of our beloved Prophet(peace be upon him).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 – Manners of Sneezing and Yawning</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 16:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2012/week-10-manners-of-sneezing-and-yawning/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
 This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. In the last post, we talked about the manners of sleeping. In this post, we will look at the Sunnahs of sneezing and yawning:
 Narrated Abu Huraira: The Prophet said, &amp;ldquo;Allah loves sneezing but dislikes yawning; so if anyone of you sneezes and then praises Allah, every Muslim who hears him (praising Allah) has to say Tashmit to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Boy – Ya Ghulam!</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/o-boy-ya-ghulam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 22:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/o-boy-ya-ghulam/</guid>
      <description>بِسْمِ اللَّـهِ الرَّحْمَـٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ
This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives.
Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Click here to show evidences/reference links
Sunnah&amp;#8217;s of Eating:
 Pronounce the Tasmiya (Bismilla) [Bukhari :: Book 7 :: Volume 65 :: Hadith 288]   If you forget to say Bismillah, before starting, say this supplication. [At-Tirmidhee 5/506]   Eat with the right hand   Eat from what is infront of you   If some food drops, clean it and then eat it [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5044]   Eat with three fingers [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5040]   Eat together [Dawud :: Book 27 : Hadith 3755]   Not finding faults in food [Muslim :: Book 23 : Hadith 5121]   After Eating:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Siwaak a Day</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/a-siwaak-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 17:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/a-siwaak-a-day/</guid>
      <description>This is the continuation of the series, that focuses on implementing sunnah in our lives. I hope everyone had emaan rushed Ramadhan and you were able to apply the things we learned in this series.
Here is the sunnah items, we will be focusing on in this week:
Using Siwak:
 Performing Prayers [Bukhari :: Book 2 :: Volume 13 :: Hadith 12] Entering the house [Aaishah was asked what the Messenger of Allaah (peace and blessings of Allaah be upon him) did when he first came home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 3</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 22:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-3/</guid>
      <description>I hope that you had an awesome productive last week, applying and implementing the Sunnah Items, we discussed in the last post. Here is the sunnah for this week:
On Coming Out of Washroom:
 Exit with Right Foot first Say the dua  Making Ablution:
 Say Bismillah Do the Mishwaak Run water through the fingers Put water in the nose Say the Sahada after finishing Say the dua Pray 2 rakahs of tayatul whudoo  Tip of the Week:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Sunnah – Week 1</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 22:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2011/follow-the-sunnah-week-1/</guid>
      <description>Allah Subhannallah, tells us in the Quran:
 لَّقَدْ كَانَ لَكُمْ فِي رَسُولِ اللَّـهِ أُسْوَةٌ
حَسَنَةٌ لِّمَن كَانَ يَرْجُو اللَّـهَ وَ
وَذَكَرَ اللَّـهَ كَثِيرًا
 Translation:
There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.[Surah Al-Ahzab, verses 21]
The oxford dictionary defines the word &amp;#8216;role model&amp;#8216; as &amp;#8220;A person looked to by others as an example to be imitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oswatun Hasana – The Best Father</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 03:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/oswatun-hasana-the-best-father/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;There has certainly been for you in the Messenger of Allah an excellent pattern for anyone whose hope is in Allah and the Last Day and [who] remembers Allah often.&amp;#8221; [33:21]
Inshallah in this post and in future posts, we will be looking at seerah. We will look at how the prophet (SAW) set an excellent example for us in different roles; be it be as a husband, father, friend, leader and other such roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Revelation</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-beginning-of-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 14:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/the-beginning-of-revelation/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in our series of Tafseer of Juz &amp;#8216;Amma.
Although the story is well-known amongst the Muslims, we will recap the story of the first revelation: Surah Iqraa (also known as Surah &amp;#8216;Alaq), revealed in Mecca.
Imam Ahmed ibn Hanbal (rahimahullah) relates from &amp;#8216;Aisha (radiallahu &amp;#8216;anhaa) that the Prophet (salallahu alayhi wa sallam), for six months before revelation, would see true dreams that would happen the next day&amp;#8211;day after day after day, for six months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things” that Loved the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/things-that-loved-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
عن انس قال النبي ‏ ‏صلى الله عليه وسلم ‏ ‏لا يؤمن ‏ ‏أحدكم حتى أكون أحب إليه من والده وولده والناس أجمعين ‏ 
Anas radi Allahu anhu narrated that the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam said, &amp;#8220;None of you truly believes (has emaan) until I am more beloved to him than his father, his child and all of mankind.&amp;#8221; (Bukhari and Muslim)
Loving the Prophet sal Allahu alayhi wa sallam is a part of emaan, and Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala has made it obligatory for us to love the Messenger alayhi salaam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Teacher</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 18:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-best-teacher/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Allah (سبحانه وتعالى) says in the Qur&amp;#8217;an,
هُوَ الَّذِي بَعَثَ فِي الْأُمِّيِّينَ رَسُولًا مِّنْهُمْ يَتْلُو عَلَيْهِمْ آيَاتِهِ وَيُزَكِّيهِمْ وَيُعَلِّمُهُمُ الْكِتَابَ وَالْحِكْمَةَ وَإِن كَانُوا مِن قَبْلُ لَفِي ضَلَالٍ مُّبِينٍ  Translation: It is He who has sent among the unlettered a Messenger from themselves reciting to them His verses and purifying them and teaching them the Book and wisdom although they were before in clear error. [Suratul Jumu&amp;#8217;ah, verse 2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild Rumors</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wild-rumors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2007 02:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/wild-rumors/</guid>
      <description>After the battle of Uhud, &amp;#8216;Aisha (رضالله عنها) lost her necklace; so while the Muslim army moved forward, she stayed behind to find it. The army had a lost-and-found guy&amp;#8211;Sawfan ibn Mu&amp;#8217;atib (رضالله عنه)&amp;#8211;who travelled behind the army and picked up lost items. So when he saw her, he immediately said la hawla wa la quwwata illa billah (there is no might or power except Allah), hopped off his camel, and let her go on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mecca’s War Criminals</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/meccas-war-criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 14:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/meccas-war-criminals/</guid>
      <description>In the eight year after Hijrah (8AH), the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and his companions conquered Mecca&amp;#8211;without a single sword-swing. 10,000 Muslim warriors arrived at the gates, and the inhabitants of Mecca raised their arms in surrender.
The norm during those days was that when a land is conquered, ALL its people are killed, and its women and children are taken as slaves and property. So when the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) conquered Mecca, the Meccans became frightened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Uncles of the Prophet</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-uncles-of-the-prophet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2007 09:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/two-uncles-of-the-prophet/</guid>
      <description>During the 23 years of revelation, the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) had many supporters and opponents, including his two uncles&amp;#8211;Abu Talib (the father of Ali (رضالله عنه)), and Abdul &amp;#8216;Uzza ibn Abdul-Muttalib, aka Abu Lahab.
Subhanallah, even within two uncles of the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم), we see great differences. Compare and constrast them:
Abu Talib:
 Extended his protection to his nephew, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), even though the Quresh wanted to kill him Wrote strong, emotional poetry during the boycott of Mecca in order to move people towards nullifying it Commanded his sons to sleep in the Prophet&amp;#8217;s (صلي الله عليه وسلم) bed at night, so that if any assassins came, the sons would die instead of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) The Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said regarding him: because of me, he will be in the lightest part of the Hellfire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shepherd’s Path</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/shepherds-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 11:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/shepherds-path/</guid>
      <description>The Shepherd&amp;#8217;s Path  The Shepherd&amp;#8217;s Path is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Muhammad Alshareef.
While many of us claim to love the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم), few of us follow his path, and fewer still know more then snatches of information about him. How did he live, and how did he die? What key lesson did the angel Jibreel send by squeezing him three times before the first revelation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits to Not Fighting Back</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/benefits-to-not-fighting-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 15:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/benefits-to-not-fighting-back/</guid>
      <description>When the Messenger of Allah (صلي الله عليه وسلم) appeared on the scene in Mecca to proclaim the message of Islam, the Muslims faced ridicule, mockery, opposition, propoganda, and even severe torture up to the point of death&amp;#8211;to the point where Muslims would walk through the streets, see their brothers and sisters being severely tortured in front of their eyes.
And Allah revealed the commandment not to fight back. Not in Mecca, not for ten years until they migrated to Medinah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of the Masjid</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-role-of-the-masjid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 23:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-role-of-the-masjid/</guid>
      <description>When the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) arrived in Medina, he built a masjid before doing anything else! The masjids the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) built were more than places to pray! Their functions included:
 A place for children: not a place where they cried and ran around but a place where they were accommodated. There are several narrations of how when the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) was praying, the children would come and climb on his back or he (صلي الله عليه وسلم) would hold them while praying salah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lessons: Power With Conciseness</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 15:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/leadership-lessons-power-with-conciseness/</guid>
      <description>Another important gem we learn from the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) and the early generations is that power comes with conciseness.
During the time of the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم), he received a letter from a man named Musaylimah, who claimed prophethood as well, and wished to divide up the area. In response, the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) wrote:
&amp;#8220;From Muhammad the Messenger of Allah to Musaylimah the liar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Brings Change</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pain-brings-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2006 20:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/pain-brings-change/</guid>
      <description>Pain is often an instigator of change. Pain works as one method to break people out of their cycles or mindsets.
Look at the story of &amp;#8216;Umar ibn al-Khattab, may Allah be pleased with him. In Mecca, before he became Muslim, he was one of the toughest on the Muslims.
One of his relatives, Umm Abdullah, prepared to leave for Habasha. He asked &amp;#8220;where are you going?&amp;#8221; and she said &amp;#8220;To Habasha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing to Good Deeds: Abu Dujana and the Prophet’s Sword</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2006 05:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/competing-to-good-deeds-abu-dujana-and-the-prophets-sword/</guid>
      <description>Before the battle of Uhud, when the Muslims were preparing and such, the Prophet, peace be upon him, lifted up his sword and said &amp;#8220;who will fight with my sword?&amp;#8221;
And all the sahaba were like &amp;#8220;me, me&amp;#8221;, like &amp;#8220;pick me&amp;#8221;. The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) put down his sword. Their emotions were raised.
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) raised it again and said &amp;#8220;who will take my sword and give it the haq (right) due to the sword?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Qur’an on Battle Tactics</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-on-battle-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 03:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2006/the-quran-on-battle-tactics/</guid>
      <description>In Surah Nisaa, Allah says:
يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِينَ آمَنُواْ خُذُواْ حِذْرَكُمْ فَانفِرُواْ ثُبَاتٍ أَوِ انفِرُواْ جَمِيعًا  Translation: O ye who believe! Take your precautions, and either go forth in parties or go forth all together (Surah Nisaa, 4:71).1
The message: prepare, and fight in groups.
A related incident: after the battle of Uhud, many tribes targeted the Muslims to take them down once and for all. The day the Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) returned from battle, he slept, prayed &amp;#8216;Isha (alone), and the next day, after Fajr, said &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;re going after [the fleeing army].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>