<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asmaa Was Sifaat on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/categories/asmaa-was-sifaat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asmaa Was Sifaat on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/categories/asmaa-was-sifaat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem Together</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 23:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem-together/</guid>
      <description>Allah introduces himself in Surah Fatiha as Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem, both. Both of these names derive their meaning from the word mercy (rahmah).
In classical Arabic, rahmah represents the mercy of a mother for her child. As the child grows, it causes the mother to be sick and weak; it eats nutrition from the mother; in the later trimesters, the child even stretches, punches, or kicks the mother&amp;#8217;s ribs! But still, the mother cares for, takes care of, and protects the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Complete Oneness – Part 2</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2009/his-complete-oneness-part-2/</guid>
      <description>ALLAH IS AS HE DESCRIBES HIMSELF WITH NO ADDITIONS BEYOND WHICH WE DO NOT PONDER NOR PUT CONDITIONS
Continuing in our explanation of the poem and our discussion of the branches tawheed, we now move into the second branch which is the oneness, uniqueness, and exclusiveness of Allah’s Names and Attributes (tawheed al-asma was-sifat). There are five points we will discuss; three points in this post and the remaining two in the next post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allah’s Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/allahs-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 16:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/allahs-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>We take it for granted that Allah has infinite knowledge. But what does this mean? Let&amp;#8217;s take a &amp;#8220;tour,&amp;#8221; if you like, of some of the things Allah knows.
There are 6-8 billion people on the face of the earth. That&amp;#8217;s 6 * 1000 * 1000 * 1000. That&amp;#8217;s a lot of people! Can you imagine learning 6 names? Or 60? Or 6000? But Allah knows their names&amp;#8211;all 6,000,000,000 of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ar Rahman and ar Raheem</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 13:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ar-rahman-and-ar-raheem/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Ar-Rahman: The Entirely Merciful, Ar-Raheem: The Especially Merciful 
Both of the names Rahman and Raheem come from the root Ra-ha-meem (ر ح م), these names are similar so they require a parallel explanation. What is Rahmah? Rahmah is mercy. In the dictionary it means: compassion, kindness and gentleness. Also when a person is kind, compassionate and tenderhearted towards the other. So Ar-Rahman and Ar-Raheem: The One who has a lot of Rahmah, The One who shows a lot of rahmah, He expresses a lot of Rahmah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ismul Jalaalah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 19:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/ismul-jalaalah/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah.
Ismul Jalaalah, The Grand Name: Allah الله. This is Allah&amp;#8217;s Personal Name. His Identifying Name. This Name only belongs to Allah, no one else can have besides Allah. Allah is the Title, the Name, of the One True Ilaah. The Name of Allah, you cannot play around with: there is no plural, there is no feminine. The Name Allah appears over 3000 times in the Qur&amp;#8217;an.
When we mentioned the Name &amp;#8220;Allah&amp;#8221; linguistically, we don&amp;#8217;t say &amp;#8220;the word Allah&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;the Name Allah&amp;#8221; because it is not appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Receive Allah’s Special Mercy</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/how-to-receive-allahs-special-mercy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 01:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/how-to-receive-allahs-special-mercy/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
We know that Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala Name&amp;#8217;s Ar-Raheem is specifically for the believers, so how is it that one can receive this special Mercy from ar Raheem?
 Obedience to Allah and His Messenger. &amp;#8220;and obey Allah and His Messenger so that you all may receive Mercy.&amp;#8221; [3:132]   Taqwa of Allah ta&amp;#8217;ala, fear and consciousness of Allah. &amp;#8220;And this is a book, We have sent it down as one blessed, so follow it and fear Allah so that you all may receive Mercy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elite 99 Names of Allah</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-elite-99-names-of-allah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-elite-99-names-of-allah/</guid>
      <description>Having already discussed the unlimited number of Allah&amp;#8217;s names and attributes, we turn now to an authentic hadith that seems to clash with what we said before.
The Messenger of Allah (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said:
إِنَّ لِلَّهِ تِسْعَةً وَتِسْعِينَ اسْمًا مِائَةً إِلاّ وَاحِدًا مَنْ أَحْصَاهَا دَخَلَ الْجَنَّةَ .  Translation: Indeed, Allah has 99 names (one hundred minus one); whoever memorizes them will enter Jannah. [Saheeh Bukhari and Saheeh Muslim]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Love</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2007 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/real-love/</guid>
      <description>Bismillah
There are many words in Arabic that translate as &amp;#8220;love&amp;#8221; in English; two of them are hubb and wudd. What is the difference between hubb (حَبَّ) and wudd (وَدَّ)? Hubb, which is from ح ب ب ، means to love. It is a love that you have for someone or something that you keep inside of you&amp;#8211;inner feelings of admiration and fondness. While wudd, from و د د، is a more intense form of hubb, a whole-hearted and deep love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Haleem</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-haleem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 00:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-haleem/</guid>
      <description>Of Allah&amp;#8217;s names, is Al-Haleem (الحليم). What does Al-Haleem mean?
It&amp;#8217;s a very very deep name—like all of Allah&amp;#8217;s names, it&amp;#8217;s very deep. It comes from the root hilm, and hilm means a wisdom and a forebearance that allows a person to control their anger. Hilm is an intelligence that, in our terms, allows someone to control their anger, even if their anger is justified. It allows you to, when you are justifiably angry, to control it and not manifest it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Ghafuwr and Al-Ghaffaar</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 08:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-ghafuwr-and-al-ghaffaar/</guid>
      <description>Of Allah&amp;#8217;s greatest names is Al-Ghafuwr (الغَفُور). It&amp;#8217;s one of the most common names mentioned in the Qur&amp;#8217;an (91 times). The name itself is on the pattern that denotes a very powerful doer of an action.
Linguistic Meaning: The root of Al-Ghaffuwr and Al-Ghaffar is the verb is ghafara (غَفَرَ), which does NOT mean &amp;#8220;to forgive&amp;#8221;; rather, it means to shield and protect and cover. Like a helmet, which, in Arabic, is called a &amp;#8220;mighfaar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Name</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 13:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/the-grand-name/</guid>
      <description>Question: I heard that there&amp;#8217;s one name of Allah, that if you use it to invoke Allah, your du&amp;#8217;a is accepted. Is this true?
Answerer: Shaykh Yasir Qadhi
The Prophet (صلي الله عليه وسلم) said: &amp;#8220;To Allah belongs a Grand Name, that, if you make du&amp;#8217;a with it, it will be responded to. And if you plead or request with it, it shall be answered.&amp;#8221; [Recorded in Abu Dawud, Tirmidhi, and others; Saheeh]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Upon Light</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-upon-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 07:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/light-upon-light/</guid>
      <description>Light Upon Light  Light Upon Light: Fundamentals of Faith 102 is an AlMaghrib Institute course taught by Yasir Qadhi.
Allah. The name conjures up many associations&amp;#8211;the Creator, the Sustainer, the only one to be worshipped. The All-Knowing, the All-Seeing, the All-Hearing. Ar-Rahmaan, Ar-Raheem.
But who is Allah? Do we really know Allah (سبحانه وتعال), in all His majesty and glory and might and mercy? Or&amp;#8211;like so many of the Muslims today&amp;#8211;do we only claim to know Allah, while in fact, we know almost nothing about Him&amp;#8211;the one who sent the Prophets as a mercy to us, who created us for nothing but His worship, out of His mercy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al-Qahhar – The Subduer</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2007/al-qahhar/</guid>
      <description>ٱلۡقَهَّارُ &amp;#8211; Al Qahhar  The root word for ٱلۡقَهَّارُ is قَهر which is defined as:
 to compel something or someone against his/her wishes to subdue to overcome to force [1]  Thus, with regards to Allah (سبحانه وتعال), the noble name Al-Qahhar can be translated as &amp;#8220;the Subduer, i.e. the Subduer of His creatures by His sovereign authority and power and the Disposer of them as He pleases, with and against their will.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>