<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sins on Ilm Fruits</title>
    <link>http://ilmfruits.com/tags/sins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sins on Ilm Fruits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 21:19:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ilmfruits.com/tags/sins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m Drowning and I Don’t Know Why</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/im-drowning-and-i-dont-know-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2016/im-drowning-and-i-dont-know-why/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever felt like you were drowning? Submerged in the depths of the world? With darkness encompassing you everywhere you went?
I have.
And what makes the situation even more difficult to swim through is when you don&amp;#8217;t know why. Everything seems to be on point; you&amp;#8217;re praying, going to the masjid, giving charity, etc. yet that feeling of drowning is ever-so-present.
What&amp;#8217;s going on? 
I want you to imagine an empty jar with dirt in it (or just look below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The King of the Body</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-king-of-the-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 20:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/the-king-of-the-body/</guid>
      <description>The king is the one who rules over the land and has power over it. Every king has soldiers. If the king is righteous, then the soldiers are righteous; and if the king is evil, then the soldiers are evil.
And the body has a king, too&amp;#8211;the Prophet (صلى الله عليه و سلم) said: &amp;#8220;There is a piece of flesh in the body; if it is righteous, the whole body is righteous; if it is evil, then the whole body is evil; indeed, it is the heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qareen</title>
      <link>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 01:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ilmfruits.com/2008/qareen/</guid>
      <description>What is a Qareen? A shaytaan, a devil, assigned to someone to mislead and misguide him. Someone to whisper to him in the light of day and the darkness of night. Allah says:
وَمَن يَعْشُ عَن ذِكْرِ الرَّحْمَنِ نُقَيِّضْ لَهُ شَيْطَاناً فَهُوَ لَهُ قَرِينٌ  Translation: And whoever is blinded from remembrance of Ar-Rahman, we appoint for him a qareen, and he is to him a companion. [Surah Az-Zukhruf, verse 36]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>